<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BACKUP-PHASE-22 NAME="Portable Data Backup Contract" STATUS="blocked-live" MODULE="M-035" CREATED="2026-05-10">
  <contract>
    <purpose>Define a portable backup and restore evidence contract for KrotPN emergency relocation.</purpose>
    <scope>Maintenance freeze, pre-backup evidence, bundle manifest, checksums, restore validation, and secret-redaction rules.</scope>
    <depends>M-035, M-034, M-001, M-003, M-020, M-028, M-030</depends>
    <links>docs/modules/M-035.xml docs/plans/Phase-22.xml docs/verification/V-M-035.xml</links>
    <role>DATA_RECOVERY_CONTRACT</role>
    <map-mode>SUMMARY</map-mode>
  </contract>

  <module-map>
    <section-maintenance-freeze>Defines the operator freeze sequence before backup capture.</section-maintenance-freeze>
    <section-pre-backup-evidence>Defines version, node, table count, and migration evidence captured before backup.</section-pre-backup-evidence>
    <section-backup-bundle>Defines required portable backup artifacts and manifest fields.</section-backup-bundle>
    <section-restore-integrity>Defines restore validation gates for schema, counts, checksums, invariants, and no-secret logs.</section-restore-integrity>
    <section-secret-redaction>Defines evidence rules that prevent raw secrets from entering logs.</section-secret-redaction>
  </module-map>

  <change-summary>
    <change-1>v1.0.0 - Phase-22 step-2 created maintenance/freeze and pre-backup evidence contract.</change-1>
    <change-2>v1.1.0 - Phase-22 step-3 defined full backup bundle, manifest, and checksum contract.</change-2>
    <change-3>v1.2.0 - Phase-22 step-4 defined restore integrity gates, row invariants, and no-secret-log evidence.</change-3>
    <change-4>v1.3.0 - Phase-22 step-6 linked restore sequence evidence to bundle validation outputs.</change-4>
    <change-5>v1.4.0 - Phase-22 marked blocked-live until trusted bundle restore dry-run evidence exists.</change-5>
  </change-summary>

  <maintenance-freeze>
    <freeze-1 order="1">Announce maintenance window and stop non-essential operator actions that mutate users, plans, subscriptions, devices, or VPN clients.</freeze-1>
    <freeze-2 order="2">Record incident mode, operator identity, current app version or git commit, old RU/DE addresses, and expected data-loss tolerance.</freeze-2>
    <freeze-3 order="3">Capture service inventory: backend, frontend, admin, PostgreSQL, Redis, RU AWG, DE AWG, and reverse proxy status.</freeze-3>
    <freeze-4 order="4">Capture pre-backup table counts before database dump: users, subscriptions, payments, devices, vpn clients, plans, audit events, and migration state.</freeze-4>
    <freeze-5 order="5">Capture VPN topology metadata: client subnet, relay subnet, RU endpoint, DE endpoint, AWG profile fingerprints, and peer count without exposing private keys.</freeze-5>
    <freeze-6 order="6">Confirm whether old servers remain rollback candidates before deploying replacement servers.</freeze-6>
  </maintenance-freeze>

  <pre-backup-evidence>
    <evidence-app-version>Application version, release tag, or git commit used by the old deployment.</evidence-app-version>
    <evidence-node-addresses>Old RU and DE public addresses, internal relay addresses, and planned replacement addresses when known.</evidence-node-addresses>
    <evidence-table-counts>table_counts.before.json with critical table counts and timestamp.</evidence-table-counts>
    <evidence-migration-state>migration_state.before.txt with Alembic/current schema state or explicit create_all compatibility note.</evidence-migration-state>
    <evidence-vpn-fingerprints>AWG profile and peer fingerprints only; raw private keys and preshared keys are prohibited in evidence logs.</evidence-vpn-fingerprints>
  </pre-backup-evidence>

  <backup-bundle-contract>
    <bundle-root>krotpn-dr-bundle-YYYYMMDD-HHMMSS/</bundle-root>
    <artifact-1 name="manifest.json" required="true">
      <contains>bundle_id, created_at, source_ru, source_de, app_version, schema_version, artifact list, sha256 checksums, table counts, and redaction confirmation.</contains>
      <secret-policy>Manifest may record key names and fingerprints but must not contain secret values.</secret-policy>
    </artifact-1>
    <artifact-2 name="postgres.dump" required="true">
      <contains>PostgreSQL custom-format dump or operator-approved equivalent covering users, subscriptions, payments, devices, vpn clients, plans, audit events, and migration state.</contains>
      <restore-role>Primary data source for replacement database restore.</restore-role>
    </artifact-2>
    <artifact-3 name="runtime-env.enc" required="true">
      <contains>Protected runtime environment material needed for backend, database, Redis, billing, Telegram, admin bootstrap, encryption, and JWT validation.</contains>
      <restore-role>Bootstraps replacement deployment without guessing secrets.</restore-role>
    </artifact-3>
    <artifact-4 name="vpn-state.tar.enc" required="true">
      <contains>AWG profiles, server public/private key material, preshared-key material when present, subnet settings, relay profile, peer state, and device-client linkage export.</contains>
      <restore-role>Preserves existing client config compatibility unless explicit rotation is approved.</restore-role>
    </artifact-4>
    <artifact-5 name="checksums.sha256" required="true">
      <contains>SHA-256 checksum for each bundle artifact after encryption/protection.</contains>
      <restore-role>Blocks restore validation when any artifact changes unexpectedly.</restore-role>
    </artifact-5>
    <artifact-6 name="evidence/" required="true">
      <contains>table_counts.before.json, migration_state.before.txt, service_inventory.before.json, vpn_fingerprints.before.json, and restore_notes.md placeholder.</contains>
      <restore-role>Supports before/after comparison and operator handoff.</restore-role>
    </artifact-6>
  </backup-bundle-contract>

  <manifest-required-fields>
    <field-1>bundle_id</field-1>
    <field-2>created_at_utc</field-2>
    <field-3>source_app_version</field-3>
    <field-4>source_ru_address</field-4>
    <field-5>source_de_address</field-5>
    <field-6>schema_version_or_migration_state</field-6>
    <field-7>vpn_client_subnet</field-7>
    <field-8>vpn_relay_subnet</field-8>
    <field-9>artifact_checksums</field-9>
    <field-10>table_counts_before</field-10>
    <field-11>secret_redaction_confirmed</field-11>
    <field-12>operator_notes</field-12>
  </manifest-required-fields>

  <checksum-rules>
    <rule-1>Generate checksums after artifact protection/encryption so restore validates the transferred bundle exactly.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Do not pass restore validation if postgres.dump, runtime-env.enc, vpn-state.tar.enc, or manifest.json checksum is missing.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Record checksum verification output as pass/fail and artifact name only; do not print artifact contents.</rule-3>
  </checksum-rules>

  <restore-integrity-gates>
    <gate-1 name="schema-version" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>schema_version_or_migration_state from manifest matches migration_state.after.txt after restore.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Stop restore validation and inspect M-028 migration state before starting public traffic.</failure-action>
    </gate-1>
    <gate-2 name="checksum-verification" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>checksums.sha256 verifies manifest.json, postgres.dump, runtime-env.enc, vpn-state.tar.enc, and evidence files.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Reject the bundle unless operator records a signed incident waiver and alternate integrity proof.</failure-action>
    </gate-2>
    <gate-3 name="critical-table-counts" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>table_counts.after.json matches table_counts.before.json for users, subscriptions, payments, devices, vpn clients, plans, audit events, and migration rows within explicit tolerance.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Do not cut over until discrepancy is explained and accepted.</failure-action>
    </gate-3>
    <gate-4 name="selected-row-invariants" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Sampled active users retain subscription status, device rows retain user linkage, VPN clients retain device/client linkage, and billing records retain payment/subscription linkage.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Block cutover because relational integrity may be corrupted.</failure-action>
    </gate-4>
    <gate-5 name="no-secret-log-evidence" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>restore_notes.md confirms restore output was reviewed for secret exposure and contains artifact names, pass/fail checks, and fingerprints only.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Stop and rotate exposed material or record an explicit incident decision.</failure-action>
    </gate-5>
  </restore-integrity-gates>

  <row-invariants>
    <invariant-1>Every active subscription references an existing user.</invariant-1>
    <invariant-2>Every device row references an existing user and preserves revoked/blocked state.</invariant-2>
    <invariant-3>Every active VPN client references an existing user and, when present, the expected device identifier.</invariant-3>
    <invariant-4>Payment records retain provider identifiers and subscription linkage without duplicate successful webhook effects.</invariant-4>
    <invariant-5>Migration state after restore is not older than the source migration state.</invariant-5>
  </row-invariants>

  <restore-sequence-evidence>
    <evidence-1>restore_notes.md records bundle verification, runtime env restore, database restore, VPN state restore, migration-state comparison, and service-start decision.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>table_counts.after.json is produced after PostgreSQL restore and before application cutover.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>vpn_fingerprints.after.json is produced after VPN/AWG restore and before client compatibility validation.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>service_start_notes.md records whether services were started only after integrity gates passed.</evidence-4>
  </restore-sequence-evidence>

  <cutover-evidence-retention>
    <item-1>Keep the source backup bundle immutable until post-cutover monitoring is complete.</item-1>
    <item-2>Keep table_counts.before.json and table_counts.after.json available for rollback decisions.</item-2>
    <item-3>Keep restore_notes.md, service_start_notes.md, vpn_fingerprints.after.json, and client_compatibility_after.json attached to incident handoff notes.</item-3>
  </cutover-evidence-retention>

  <vpn-restore-evidence>
    <evidence-1>vpn_fingerprints.before.json and vpn_fingerprints.after.json compare AWG profile fingerprints without raw key output.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>vpn_network_after.json records VPN_CLIENT_SUBNET, VPN_RELAY_SUBNET, VPN_CAPACITY_PROFILE, and VPN_NETWORK_ROTATE state.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>client_compatibility_after.json records sampled existing client/device config compatibility and whether rotation was required.</evidence-3>
  </vpn-restore-evidence>

  <secret-redaction-policy>
    <rule-1>Never print raw .env, JWT secret, data encryption key, database password, Telegram token, YooKassa secret, AWG private key, or preshared key.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Evidence may include artifact names, byte sizes, checksums, key presence booleans, and non-secret fingerprints.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Any accidental secret exposure blocks Phase-22 evidence until the value is rotated or the operator records an incident waiver.</rule-3>
  </secret-redaction-policy>
</BACKUP-PHASE-22>
