<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DR-PHASE-22 NAME="Emergency Server Relocation Runbook" STATUS="blocked-live" MODULE="M-034" CREATED="2026-05-10">
  <contract>
    <purpose>Guide the operator through emergency or planned relocation of KrotPN to replacement RU/DE servers.</purpose>
    <scope>Incident classification, decision points, freeze, backup, replacement deployment checkpoint, restore, validation, cutover, rollback, and evidence capture.</scope>
    <depends>M-034, M-035, M-001, M-003, M-012, M-028, M-032</depends>
    <links>docs/modules/M-034.xml docs/plans/Phase-22.xml docs/verification/V-M-034.xml</links>
    <role>OPERATOR_RUNBOOK</role>
    <map-mode>SUMMARY</map-mode>
  </contract>

  <module-map>
    <section-incident-modes>Classifies recovery mode before any action is taken.</section-incident-modes>
    <section-decision-points>Defines operator go/no-go choices and required evidence.</section-decision-points>
    <section-replacement-server-runbook>Defines replacement RU/DE deployment checkpoint using existing approved scripts unchanged.</section-replacement-server-runbook>
    <section-restore-sequence>Defines ordered database, runtime, VPN, migration, and service-start restore sequence.</section-restore-sequence>
    <section-vpn-validation>Defines tunnel, profile, address-pool, client compatibility, and rotation-guard checks.</section-vpn-validation>
    <section-application-validation>Defines application, auth, billing, device, database, Redis, frontend, and admin checks.</section-application-validation>
    <section-cutover-rollback>Defines go/no-go, cutover, rollback, and post-cutover monitoring procedure.</section-cutover-rollback>
    <section-live-boundaries>Separates local dry-run evidence from live VPS evidence.</section-live-boundaries>
  </module-map>

  <change-summary>
    <change-1>v1.0.0 - Phase-22 step-1 created incident modes and operator decision points.</change-1>
    <change-2>v1.1.0 - Phase-22 step-2 added maintenance/freeze sequence and backup evidence handoff.</change-2>
    <change-3>v1.2.0 - Phase-22 step-5 added replacement-server runbook and restore checkpoint.</change-3>
    <change-4>v1.3.0 - Phase-22 step-6 added ordered restore sequence and service-start gate.</change-4>
    <change-5>v1.4.0 - Phase-22 step-7 added VPN-specific validation and rotation guard.</change-5>
    <change-6>v1.5.0 - Phase-22 step-8 added application validation gates.</change-6>
    <change-7>v1.6.0 - Phase-22 step-9 added cutover, rollback, and monitoring procedure.</change-7>
    <change-8>v1.7.0 - Phase-22 marked blocked-live until non-production restore rehearsal is performed.</change-8>
  </change-summary>

  <incident-modes>
    <mode-1 id="TOTAL_SERVER_LOSS" severity="critical">
      <trigger>RU and/or DE server is unavailable and old-server rollback may be impossible.</trigger>
      <operator-decision>Start emergency restore from the latest verified backup bundle; record backup age and expected data loss window.</operator-decision>
      <rollback-eligibility>Rollback is unavailable unless the old provider or snapshots recover before cutover.</rollback-eligibility>
    </mode-1>
    <mode-2 id="PLANNED_PROVIDER_MIGRATION" severity="high">
      <trigger>Operator intentionally moves service to replacement RU/DE servers.</trigger>
      <operator-decision>Schedule maintenance, freeze risky writes, capture fresh backup, deploy replacement servers, then cut over only after validation.</operator-decision>
      <rollback-eligibility>Rollback remains available while old servers and DNS/IP target are still controlled by the operator.</rollback-eligibility>
    </mode-2>
    <mode-3 id="PARTIAL_RU_FAILURE" severity="critical">
      <trigger>RU entry node or RU-hosted application stack fails while DE exit may still be healthy.</trigger>
      <operator-decision>Prioritize RU replacement because user/API/admin surfaces and entry tunnel terminate there.</operator-decision>
      <rollback-eligibility>Rollback depends on RU host recoverability and preservation of database/runtime state.</rollback-eligibility>
    </mode-3>
    <mode-4 id="PARTIAL_DE_FAILURE" severity="high">
      <trigger>DE exit node fails while RU application stack is still reachable.</trigger>
      <operator-decision>Replace DE, validate RU-DE tunnel and exit egress, and avoid client rotation unless compatibility checks fail.</operator-decision>
      <rollback-eligibility>Rollback is possible if old DE recovers and tunnel profile parity is preserved.</rollback-eligibility>
    </mode-4>
    <mode-5 id="SECURITY_INCIDENT_RELOCATION" severity="critical">
      <trigger>Operator suspects server compromise, leaked secret material, or untrusted host access.</trigger>
      <operator-decision>Relocate with explicit secret rotation decision; preserve data only after assessing backup trust.</operator-decision>
      <rollback-eligibility>Rollback to old servers is blocked unless compromise is disproven.</rollback-eligibility>
    </mode-5>
  </incident-modes>

  <decision-points>
    <decision-1 name="enter-maintenance">
      <required-evidence>Incident mode, operator identity, latest backup age, old-server availability, and user-impact note.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>Operator confirms recovery or migration is safer than waiting.</go-condition>
      <abort-condition>Incident is transient and old servers can be safely restored without relocation.</abort-condition>
    </decision-1>
    <decision-2 name="backup-or-use-existing-bundle">
      <required-evidence>Fresh backup availability or explicit reason why only an existing bundle can be used.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>Backup bundle exists and its manifest can be checked before restore.</go-condition>
      <abort-condition>No trusted backup exists and operator has not accepted data-loss risk.</abort-condition>
    </decision-2>
    <decision-3 name="deploy-replacement">
      <required-evidence>Target RU/DE IPs, OS readiness, SSH access, and confirmation that existing deploy/install scripts will be used unchanged.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>Replacement hosts are ready and no script redesign is required.</go-condition>
      <abort-condition>Deployment would require unplanned changes to deploy/ or install.sh.</abort-condition>
    </decision-3>
    <decision-4 name="restore-validation">
      <required-evidence>Manifest checksums, table counts, migration state, AWG profile parity, and no-secret-log review.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>All restore checks pass or operator records an explicit risk waiver.</go-condition>
      <abort-condition>Critical counts, checksums, or client-compatibility checks fail.</abort-condition>
    </decision-4>
    <decision-5 name="cutover">
      <required-evidence>Backend, frontend, admin, auth, billing read path, Redis, RU-DE tunnel, and existing client/device validation.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>Replacement deployment is healthier than the old target and rollback status is known.</go-condition>
      <abort-condition>Any critical health, auth, payment-read, or VPN handshake gate is missing.</abort-condition>
    </decision-5>
  </decision-points>

  <maintenance-freeze-handoff>
    <handoff-1>Before backup capture, follow docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml maintenance-freeze steps in order.</handoff-1>
    <handoff-2>Do not start replacement deployment until pre-backup evidence names app version, old RU/DE addresses, table counts, migration state, and rollback candidate status.</handoff-2>
    <handoff-3>If old servers are unavailable, record why fresh backup capture is impossible and use the latest trusted backup bundle only after operator accepts data-loss risk.</handoff-3>
  </maintenance-freeze-handoff>

  <replacement-server-runbook>
    <stage-1 name="target-preflight">
      <operator-action>Confirm replacement RU and DE hosts, OS baseline, SSH access, DNS/IP plan, and whether old servers remain rollback candidates.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>target_hosts.md with RU/DE addresses, provider names, access owner, and rollback status.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Target hosts require unplanned changes to deploy/, install.sh, nginx, or docker-compose.yml before restore.</blocked-if>
    </stage-1>
    <stage-2 name="fresh-deploy">
      <operator-action>Run the existing operator-approved install/deploy flow exactly as currently documented for a fresh RU/DE deployment.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>deploy_notes.md states which existing script entrypoint was used and records only success/failure, timestamps, hostnames, and non-secret fingerprints.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Any recovery step requires editing deploy scripts or changing the approved password-based deployment flow.</blocked-if>
    </stage-2>
    <stage-3 name="restore-checkpoint-stop">
      <operator-action>After replacement deployment boots, stop at restore checkpoint before public cutover or user traffic is accepted.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>restore_checkpoint.md confirms backend/database services are ready for restore, public cutover has not happened, and secrets were not printed.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Replacement deployment is already serving production traffic before database/runtime/VPN restore validation.</blocked-if>
    </stage-3>
    <stage-4 name="handoff-to-restore">
      <operator-action>Hand off to restore sequence only after the backup manifest, checksums, and target-host evidence are available.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>manifest.json, checksums.sha256, target_hosts.md, and restore_checkpoint.md.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Backup bundle is missing or restore target cannot be isolated from users during restore.</blocked-if>
    </stage-4>
  </replacement-server-runbook>

  <restore-sequence>
    <restore-1 order="1" name="verify-bundle-before-restore">
      <operator-action>Verify manifest and checksums before loading any data into the replacement environment.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>checksums.sha256 pass, manifest.json present, and restore_notes.md started.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Any required bundle artifact is missing or checksum verification fails.</blocked-if>
    </restore-1>
    <restore-2 order="2" name="restore-runtime-env">
      <operator-action>Restore protected runtime environment material to the replacement deployment without printing secret values.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>runtime env keys present as booleans/fingerprints only; no raw secret output.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Backend, database, Redis, billing, Telegram, JWT, or encryption keys are missing.</blocked-if>
    </restore-2>
    <restore-3 order="3" name="restore-postgres">
      <operator-action>Restore postgres.dump into the replacement PostgreSQL target while public traffic remains blocked.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>restore_notes.md records dump file name, restore status, table_counts.after.json, and no secret output.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Database restore exits with errors or critical table counts cannot be captured.</blocked-if>
    </restore-3>
    <restore-4 order="4" name="restore-vpn-state">
      <operator-action>Restore AWG profiles, subnet settings, server key material, peer state, and device-client linkage from vpn-state.tar.enc.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>vpn_fingerprints.after.json matches expected profile fingerprints and peer counts within explicit tolerance.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Restored VPN state would silently invalidate existing client configs.</blocked-if>
    </restore-4>
    <restore-5 order="5" name="verify-migration-state">
      <operator-action>Compare source and restored migration state, then run compatibility checks before application startup.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>migration_state.after.txt is present and matches or supersedes the source state.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Migration state is older than source or incompatible with restored database contents.</blocked-if>
    </restore-5>
    <restore-6 order="6" name="start-services-after-validation">
      <operator-action>Start services only after restore integrity gates pass; keep cutover blocked until application and VPN validation complete.</operator-action>
      <required-evidence>service_start_notes.md with startup status and link to validation checklist.</required-evidence>
      <blocked-if>Restore integrity gates are incomplete, waived without operator note, or failed.</blocked-if>
    </restore-6>
  </restore-sequence>

  <vpn-validation>
    <vpn-check-1 name="ru-de-tunnel-health" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>RU and DE AWG interfaces are up, relay addresses are reachable, and tunnel handshake is fresh enough for operator-defined tolerance.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Do not cut over; inspect host-level AWG/routing state on replacement RU/DE.</failure-action>
    </vpn-check-1>
    <vpn-check-2 name="awg-profile-parity" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Restored CLIENT_PROFILE and RELAY_PROFILE fingerprints match the expected bundle fingerprints; raw keys are not printed.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Stop validation because client and relay handshakes may fail after cutover.</failure-action>
    </vpn-check-2>
    <vpn-check-3 name="address-pool-compatibility" live-required="false" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Restored VPN_CLIENT_SUBNET, VPN_RELAY_SUBNET, VPN_CAPACITY_PROFILE, and stored VPNClient addresses match M-032 capacity and no-silent-migration rules.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Abort cutover unless operator explicitly approves address-pool rotation and client reprovisioning.</failure-action>
    </vpn-check-3>
    <vpn-check-4 name="existing-client-config-behavior" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>At least one existing user/device config path is validated without forced rotation; generated config still uses the restored address and profile values.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Do not cut over because existing users may lose connectivity.</failure-action>
    </vpn-check-4>
    <vpn-check-5 name="explicit-rotation-guard" live-required="false" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>restore_notes.md records VPN_NETWORK_ROTATE state. If rotation is needed, operator approval and client communication plan are attached.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Block any silent client address/profile rewrite.</failure-action>
    </vpn-check-5>
  </vpn-validation>

  <application-validation>
    <app-check-1 name="backend-health" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Backend health endpoint responds on replacement RU and reports service readiness without leaking env values.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Do not cut over; inspect backend startup, env, and database connectivity.</failure-action>
    </app-check-1>
    <app-check-2 name="database-and-redis" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Database session opens successfully, restored critical counts are visible to the app, and Redis/token-blacklist dependency is reachable or documented as degraded but safe.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Stop validation if auth/session behavior could be inconsistent.</failure-action>
    </app-check-2>
    <app-check-3 name="user-admin-auth-smoke" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>User login/session path and admin login/session path succeed or fail only for expected credential reasons; 401/403 behavior remains intact.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Block cutover because operators or users may be locked out.</failure-action>
    </app-check-3>
    <app-check-4 name="frontend-admin-reachability" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>User frontend and admin frontend load over the intended replacement endpoint with no mixed-target or old-host dependency.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Do not switch DNS/IP until web surfaces point at the replacement stack.</failure-action>
    </app-check-4>
    <app-check-5 name="billing-read-path" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>Plans, active subscriptions, payment records, and subscription status read paths return restored data without creating new payments.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Block cutover until billing state is readable and side-effect-free.</failure-action>
    </app-check-5>
    <app-check-6 name="device-listing" live-required="true" blocks-cutover="true">
      <required-evidence>User/admin device listing returns restored devices, blocked/revoked state, and device-client linkage.</required-evidence>
      <failure-action>Block cutover because config provisioning and anti-sharing controls may be inconsistent.</failure-action>
    </app-check-6>
  </application-validation>

  <cutover-rollback-procedure>
    <go-no-go-gate>
      <required-evidence>Restore integrity gates pass, VPN validation passes, application validation passes, backup bundle is preserved, and rollback status is known.</required-evidence>
      <go-condition>Operator signs off that replacement RU/DE is healthier than the old target and that rollback path is available or explicitly waived.</go-condition>
      <no-go-condition>Any critical checksum, table count, migration, auth, billing, frontend/admin, Redis, device, or VPN gate is missing or failed.</no-go-condition>
    </go-no-go-gate>
    <cutover-steps>
      <step-1>Record final pre-cutover timestamp, operator identity, replacement RU/DE addresses, old target status, and rollback target.</step-1>
      <step-2>Switch DNS/IP/operator traffic target only after go/no-go gate is passed.</step-2>
      <step-3>Immediately rerun backend, frontend, admin, auth, billing read, device listing, RU/DE tunnel, and existing client config smoke checks.</step-3>
      <step-4>Record post-cutover monitoring start time and expected observation window.</step-4>
    </cutover-steps>
    <rollback-checkpoints>
      <checkpoint-1 name="pre-cutover">Abort before switching traffic if any validation gate fails.</checkpoint-1>
      <checkpoint-2 name="immediate-post-cutover">Rollback to old target if health, auth, admin access, billing read, or VPN handshake fails after switching.</checkpoint-2>
      <checkpoint-3 name="monitoring-window">Rollback or pause user onboarding if error rate, failed auth, failed config downloads, or VPN handshake failures exceed operator tolerance.</checkpoint-3>
      <checkpoint-4 name="no-rollback">If old servers are unavailable, record explicit no-rollback decision and increase monitoring/evidence requirements.</checkpoint-4>
    </rollback-checkpoints>
    <post-cutover-monitoring>
      <monitor-1>Backend and admin health responses.</monitor-1>
      <monitor-2>User login, admin login, billing read, and config download smoke checks.</monitor-2>
      <monitor-3>RU/DE tunnel freshness and at least one existing client/device config path.</monitor-3>
      <monitor-4>New errors that may indicate missing runtime env, Redis, database, or VPN state.</monitor-4>
    </post-cutover-monitoring>
  </cutover-rollback-procedure>

  <live-boundaries>
    <local-only>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, manifest schema review, and non-production dry-run can prove document and procedure consistency.</local-only>
    <live-required>Replacement VPS deployment, RU-DE tunnel health, DNS/IP cutover, and existing user config connectivity require live or restore-target evidence.</live-required>
  </live-boundaries>
</DR-PHASE-22>
