<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-26 NAME="Stabilization Gates and Operator Handoff" STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-033,M-034,M-035,M-036,M-037,M-038,M-039" CREATED="2026-05-10" UPDATED="2026-05-10">
  <goal>
    Close the improvement wave with explicit verification gates, operator handoff, and a clear record of local versus live
    evidence.
  </goal>

  <scope>
    <included>Verification matrix, MyGRACE refresh, UI/mobile smoke reports, DR dry-run status, and operator handoff notes.</included>
    <excluded>New product features beyond the planned cleanup, recovery, UI, and session hardening work.</excluded>
  </scope>

  <step-1 MODULE="M-033" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done-local">
    Run MyGRACE integrity review and ensure indexes, per-module files, per-phase files, and verification files are synchronized.
  </step-1>

  <step-2 MODULE="M-034,M-035" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done-local">
    Record disaster recovery dry-run status, blocked live checks, backup manifest shape, and restore evidence expectations.
  </step-2>

  <step-3 MODULE="M-036,M-037,M-038" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="done-local">
    Record mobile UI verification evidence for user and admin frontends, including viewport coverage and unresolved UX issues.
  </step-3>

  <step-4 MODULE="M-039" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done-local">
    Record auth/session smoke evidence and any remaining compatibility risks.
  </step-4>

  <step-5 MODULE="M-033,M-034" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="done-local">
    Produce final operator handoff: what changed, how to verify, how to recover, and what must not be touched without approval.
  </step-5>

  <verification>
    <check-1>All planned verification entries have pass, pending, blocked, or live-required evidence status.</check-1>
    <check-2>Operator handoff states that deploy/install scripts were not modified by this wave.</check-2>
    <check-3>Known residual risks are documented with next recommended phase.</check-3>
  </verification>
  <outcome>
    <result-1>Created docs/handoff/STABILIZATION-PHASE-26.xml with verification matrix, operator handoff, protected surfaces, and remaining live-required gates.</result-1>
    <result-2>Recorded Phase-22 as blocked-live and Phase-23/24/25 as locally verified with explicit evidence links.</result-2>
    <result-3>Confirmed deploy/install surfaces are out of scope and must remain unchanged without explicit operator approval.</result-3>
  </outcome>
</Phase-26>
