<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-44 NAME="Email Onboarding UX and Password Recovery" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.2.0" MODULES="M-062,M-001,M-002,M-009,M-027,M-028,M-040,M-041" CREATED="2026-06-01" UPDATED="2026-06-01">
  <purpose>Improve registration trust and supportability by redesigning verification emails, clarifying check-email UX, enforcing strong passwords, adding password reset, and handling duplicate email registration clearly.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>Beautiful verification email template, password reset email template, operator note for sender avatar and deliverability, spam-folder hint in the pending registration block, removal of stale trial/VPN wording, removal of the registration right-side explanatory panel, strong-password policy, forgot/reset password flow, and duplicate-email recovery CTA.</in>
    <out>Deploy/install script changes, paid billing changes, first-handshake trial activation, cookie-only auth migration, and any guarantee that all mail clients will render a sender avatar.</out>
  </scope>
  <operator-notes>
    <note-1>Sender avatar is not a reliable backend email payload feature. KrotPN should document provider/mailbox-side options such as sender mailbox profile, domain branding, BIMI/DMARC readiness where applicable, and Resend domain verification, but code must not claim it can force avatars in every recipient mailbox.</note-1>
    <note-2>Spam placement cannot be eliminated by frontend code. The product fix is twofold: improve domain/provider deliverability and make the UI tell users to check spam if the email is missing.</note-2>
  </operator-notes>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-062,M-040" STATUS="done-local">Redesign verification email HTML/text templates with KrotPN branding, compact Russian copy, safe button/link fallback, and no token exposure in logs.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-062,M-040" STATUS="done-local">Add password reset email template and document the sender-avatar/deliverability operator boundary for Resend-backed mail.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-062,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Update registration pending UI: add spam-folder guidance, remove "trial на 3 дня и VPN-доступ", and remove the right-side explanatory block.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-062,M-002,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Implement shared strong-password policy with backend enforcement and frontend strength feedback for registration and password reset.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-062,M-002,M-028,M-027" STATUS="done-local">Add one-time password reset token storage, request endpoint, reset endpoint, TTL, replay protection, and rate-limit hooks.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-062,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Add forgot-password and reset-password frontend screens with compact mobile-first layout and safe success/error states.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-062,M-041,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Return explicit duplicate-email registration guidance with a reset-password CTA while keeping throttling and safe logs.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-062" STATUS="done-local">Run backend auth/email tests, frontend build, Phase-44 smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and verify no deploy/install files changed.</step-8>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>User registers -> M-041 creates pending registration -> M-040 sends branded verification email -> M-009 pending screen tells user to check inbox and spam.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>User forgets password -> M-002 validates request shape and throttling -> M-040 sends reset email -> M-002 consumes token once -> M-027 password hash update.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>Duplicate registration -> M-041 identifies existing email -> M-009 shows account-exists message and reset CTA without creating pending side effects.</flow-3>
  </data-flow>
  <mental-walkthroughs>
    <walkthrough-1>Normal registration: user enters strong password, sees check-email state with spam hint, verifies email, and proceeds without stale 3-day wording.</walkthrough-1>
    <walkthrough-2>Weak password: frontend warns early, backend rejects deterministically, no pending registration or provider email is created.</walkthrough-2>
    <walkthrough-3>Forgot password: user requests reset, receives email, token works once, replay fails, and no token or raw email provider payload appears in logs.</walkthrough-3>
  </mental-walkthroughs>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1>Verification and reset email templates render HTML and text fallback and never log tokens or provider secrets.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Registration pending UI includes spam-folder guidance and contains no "trial на 3 дня", immediate VPN access promise, or removed right-side info panel.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Strong-password policy is enforced server-side and reflected client-side.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Password reset tokens are one-time, TTL-bound, and replay-safe.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Duplicate-email registration clearly offers password recovery.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Frontend remains compact and mobile-safe.</gate-6>
    <gate-7>Deploy/install scripts remain untouched.</gate-7>
  </phase-gates>
  <risks>
    <risk-1 severity="high">Password reset expands the account takeover surface if token TTL, replay checks, or throttling are weak.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="medium">Explicit duplicate-email messaging improves UX but increases enumeration clarity; throttling and safe provider responses are required.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="medium">Email deliverability and avatars are partly external to KrotPN and must be documented honestly.</risk-3>
  </risks>
  <verification>
    <commands>
      <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_email_delivery.py tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_password_recovery.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-44.xml docs/modules/M-062.xml docs/modules/M-002.xml docs/modules/M-009.xml docs/modules/M-028.xml docs/modules/M-040.xml docs/verification/V-M-062.xml docs/verification/V-M-002.xml docs/verification/V-M-009.xml docs/verification/V-M-028.xml docs/verification/V-M-040.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/requirements.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
      <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
    </commands>
  </verification>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-06-01: backend Phase-44 auth/email/migration tests passed outside sandbox because sandbox aiosqlite in-memory DB hangs; result was 29 passed in 0.84s.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-06-01: frontend npm run build passed and node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs passed.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: XML parse and MyGRACE lint passed.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>deploy/install scripts were intentionally untouched by Phase-44 execution.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
</Phase-44>
