<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-29 NAME="MTProto Provisioning Core" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.2.0" UPDATED="2026-05-14">
  <Goal>Port the required KPprotoN provisioning logic into KrotPN with Postgres-backed assignment state.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-042,M-043,M-001,M-002,M-028</Modules>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No public MTProto runtime edge changes yet.</item-1>
    <item-2>No user dashboard work yet.</item-2>
    <item-3>No deploy/install script changes.</item-3>
  </NonGoals>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Add MTProto settings: base domain, proxy port, base secret, private salt, SNI prefix strategy, and rotation marker.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Create Postgres assignment model and Alembic migration for M-042 with unique user and SNI constraints.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Implement deterministic SNI generation under krotpn.xyz and collision-safe fallback policy.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Implement derived fake-TLS secret generation and tg://proxy assembly using KPprotoN-compatible test vectors.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Add idempotent issue/reissue service that stores assignment metadata and returns owner-safe proxy payload.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="done-local">Add backend tests for assignment persistence, derived credential behavior, rotation warning, and migration compatibility.</step-6>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
    <command>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-29.xml docs/verification/V-M-042.xml docs/verification/V-M-043.xml docs/verification-index.xml; mygrace lint</command>
  </Verification>
  <VerificationMatrix>
    <matrix-1 module="M-042" level="module-local">Assignment model, repository idempotency, uniqueness constraints, restore-safe fields, migration compatibility, and secret/link redaction.</matrix-1>
    <matrix-2 module="M-043" level="module-local">Deterministic wildcard-safe SNI, derived fake-TLS secret vectors, tg://proxy assembly, idempotent issue/reissue, and safe failure paths.</matrix-2>
    <matrix-3 module="M-001,M-002,M-028" level="wave-level">Settings validation, verified-user precondition, Alembic coverage, and no regressions in existing auth/migration contracts.</matrix-3>
    <matrix-4 module="M-041" level="phase-level">No MTProto proxy is issued before verified-email activation; automatic issuance remains deferred until later integration phases unless explicitly added to Phase-29 execution.</matrix-4>
  </VerificationMatrix>
  <PreflightGates>
    <gate-1>Execution may stay module-local, but release-level closure must acknowledge Phase-28 partial-local V-M-004 and V-M-022 debt until those route/API gates pass.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Automated tests must not call live Telegram, mutate host VPN state, or touch deploy/install scripts.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>All logs and admin-safe responses must redact base secret, salt, derived secret, token material, and full tg://proxy links.</gate-3>
  </PreflightGates>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>One verified user maps to one canonical MTProto assignment unless explicit rotation is requested.</item-1>
    <item-2>Derived secret differs from raw base secret and is bound to the assigned SNI.</item-2>
    <item-3>Assignment restore from Postgres is sufficient to rebuild user-safe response payloads.</item-3>
    <item-4>Base secret or salt rotation is represented as a reissue-required condition.</item-4>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Completion>
    <item-1>M-042 now has SQLModel assignment metadata, a repository, unique user/SNI invariants, and an Alembic revision for mtproto_assignments.</item-1>
    <item-2>M-043 now has deterministic SNI generation, KPprotoN-compatible fake-TLS derivation, tg://proxy assembly, and idempotent verified-user issue/reissue service.</item-2>
    <item-3>Phase-29 backend verification passed locally: 14 targeted tests across assignment registry, provisioning, and migration evidence.</item-3>
  </Completion>
  <RefreshNotes>
    <note-1>Release-level closure still inherits Phase-28 partial-local debt for V-M-004 and V-M-022 route/API gates; Phase-29 itself is module-local complete.</note-1>
  </RefreshNotes>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Wrong fake-TLS secret format will produce links Telegram rejects even if backend tests pass superficially.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Storing full proxy links unnecessarily increases breach impact.</risk-2>
  </Risks>
</Phase-29>
