<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-36 NAME="Resend Deploy Email Provider Wiring" STATUS="passed-live" VERSION="1.3.0">
  <Goal>Make clean production deployments configure Resend email delivery so verified-registration emails are sent instead of failing with provider_disabled.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-040,M-041,M-012,M-001,M-048</Modules>
  <OperatorIntent>
    <item-1>The production email provider is Resend.</item-1>
    <item-2>The installer asks for the Resend API key during clean VPS deployment.</item-2>
    <item-3>The sender address is noreply@krotpn.xyz after the operator verifies krotpn.xyz in Resend.</item-3>
  </OperatorIntent>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No custom mail server, SMTP migration, or alternate provider selection in this phase.</item-1>
    <item-2>No live email send in automated tests because API keys and real recipients are operator-controlled secrets.</item-2>
    <item-3>No frontend redesign; user-facing behavior remains the existing check-email and verify-email flow.</item-3>
  </NonGoals>
  <DataFlow>
    <flow-1>install.sh collects PUBLIC_DOMAIN, TLS paths, then prompts for RESEND_API_KEY with secret input and EMAIL_FROM defaulting to noreply@krotpn.xyz.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>install.sh validates that the Resend API key and sender email are non-empty and safe for temporary deploy config materialization.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>install.sh writes redaction-safe values into /tmp/krotpn_deploy.conf without printing the API key.</flow-3>
    <flow-4>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh writes EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL, EMAIL_FROM, and EMAIL_VERIFICATION_URL_BASE into /opt/KrotPN/.env.</flow-4>
    <flow-5>M-040 ResendEmailProvider sends verification email through https://api.resend.com/emails; M-041 blocks registration activation until the email token is verified.</flow-5>
  </DataFlow>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Extend install.sh input collection with secret Resend API key prompt and sender email prompt defaulting to noreply@krotpn.xyz.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Validate Resend API key and sender email format without accepting shell metacharacters, newlines, or empty values.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Pass RESEND_API_KEY, EMAIL_PROVIDER, EMAIL_FROM, and RESEND_API_URL through the temporary RU deploy config with redacted operator output.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="pass-local">Update deploy/deploy-on-server.sh .env generation so clean production deploys enable Resend instead of leaving EMAIL_PROVIDER disabled.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="pass-local">Add deterministic Resend request-shape, deploy env, installer prompt, redaction, and registration-provider smoke coverage.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="passed-live">Apply a live hotfix path for already-deployed RU servers by setting Resend env values and restarting backend after operator domain verification is ready.</step-6>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command-1>bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_email_delivery.py tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py -v</command-3>
    <command-4>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-36.xml docs/modules/M-040.xml docs/modules/M-041.xml docs/modules/M-012.xml docs/modules/M-001.xml docs/modules/M-048.xml docs/verification/V-M-001.xml docs/verification/V-M-012.xml docs/verification/V-M-040.xml docs/verification/V-M-041.xml docs/verification/V-M-048.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-4>
    <command-5 status="pass-live">operator-live: after krotpn.xyz is verified in Resend, submit one registration to a controlled mailbox and verify the email is delivered without logging API key or token.</command-5>
    <command-6 status="pass-live">operator-live-existing-ru: update /opt/KrotPN/.env with Resend values, restart backend, then repeat the controlled-mailbox registration smoke with redacted evidence.</command-6>
  </Verification>
  <VerificationMatrix>
    <gate-1 MODULES="M-048,M-012" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Installer collects Resend API key through secret input, defaults EMAIL_FROM to noreply@krotpn.xyz, rejects blank or unsafe values, and does not print the key.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 MODULES="M-012,M-001" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Deploy-generated .env enables EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend and backend Settings accepts the Resend configuration without exposing secret material.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 MODULES="M-040" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Resend provider sends the expected POST request shape through a fake transport: endpoint, Bearer auth, sender, recipient, subject, HTML, and text payload.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 MODULES="M-041,M-040" EVIDENCE="deterministic">/register creates only pending registration state, invokes email delivery once, and does not emit provider_disabled when Resend env values are present.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 MODULES="M-040,M-041,M-048" EVIDENCE="operator-live" STATUS="passed">After Resend verifies krotpn.xyz, a controlled mailbox receives one verification email and backend/deploy logs redact API keys, tokens, and full verification links.</gate-5>
  </VerificationMatrix>
  <TelemetryRequirements>
    <marker-1>[M-048][installer_resend][PROMPT_SECRET]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-048][deploy_resend][ENV_WIRING]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-040][send_verification_email][POST_PROVIDER]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-040][send_verification_email][MAP_PROVIDER_ERROR]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-041][request_registration][PENDING_RESPONSE]</marker-5>
    <redaction-1>Telemetry may include provider name, masked recipient, HTTP status class, and safe error code.</redaction-1>
    <redaction-2>Telemetry must never include RESEND_API_KEY, verification token, full verification URL, password, provider response body, or raw .env contents.</redaction-2>
  </TelemetryRequirements>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>Fresh install asks for Resend API key and email sender, defaulting sender to noreply@krotpn.xyz.</item-1>
    <item-2>Generated .env contains EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL=https://api.resend.com/emails, EMAIL_FROM=noreply@krotpn.xyz, and EMAIL_VERIFICATION_URL_BASE=https://krotpn.xyz/verify-email.</item-2>
    <item-3>Registration no longer fails with "Email provider is disabled" when Resend API key is provided.</item-3>
    <item-4>Resend API key, verification tokens, full verification links, and provider error bodies never appear in logs, XML evidence, frontend output, or installer output.</item-4>
    <item-5>Missing Resend API key fails closed before claiming deploy success for verified-registration readiness.</item-5>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Resend can reject mail again if krotpn.xyz or noreply@krotpn.xyz sender verification drifts in the Resend dashboard.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Free Resend limits can throttle registration bursts; rate-limit errors must map to safe user/operator messages.</risk-2>
    <risk-3>API key leakage would compromise outbound email; installer, deploy, logs, and verification output must redact it.</risk-3>
    <risk-4>Strict deploy validation can block clean VPS deployment if operator does not yet have the Resend API key; the error must be explicit.</risk-4>
  </Risks>
  <AutonomousExecutionSafety>
    <safe-local>Static source smoke, fake-provider tests, Resend request-shape tests with fake httpx transport, bash syntax checks, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Future Resend API key rotation, sender/domain reverification, live mailbox receipt, and any production Resend smoke.</requires-operator>
  </AutonomousExecutionSafety>
  <ExecutionEvidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: install.sh now collects RESEND_API_KEY through secret input, validates EMAIL_FROM, and writes redacted Resend deploy config for RU.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: deploy/deploy-on-server.sh validates Resend env, writes EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL, EMAIL_FROM, and EMAIL_VERIFICATION_URL_BASE into /opt/KrotPN/.env, and aborts before deploy when the key is missing.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-17: scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs and backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py passed locally.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-19: Clean VPS registration via email succeeded after Resend API key and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender wiring, closing the provider_disabled live blocker.</evidence-4>
  </ExecutionEvidence>
</Phase-36>
