<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-42 NAME="MTProto Usage Analytics and Promotion Tag Control" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.3.0" MODULES="M-054,M-055,M-056,M-057,M-058,M-059,M-042,M-044,M-047,M-049,M-050,M-051" CREATED="2026-05-19" UPDATED="2026-05-19">
  <purpose>Give the KrotPN operator metadata-only MTProto usage analytics, abuse visibility, runtime availability proof, and safe @MTProxyBot promotion tag control without exposing proxy secrets or Telegram payload data.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>Usage events, sessions, rollups, last seen, traffic windows, errors, unknown/rejected SNI, active connections, top users, observe-only abuse signals, runtime health, req_pq proof, admin API, admin UI, and promotion tag control.</in>
    <out>Telegram chat/channel/message visibility, Telegram account inspection, payload inspection, automatic punitive blocking, deploy/install redesign, and user-facing proxy reissue unless explicitly required.</out>
  </scope>
  <privacy-boundary>
    <rule-1>MTProto analytics is transport metadata only.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Do not attempt to infer Telegram chats, channels, message content, contacts, or Telegram user ids.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Raw IP storage is avoided by default; use HMAC/hash or aggregate prefixes for distinct-client analytics.</rule-3>
  </privacy-boundary>
  <source-notes>
    <note-1>Telegram MTProxy promotion tags are obtained through @MTProxyBot and configured on the server side; see https://core.telegram.org/proxy.</note-1>
    <note-2>Existing KrotPN production path remains Phase-41 KPprotoN fake-TLS, not the superseded official MTProxy path.</note-2>
  </source-notes>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-054" STATUS="done-local">Design Alembic-backed usage event, session, rollup, last-seen, and abuse-signal tables with secret-free fields and bounded retention.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-055" STATUS="done-local">Extend KPprotoN runtime policy metadata, mtproto_proxy metric backend, active-SNI sampler, and private API to expose handshake, close, bytes, error, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, active connection, and req_pq proof telemetry.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-055,M-054" STATUS="done-local">Add backend telemetry ingestion task with cursoring, idempotent event writes, failure-safe retries, and no impact on MTProto availability.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-056" STATUS="done-local">Build aggregation service for global summary, per-proxy usage, top users, day/week/month traffic, session duration, connection count, and last seen.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-056" STATUS="done-local">Add observe-only abuse classifiers for many IP hashes, high concurrent sessions, traffic spikes, and repeated handshake failures.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-057" STATUS="done-local">Expose admin analytics APIs with filters, pagination, redaction guards, and per-assignment drill-down.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-058" STATUS="done-local">Add compact frontend-admin analytics UI with mobile-safe summary, time filters, top users, per-proxy detail, abuse signal lists, and runtime proof status.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-059" STATUS="done-local">Implement promotion tag validation, masked storage/state, explicit admin update, audit logging, and runtime apply or pending-restart semantics.</step-8>
    <step-9 MODULE="M-059,M-049,M-050" STATUS="done-local">Propagate non-blank MTPROTO_AD_TAG/PROXY_AD_TAG to the DE runtime without rotating user SNI, base secret, salt, or proxy links.</step-9>
    <step-10 MODULE="M-054,M-055,M-056,M-057,M-058,M-059" STATUS="pass-local">Run backend, runtime smoke, admin UI build, redaction smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and live optional req_pq proof before release.</step-10>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>Telegram client -> RU SNI router -> DE KPprotoN runtime -> Telegram DC.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>DE runtime emits secret-free telemetry -> backend ingestion task -> Postgres M-054 tables -> M-056 aggregation -> M-057 admin API -> M-058 admin UI.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>Admin promotion tag update -> M-059 validation/storage/audit -> runtime env/apply state -> M-057/M-058 masked status.</flow-3>
  </data-flow>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1>All telemetry payloads and admin responses pass redaction checks.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Runtime telemetry buffer overflow cannot break MTProto traffic.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Admin can view global and per-proxy stats for issued, active, disabled, reissue_required, active connections, last seen, traffic, errors, sessions, top users, and abuse signals.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Promotion tag accepts valid 32-hex tag or zero fallback, rejects blanks/malformed values, and never logs full tag.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Existing Phase-41 issued-link req_pq and Telegram Desktop/mobile proof standard remains the release bar for MTProto edge changes.</gate-5>
  </phase-gates>
  <risks>
    <risk-1 severity="high">Exact byte/session counters may require careful hooks inside or around mtproto_proxy internals.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="high">Telemetry volume can grow quickly; bounded raw event retention and rollups are required.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="medium">Mobile networks may trigger false abuse signals; Phase-42 remains observe-only.</risk-3>
    <risk-4 severity="medium">Promotion tag updates may require controlled runtime restart if hot-apply is unavailable.</risk-4>
    <risk-5 severity="medium">Live byte counters are exact globally; exact per-user byte attribution during concurrent active SNI domains still requires a deeper data-plane hook or live validation before enforcement use.</risk-5>
  </risks>
  <verification>
    <verification-design status="verification-designed">
      <gate-1 MODULES="M-054,M-055">Runtime telemetry must become idempotent database evidence without blocking MTProto traffic or storing secrets.</gate-1>
      <gate-2 MODULES="M-056">Analytics must expose issued totals, status counts, active connections, last seen, traffic windows, errors, session duration, top users, abuse signals, runtime health, and req_pq proof state.</gate-2>
      <gate-3 MODULES="M-057,M-058">Admin API and UI must be admin-only, compact on mobile, filterable, paginated where needed, and redaction-guarded.</gate-3>
      <gate-4 MODULES="M-059">Promotion tag control must accept valid 32-hex @MTProxyBot tags or zero fallback, reject blanks/malformed values, and never log or render the full tag.</gate-4>
      <gate-5 MODULES="M-049,M-050,M-051">Any runtime change must preserve Phase-41 issued-link req_pq and Telegram Desktop/mobile availability proof.</gate-5>
    </verification-design>
    <evidence-levels>
      <level-1>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and documentation/index consistency for Phase-42 artifacts.</level-1>
      <level-2>Local deterministic backend tests for M-054, M-056, M-057, and M-059.</level-2>
      <level-3>Local runtime smoke for M-055 metric backend, active-SNI sampler, private telemetry API, and promotion tag propagation using synthetic telemetry and fake tags.</level-3>
      <level-4>Frontend-admin build plus static/mobile smoke for M-058.</level-4>
      <level-5>Optional live proof after operator deploy: issued-link mtp_ping/req_pq, Telegram Desktop/mobile availability, and masked admin analytics inspection.</level-5>
    </evidence-levels>
    <redaction-gates>
      <gate-1>No full tg links, fake-TLS secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, private keys, raw public IPs, or full promotion tags in API responses, logs, telemetry, audit rows, or frontend bundles.</gate-1>
      <gate-2>Telegram chats, channels, messages, contacts, Telegram account ids, or payload content are out of scope and must not be inferred.</gate-2>
      <gate-3>Unknown/rejected SNI events are retained only with masked identifiers and safe reason codes.</gate-3>
    </redaction-gates>
    <commands>
      <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-42.xml docs/modules/M-054.xml docs/modules/M-055.xml docs/modules/M-056.xml docs/modules/M-057.xml docs/modules/M-058.xml docs/modules/M-059.xml docs/verification/V-M-054.xml docs/verification/V-M-055.xml docs/verification/V-M-056.xml docs/verification/V-M-057.xml docs/verification/V-M-058.xml docs/verification/V-M-059.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
      <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py tests/test_mtproto_runtime_telemetry_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_analytics_api.py tests/test_mtproto_promotion_tag.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_scheduler.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_ops.py tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py -v</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase42-mtproto-telemetry-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase42-mtproto-promotion-tag-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd mtproto-runtime &amp;&amp; rebar3 compile</command>
    </commands>
    <autonomous-execution-safety>
      <safe-local>Documentation, local unit tests, static smoke scripts, frontend build, and synthetic runtime fixtures are safe to execute autonomously.</safe-local>
      <blocked-live>Production runtime restart, real promotion tag apply, retention pruning, or live traffic inspection require explicit operator approval and redacted evidence only.</blocked-live>
    </autonomous-execution-safety>
  </verification>
</Phase-42>
