<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-32 NAME="Domain TLS and Shared 443 Edge" STATUS="partial-local" VERSION="1.1.0" UPDATED="2026-05-14">
  <Goal>Define and implement the krotpn.xyz production edge for HTTPS redirect, wildcard TLS, and shared 443 MTProto coexistence.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-046,M-012,M-044,M-001</Modules>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No redesign of operator-approved deploy/install scripts without explicit approval.</item-1>
    <item-2>No admin UX work in this phase.</item-2>
  </NonGoals>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Define edge settings for krotpn.xyz, canonical frontend URL, wildcard certificate paths, and MTProto SNI domain suffix.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Add static nginx/edge contract for HTTP to HTTPS redirect and canonical host handling.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Design shared 443 routing: MTProto fake-TLS by issued SNI, normal HTTPS fallback to KrotPN nginx/frontend/backend/admin.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Create local/static verification for redirect, certificate path expectations, and no accidental deploy/install rewrite.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Prepare rollback notes and staging/live smoke checklist for krotpn.xyz cutover.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="blocked-live">Run production-like smoke only after operator provides wildcard certificate and DNS readiness.</step-6>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py -v</command>
    <command>sh -c 'if [ -e .env ]; then DB_PASSWORD=phase32-compose-check docker compose config; else ln -s .env.example .env &amp;&amp; trap "rm -f .env" EXIT &amp;&amp; DB_PASSWORD=phase32-compose-check docker compose config; fi'</command>
    <command>node scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-32.xml docs/modules/M-046.xml docs/verification/V-M-046.xml docs/edge/PHASE-32-CUTOVER.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command>
    <command>blocked-live: http://krotpn.xyz redirects to https://krotpn.xyz and HTTPS/MTProto surfaces stay healthy after DNS and wildcard TLS readiness.</command>
  </Verification>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>HTTP requests to krotpn.xyz redirect permanently to HTTPS.</item-1>
    <item-2>Wildcard certificate covers krotpn.xyz and *.krotpn.xyz before MTProto production links are advertised.</item-2>
    <item-3>Shared 443 edge is tested with both normal HTTPS and at least one issued MTProto SNI.</item-3>
    <item-4>Rollback path restores the previous nginx-only 443 behavior if shared edge fails.</item-4>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>443 ownership conflict between nginx and MTProto edge can take the whole public surface down.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Let's Encrypt wildcard DNS-01 is operator-dependent and cannot be fully proven locally.</risk-2>
  </Risks>
  <Completion>
    <item-1>M-001 now exposes krotpn.xyz frontend, edge domain, wildcard certificate path, and shared 443 readiness settings.</item-1>
    <item-2>nginx now includes a canonical krotpn.xyz/www HTTP to HTTPS redirect and a wildcard HTTPS fallback server while preserving legacy default HTTP/HTTPS behavior.</item-2>
    <item-3>Phase-32 local static tests and smoke script verify redirect contract, TLS path expectations, compose config, protected deploy/install guard, and rollback runbook.</item-3>
    <item-4>M-044/M-043/M-040 regression tests passed for runtime bridge, scheduler, MTProto provisioning, email delivery, and email verification URL behavior.</item-4>
  </Completion>
  <BlockedLive>
    <item-1>Production-like smoke remains blocked until DNS points at the intended edge and a trusted wildcard certificate for krotpn.xyz and *.krotpn.xyz is installed.</item-1>
    <item-2>Actual MTProto shared 443 route must be enabled and verified during an operator rollback window; local execution only defines the safe contract and fallback.</item-2>
  </BlockedLive>
</Phase-32>
