<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-38 NAME="DE-backed MTProto Edge and RU SNI Router" STATUS="pending" VERSION="1.0.0">
  <Goal>Replace the blocked RU-only MTProto shared-443 runtime with a DE-hosted MTProto runtime and an RU public TCP 443 SNI router that preserves HTTPS while routing issued Telegram proxy SNI to DE.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-050,M-049,M-044,M-046,M-048,M-012,M-043</Modules>
  <OperatorProblem>
    <item-1>Issued MTProto proxy links exist in the user cabinet, but Telegram Desktop marks them unavailable.</item-1>
    <item-2>Phase-37 fixed missing local runtime pieces, but live RU mtproto_proxy still fails downstream Telegram handshakes.</item-2>
    <item-3>Keeping nginx on public 443 preserves the website, but leaves MTProto unavailable.</item-3>
  </OperatorProblem>
  <ArchitectureDecision>
    <item-1>RU remains the public entry for krotpn.xyz and user-issued wildcard SNI names.</item-1>
    <item-2>RU public TCP 443 is owned by an SNI router, not nginx and not the MTProto runtime.</item-2>
    <item-3>DE hosts the real MTProto runtime and handles Telegram upstream reachability.</item-3>
    <item-4>RU backend applies SNI policy to the DE runtime through a private, token-protected policy API.</item-4>
  </ArchitectureDecision>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No rotation of existing MTProto base secret, salt, SNI names, or user tg links.</item-1>
    <item-2>No redesign of billing, registration, frontend UX, or admin UX in this phase.</item-2>
    <item-3>No public exposure of the DE policy API or raw runtime health payloads.</item-3>
    <item-4>No automatic Lets Encrypt issuance; the operator-provided wildcard TLS model remains in force.</item-4>
  </NonGoals>
  <DataFlow>
    <flow-1>Browser HTTPS to krotpn.xyz:443 reaches the RU SNI router and routes to local nginx fallback on 127.0.0.1:8443.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>Telegram fake-TLS to u-*.krotpn.xyz:443 reaches the RU SNI router and routes to the DE MTProto runtime.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>Backend provisioning reuses the existing assignment and sends apply/revoke/health to the DE policy API over the private RU-DE path.</flow-3>
    <flow-4>Startup or scheduler replay sends all active assignment SNI policies to the DE runtime after deploy, restart, or restore.</flow-4>
    <flow-5>Admin/user health surfaces show degraded status when DE runtime or private policy API is unavailable, without leaking secrets.</flow-5>
  </DataFlow>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="pending">Design and document the RU TCP 443 SNI router target map for canonical web hosts, issued MTProto wildcard hosts, and unknown SNI fallback.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pending">Define DE MTProto runtime deployment, TLS mount expectations, firewall rules, service ownership, and rollback behavior.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pending">Define private RU-to-DE policy API connectivity, token handling, bind address, and deny-public checks.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="pending">Adjust runtime bridge configuration contract so apply, revoke, health, and replay target the DE runtime safely.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="pending">Preserve existing assignment credentials and replay active SNI policies without reissuing user proxy links.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="pending">Add deterministic static smoke coverage for SNI router config, DE runtime env, policy URL safety, secret redaction, and rollback notes.</step-6>
    <step-7 STATUS="pending">Run local verification: script syntax, compose config, backend MTProto tests, Phase-38 smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint.</step-7>
    <step-8 STATUS="pending">Run operator-live verification: RU HTTPS, RU router, DE runtime, private policy health, assignment replay, and Telegram Desktop availability.</step-8>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command-1>bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</command-1>
    <command-2>docker compose config</command-2>
    <command-3>node scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</command-3>
    <command-4>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py -v</command-4>
    <command-5>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/modules/M-050.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml docs/verification/V-M-050.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-5>
    <command-6>operator-live: verify RU public 443 owner is the SNI router, RU nginx fallback is healthy, DE MTProto runtime listens on its configured port, private policy health succeeds only from RU/backend, and Telegram Desktop marks the issued proxy available.</command-6>
  </Verification>
  <VerificationMatrix>
    <gate-1 MODULES="M-050,M-046" EVIDENCE="deterministic">SNI router config sends krotpn.xyz and www.krotpn.xyz to RU nginx fallback and issued wildcard SNI to DE runtime.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 MODULES="M-050,M-048" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Wildcard cert material delivery to DE is defined without printing or storing private key material in logs or XML evidence.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 MODULES="M-050,M-044" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Backend bridge targets a private DE policy API URL with token auth and redacts token/secret material.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 MODULES="M-050,M-043,M-049" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Existing assignment SNI, base secret, salt, and tg links are preserved and replayed instead of reissued.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 MODULES="M-050,M-046" EVIDENCE="operator-live">https://krotpn.xyz remains reachable after RU public 443 ownership changes to the SNI router.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 MODULES="M-050" EVIDENCE="operator-live">Telegram Desktop marks an issued user proxy available through the DE runtime route.</gate-6>
  </VerificationMatrix>
  <TelemetryRequirements>
    <marker-1>[M-050][ru_sni_router][ROUTE_WEB]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-050][ru_sni_router][ROUTE_MTPROTO]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-050][de_mtproto_runtime][START_RUNTIME]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-050][de_policy_api][HEALTH]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][POST_APPLY]</marker-5>
    <redaction-1>Never log runtime tokens, private keys, base secret, salt, derived secrets, full tg links, JWTs, Resend keys, or verification tokens.</redaction-1>
    <redaction-2>Live evidence may include service roles, public/private port roles, status codes, policy counts, and redacted SNI suffixes only.</redaction-2>
  </TelemetryRequirements>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>RU public TCP 443 routes normal HTTPS to the web fallback and MTProto SNI to DE without nginx directly owning public 443.</item-1>
    <item-2>DE runtime has Telegram upstream reachability and serves the issued fake-TLS MTProto policy.</item-2>
    <item-3>Backend apply/revoke/health works against the private DE policy API and fails degraded, not silently active, when unavailable.</item-3>
    <item-4>Existing user dashboard MTProto links remain stable unless explicit reissue is requested.</item-4>
    <item-5>HTTPS, API, admin, registration email, and VPN surfaces remain unaffected by the MTProto edge change.</item-5>
    <item-6>Telegram Desktop marks the issued proxy available in operator-live smoke.</item-6>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Misconfigured SNI routing can break both HTTPS and Telegram proxy traffic.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Copying wildcard TLS material to DE increases private-key handling risk and must stay redacted.</risk-2>
    <risk-3>Opening the DE policy API publicly would expose runtime control and is a critical deployment failure.</risk-3>
    <risk-4>Telegram availability still requires live client proof because local tests cannot emulate all Telegram network behavior.</risk-4>
  </Risks>
  <AutonomousExecutionSafety>
    <safe-local>Planning docs, static smoke, syntax checks, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and backend fake/private-adapter tests.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Public 443 routing change, DE runtime deployment, private policy API live proof, wildcard key material placement, and Telegram Desktop availability proof.</requires-operator>
  </AutonomousExecutionSafety>
</Phase-38>
