<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-43 NAME="MTProto Admin Analytics UX, Abuse Alerts and 90-day IP Observability" STATUS="verification-designed" VERSION="1.1.0" MODULES="M-001,M-008,M-026,M-028,M-042,M-047,M-054,M-055,M-056,M-057,M-058,M-060,M-061" CREATED="2026-05-20" UPDATED="2026-05-20">
  <purpose>Upgrade MTProto admin analytics into a compact operational console with abuse notifications, 90-day admin-only IP history, user search, graphs, proxy CPU/RAM metrics, and bounded storage retention.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>Remove visible Recent events, add abuse alert inbox, collect admin-only encrypted raw client IP observations for 90 days, add user/proxy search, current/last/all IP views, top-user expansion, timeseries graphs, runtime CPU/RAM metrics, auto-refresh, storage-budget retention, and confirmation-safe admin actions.</in>
    <out>Telegram chat/channel/message visibility, Telegram account inspection, payload inspection, automatic punishment without admin review, deploy/install script redesign, and exposing raw IPs to users or logs.</out>
  </scope>
  <privacy-boundary>
    <rule-1>MTProto payload, Telegram chats, channels, messages, contacts, and Telegram user ids remain out of scope.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Raw client IP is allowed only for authenticated admins, encrypted at rest, scoped to investigation screens, and retained for 90 days.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Raw IP must not be copied into application logs, audit details, non-admin APIs, frontend bundles, user responses, or smoke output.</rule-3>
    <rule-4>Unknown or untrusted IP source must be shown as source_ip_unavailable rather than inferred.</rule-4>
  </privacy-boundary>
  <retention-policy>
    <raw-events days="30">Detailed MTProto usage events are kept briefly for debugging and rollup rebuilds.</raw-events>
    <sessions days="90">Session summaries and exact encrypted IP observations are kept for the requested three-month investigation window.</sessions>
    <hourly-rollups days="90">Hourly graph data is kept for three-month admin history.</hourly-rollups>
    <daily-rollups days="365">Daily traffic, connection, duration, and error aggregates are kept for annual trend review.</daily-rollups>
    <monthly-rollups months="24">Monthly aggregates are kept for long-horizon service sizing.</monthly-rollups>
    <alerts days="180">Abuse alerts and review states are kept longer than raw IP evidence for operational accountability.</alerts>
  </retention-policy>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-054,M-061" STATUS="planned">Update telemetry privacy and retention contract so raw IP is admin-only, encrypted, and retained for 90 days while raw usage events remain bounded to 30 days.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-061,M-028" STATUS="planned">Design Alembic-backed IP observation storage with encrypted raw IP, HMAC hash, prefix, current_active, first_seen, last_seen, and assignment/user indexes.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-055,M-061" STATUS="planned">Extend KPprotoN runtime telemetry and backend ingestion to carry trustworthy client IP and proxy process resource metrics when available.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-054,M-061" STATUS="planned">Record IP observations from handshake, active connection, and close events without logging raw IP strings.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-056,M-054" STATUS="planned">Add timeseries aggregation for traffic, connections, active connections, errors, and duration across hour/day buckets.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-056,M-060" STATUS="planned">Upgrade abuse detection to create deduplicated high/critical admin alerts while keeping observe-first behavior.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-057,M-060,M-061" STATUS="planned">Expose admin-only APIs for alerts, user/proxy search, user usage detail, all IPs, current IPs, last IP, sessions, timeseries, resource metrics, and storage budget.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-047,M-026,M-060" STATUS="planned">Add confirmation-safe alert actions: acknowledge, resolve, disable proxy, and optional TTL-bound IP block with audit events.</step-8>
    <step-9 MODULE="M-058" STATUS="planned">Rebuild the admin MTProto analytics UI: remove Recent events, add Overview/Users/Abuse/Settings, longer Top users, user detail drawer, graphs, resource tiles, and compact mobile layout.</step-9>
    <step-10 MODULE="M-058,M-057" STATUS="planned">Add auto-refresh with separate intervals for summary/resources/alerts, top users, graph data, and slow-changing settings.</step-10>
    <step-11 MODULE="M-008,M-054,M-056,M-060,M-061" STATUS="planned">Schedule abuse scan, rollup rebuild, raw event prune, IP observation prune, and storage-budget health checks.</step-11>
    <step-12 MODULE="M-054,M-055,M-056,M-057,M-058,M-060,M-061" STATUS="planned">Run backend, migration, runtime, UI build, static redaction, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and optional live analytics smoke after operator deploy.</step-12>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>Telegram client -> RU SNI router -> DE KPprotoN runtime -> runtime emits SNI, event type, counters, optional client IP, and resource metrics.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>Backend telemetry ingestion -> M-054 raw events/state/sessions -> M-061 encrypted IP observations -> M-056 analytics/timeseries.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>M-056 abuse classifier -> M-060 deduplicated alert -> M-057 admin API -> M-058 compact alert inbox and user detail drawer.</flow-3>
    <flow-4>Admin reviewed action -> M-047 proxy disable or TTL IP block -> M-026 audit record -> M-060 alert resolved state.</flow-4>
  </data-flow>
  <mental-walkthroughs>
    <walkthrough-1>Clear abuse: one proxy crosses IP/concurrency thresholds, M-056 records high severity, M-060 creates one open alert, M-058 shows a badge, admin opens user detail, reviews 90-day IP history, and disables the proxy with confirmation.</walkthrough-1>
    <walkthrough-2>Normal mobile roaming: a user changes networks but remains below tuned thresholds, M-061 records IP history, no high alert is generated, and the admin can still see last/current IP context.</walkthrough-2>
    <walkthrough-3>Storage pressure: raw events older than 30 days and exact IP observations older than 90 days are pruned, while hourly/daily/monthly rollups still power three-month and older trend graphs.</walkthrough-3>
  </mental-walkthroughs>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1>Recent events are not visible in the admin MTProto analytics panel.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Admin can search a user/proxy and see issued_at, last_seen_at, all IPs for 90 days, current IPs, last IP, sessions, traffic, duration, and errors.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Admin receives visible high/critical abuse alerts and can acknowledge or resolve them.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Proxy disable and IP block actions require explicit confirmation and audit records.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Graphs and runtime CPU/RAM metrics auto-refresh without causing noisy re-layout on mobile.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Retention jobs bound storage growth while preserving three-month operational history.</gate-6>
    <gate-7>Redaction gates prove no raw IP leaks outside explicit admin investigation APIs and no secrets/tg links are exposed.</gate-7>
  </phase-gates>
  <risks>
    <risk-1 severity="high">Runtime telemetry may not always expose a trustworthy client IP; the implementation must show source_ip_unavailable instead of guessing.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="high">Raw IP observability increases privacy and data-protection responsibility; encryption, audit scope, and retention must be strict.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="medium">IP blocking can affect unrelated users behind NAT or mobile carriers; proxy disable remains the safer default action.</risk-3>
    <risk-4 severity="medium">Telemetry volume can grow quickly; retention and rollups are release gates, not optional cleanup.</risk-4>
    <risk-5 severity="medium">Exact per-user byte attribution under concurrent SNI activity remains limited until deeper data-plane hooks are proven live.</risk-5>
  </risks>
  <verification>
    <verification-design status="verification-designed">
      <gate-1 MODULES="M-061">Encrypted IP storage must decrypt only through admin-only code paths and prune exact observations after 90 days.</gate-1>
      <gate-2 MODULES="M-060">Abuse alert creation must dedupe, notify, acknowledge, resolve, and never auto-block.</gate-2>
      <gate-3 MODULES="M-057,M-058">Admin search, detail, top users, graphs, resource metrics, and auto-refresh must work on compact desktop and mobile layouts.</gate-3>
      <gate-4 MODULES="M-047,M-026">Disable proxy and IP block actions must require confirmation and write audit-safe events.</gate-4>
      <gate-5 MODULES="M-054,M-055,M-056">Telemetry ingestion, rollups, runtime metrics, and retention must not break Phase-41 MTProto availability.</gate-5>
    </verification-design>
    <commands>
      <command status="planned">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-43.xml docs/modules/M-060.xml docs/modules/M-061.xml docs/verification/V-M-060.xml docs/verification/V-M-061.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/requirements.xml</command>
      <command status="planned">mygrace lint</command>
      <command status="planned">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_ip_observability.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_analytics_api.py tests/test_scheduler.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
      <command status="planned">node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="planned">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="planned">cd mtproto-runtime &amp;&amp; rebar3 compile</command>
    </commands>
    <evidence-matrix>
      <module-local>M-061 encryption/retention, M-060 alert lifecycle, M-056 timeseries/abuse, M-057 admin-only APIs, and M-058 compact UI smokes are verified independently first.</module-local>
      <wave-level>M-054/M-055/M-056 prove telemetry -> rollup -> analytics; M-060/M-047/M-026 prove alert -> action -> audit; M-057/M-058 prove API -> UI contract.</wave-level>
      <phase-level>Phase-43 closes only after redaction, retention, mobile UI, storage budget, and no-regression MTProto availability checks pass.</phase-level>
      <live-optional>After clean deploy, operator can validate live alert visibility, graph refresh, resource metrics, and Telegram proxy continuity with redacted evidence.</live-optional>
    </evidence-matrix>
  </verification>
</Phase-43>
