<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-69 NAME="Referral Bonus Activation Correctness and Masked Invite Identity" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.0.0" MODULES="M-005,M-004,M-063,M-008,M-009,M-036,M-075,M-028,M-041" CREATED="2026-06-04" UPDATED="2026-06-04">
  <purpose>Close referral bonus debt by proving and fixing the 7-day inviter reward for paid referrals, including pending activation for inviters without an active subscription and masked referred-email display in the user cabinet.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>Referral first-payment processing, 7-day bonus subscription/grant semantics, pending first-VPN activation for bonus-only inviters, active-subscription extension, idempotency, masked referred email in owner API/UI, backend tests, frontend referral history update, and MyGRACE synchronization.</in>
    <out>Live YooKassa credential setup, deploy/install scripts, public pricing changes, referral fraud scoring, admin referral redesign, raw referred email exposure, and payment provider replacement.</out>
  </scope>
  <requirements>
    <requirement-1>A paid referral must grant exactly 7 days to the referrer only after the referred user's first qualifying paid subscription/payment succeeds.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>If the referrer already has an active non-pending subscription, the reward must extend the remaining subscription window by 7 days.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>If the referrer has no active subscription, the reward must create a pending access grant whose 7-day timer starts only after the referrer's first VPN connection.</requirement-3>
    <requirement-4>Duplicate payment webhooks or repeated process_first_payment calls must not grant the same referral bonus more than once.</requirement-4>
    <requirement-5>Referral bonus semantics must not overwrite paid, complimentary, trial, expired, or pending-trial records destructively.</requirement-5>
    <requirement-6>The user referral list must show a masked referred identity instead of "Реферал #N"; full emails must not be exposed unless a future admin-only contract explicitly allows it.</requirement-6>
    <requirement-7>Existing Phase-28 verified-registration behavior must remain: unverified pending email registration cannot create referral linkage or bonus eligibility.</requirement-7>
  </requirements>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-005,M-004,M-063" STATUS="done-local">Audit current ReferralService.process_first_payment, BillingService subscription lifecycle, pending activation fields, scheduler activation path, and referral tests.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-005,M-004,M-063,M-028" STATUS="done-local">Selected migration-free data model: reuse subscriptions.pending_activation, trial_duration_days, and access_label for referral-bonus grants.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-005,M-004" STATUS="done-local">Implemented active-subscription extension so the referrer's current access receives +7 days from the correct base without shortening access.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-005,M-004,M-063" STATUS="done-local">Implemented no-active-subscription handling so a 7-day referral grant is pending until the referrer first connects through VPN.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-063,M-008,M-003" STATUS="done-local">Reused first-handshake activation for pending referral bonus access with access_label-based user copy and scheduler/VPN stats compatibility.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-005,M-004" STATUS="done-local">Hardened idempotency around bonus_given, minimum amount checks, duplicate processing, and pending bonus transfer into paid subscriptions.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-005,M-002,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Returned masked referred email in /api/v1/referrals/list and updated frontend API types without returning raw email to the user cabinet.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-009,M-036,M-075" STATUS="done-local">Updated Referrals UI so recent invitations render masked referred identity with compact mobile-safe rows and existing bonus status badges.</step-8>
    <step-9 MODULE="M-005,M-004,M-063,M-041" STATUS="done-local">Added tests for active extension, pending grant activation, duplicate webhook idempotency, scheduler activation, paid-subscription transfer, and masked identity; backend/frontend gates passed.</step-9>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>Invitee registers with referral code -> M-041 verifies email -> M-005 creates referral link exactly once.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>Invitee payment succeeds -> M-004 webhook creates/extends invitee subscription -> M-005 processes first payment -> referrer receives 7-day extension or pending bonus grant.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>Referrer with pending bonus connects via VPN -> M-003/M-008 observes first handshake -> M-063/M-004 activates the 7-day reward window.</flow-3>
    <flow-4>User opens referrals page -> M-005 returns referral rows with masked referred identity -> M-009 renders compact "Реферал ..." history.</flow-4>
  </data-flow>
  <mental-walkthroughs>
    <walkthrough-1>Referrer has 12 days left, invitee pays: referrer expiry becomes 19 days left and duplicate webhook does not add another 7 days.</walkthrough-1>
    <walkthrough-2>Referrer has never bought a subscription, invitee pays: referrer receives pending 7-day access, then the 7 days start from the referrer's first VPN connection.</walkthrough-2>
    <walkthrough-3>Invitee registers but never verifies email or never pays: referral linkage/bonus remains absent or waiting according to existing verified-registration rules.</walkthrough-3>
  </mental-walkthroughs>
  <verification-design>
    <gate-1>Backend referral tests must assert one-time bonus application and no duplicate extension from repeated webhooks.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Billing/trial tests must assert pending referral bonus activation starts from first VPN handshake and does not overwrite paid access.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verified-registration tests must assert unverified registrations still create no referral side effects.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Frontend/API smoke must assert referral history uses masked email and never "Реферал #N" as the primary identity.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Redaction checks must fail if raw referred emails, payment IDs, tokens, VPN configs, or secrets are printed in smoke/log output.</gate-5>
  </verification-design>
  <verification>
    <commands>
      <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_referrals.py tests/test_trial_activation.py tests/test_billing_service.py tests/test_scheduler.py -v</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-69.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml</command>
      <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint; git diff --check; protected deploy/install/runtime diff guard</command>
    </commands>
  </verification>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-04>Phase-69 implemented referral-bonus active extension, pending first-VPN reward grants through access_label=referral-bonus, combined trial+bonus pending duration, pending bonus transfer into paid subscriptions, masked referred identity in /api/v1/referrals/list, compact Referrals UI rendering, and phase69 static smoke. Targeted backend tests passed 34/34; frontend build and Phase-69 smoke passed.</local-2026-06-04>
  </execution-evidence>
  <risk-assessment>
    <risk-1 severity="critical">Current referral behavior appears to skip real access for referrers without active subscriptions; Phase-69 must close that without double-granting.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="critical">Webhook retries can duplicate subscription effects unless bonus processing stays idempotent.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="high">Using normal trial fields for referral bonuses can confuse UI copy; implementation must label bonus access distinctly if needed.</risk-3>
    <risk-4 severity="medium">Showing masked email improves usefulness but must not leak full referred-user identity in user-visible API responses or logs.</risk-4>
  </risk-assessment>
  <acceptance>Referral first-payment bonus reliably grants exactly 7 useful days to the inviter, either as active extension or first-VPN pending reward, and referral history shows masked referred identity with passing backend/frontend/MyGRACE verification.</acceptance>
</Phase-69>
