<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-56 NAME="Premium Public Site and Auth" STATUS="done-local" STEPS="9">
  <objective>Build a premium public entry and auth experience that presents KrotPN clearly while preserving verified-email gates.</objective>
  <modules>M-073,M-009,M-068,M-069,M-070,M-071,M-072</modules>
  <non-goals>Changing registration backend semantics, billing catalog ownership, deploy/install scripts, or MTProto/VPN provisioning.</non-goals>
  <steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-009,M-068">
      <action>Design public entry route with KrotPN offer, VPN value, free MTProto proxy value, tariffs, and CTA.</action>
      <acceptance>frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx renders the public / route with direct registration/login CTA, truthful VPN/MTProto copy, email-proof guard copy, and canonical three-plan tariff preview.</acceptance>
    </step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-009,M-069,M-071">
      <action>Retune login/register/reset/verify screens with premium compact Matrix style and visible logo.</action>
      <acceptance>Login, register, forgot/reset password, and verify-email routes show the public logo asset and keep compact Matrix auth forms readable.</acceptance>
    </step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-009">
      <action>Preserve spam-folder guidance, duplicate-email recovery CTA, and strong-password example.</action>
      <acceptance>Phase-44 and Phase-46 smoke passed after Phase-56; registration still has spam guidance, duplicate-email recovery link, password policy example, and client-side strength checks.</acceptance>
    </step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-009">
      <action>Preserve no-access-before-email-verification language and side-effect guards.</action>
      <acceptance>Public copy states access activates only after email proof; registration still stores no JWT before verification and verify-email navigates to the protected dashboard only after successful token consumption.</acceptance>
    </step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-068">
      <action>Render tariff previews from existing canonical catalog shape without frontend price authority.</action>
      <acceptance>Landing tariff preview mirrors M-068 1/6/9, 369/693/936 RUB, 30-day catalog and never creates payment or owns checkout amount/metadata.</acceptance>
    </step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-070,M-071,M-072">
      <action>Verify phone/tablet/desktop first viewport and reduced-motion auth readability.</action>
      <acceptance>Chrome headless screenshots were captured for /, /login, /register, /forgot-password, /reset-password, and /verify-email at phone/tablet/desktop sizes plus reduced-motion 390x844; representative frames were visually reviewed.</acceptance>
    </step-6>
    <step-7 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073">
      <action>Create Phase-56 smoke markers for public routes, auth states, tariff canonicality, and email-proof guard.</action>
      <acceptance>scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs emits required Phase-56 markers and validates route split, CTA, auth states, canonical tariff preview, logo visibility, reduced-motion markers, redaction, and protected deploy/install guard.</acceptance>
    </step-7>
    <step-8 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073,M-009,M-071,M-072">
      <action>Run frontend build, screenshots, smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected surface guard.</action>
      <acceptance>Frontend build, Phase-56 smoke, Phase-44/46/50/52/53/55 regression smokes, screenshot dimension checks, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected deploy/install guard passed locally.</acceptance>
    </step-8>
    <step-9 STATUS="done-local" MODULES="M-073">
      <action>Record evidence in M-073/V-M-073.</action>
      <acceptance>M-073, V-M-073, M-009, M-071, graph-index, plan-index, verification-index, and current-status record Phase-56 pass-local evidence.</acceptance>
    </step-9>
  </steps>
  <verification>V-M-073</verification>
  <execution-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-03">
    <command-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs</command-3>
    <command-4>node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</command-4>
    <command-5>node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</command-5>
    <command-6>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-6>
    <command-7>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-7>
    <command-8>node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</command-8>
    <command-9>Chrome headless production-preview screenshots for /, /login, /register, /forgot-password, /reset-password, /verify-email at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1440x900 plus reduced-motion 390x844.</command-9>
    <command-10>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose guard.</command-10>
    <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase56-screenshots</screenshot-paths>
    <result>PASS: public landing route, /dashboard protected cabinet route split, visible logo auth routes, canonical tariff preview, email-proof guard copy, screenshot matrix, regression smokes, and protected surface guard passed locally.</result>
    <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose.yml, deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml, .env.example, backend registration, billing runtime, VPN, MTProto, or runtime topology changes.</protected-surface>
  </execution-evidence>
  <acceptance>Public and auth surfaces feel premium and remain safe, compact, and truthful.</acceptance>
</Phase-56>
