<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-22 NAME="Emergency Server Relocation and Data Restore" STATUS="pending" MODULES="M-034,M-035,M-001,M-003,M-012,M-028,M-032" CREATED="2026-05-10">
  <goal>
    Define and verify an operator-safe disaster recovery path for moving KrotPN to replacement RU/DE servers with
    PostgreSQL data, secrets, VPN state, and client/device linkage preserved.
  </goal>

  <scope>
    <included>Runbook, backup manifest contract, restore checklist, validation gates, rollback checkpoints, and data integrity evidence.</included>
    <excluded>Changing deploy scripts, changing install.sh, replacing the operator-approved deployment method, and redesigning infrastructure automation.</excluded>
  </scope>

  <data-flows>
    <DF-DR-BACKUP>Old RU/DE servers and database enter a maintenance/freeze window, then produce a protected backup bundle with manifest and checksums.</DF-DR-BACKUP>
    <DF-DR-RESTORE>Fresh RU/DE servers are deployed with the existing approved scripts, then PostgreSQL, runtime secrets, and VPN state are restored.</DF-DR-RESTORE>
    <DF-DR-CUTOVER>Validated replacement servers pass health, auth, billing, and VPN handshake checks before DNS/IP/operator cutover.</DF-DR-CUTOVER>
  </data-flows>

  <step-1 MODULE="M-034" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Define incident modes and operator decision points: total server loss, planned provider migration, partial RU failure, partial DE failure, and rollback eligibility.
  </step-1>

  <step-2 MODULE="M-034,M-035" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Define the maintenance/freeze sequence: pause risky admin actions, capture current app version, record RU/DE addresses, and capture table counts before backup.
  </step-2>

  <step-3 MODULE="M-035" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Define the backup bundle contract: PostgreSQL dump, protected .env/runtime secrets, AWG profiles, server keys, subnet settings, peer state, device-client linkage, and manifest.
  </step-3>

  <step-4 MODULE="M-035,M-028" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Define restore integrity checks: schema version, migration state, checksums, table counts, selected row invariants, and no-secret-log evidence.
  </step-4>

  <step-5 MODULE="M-034,M-012" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="pending">
    Write the replacement-server runbook: provision fresh RU/DE hosts through the existing approved deploy/install scripts, then stop services at the restore checkpoint.
  </step-5>

  <step-6 MODULE="M-034,M-035,M-028" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="pending">
    Define restore sequence: load database dump, restore protected runtime env, restore VPN/AWG artifacts, verify migration state, then start services.
  </step-6>

  <step-7 MODULE="M-034,M-003,M-032" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="pending">
    Define VPN-specific validation: RU/DE tunnel health, AWG profile parity, address-pool compatibility, existing client config behavior, and explicit rotation guard.
  </step-7>

  <step-8 MODULE="M-034,M-001" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="pending">
    Define application validation: backend health, frontend/admin reachability, database connection, Redis, user/admin auth smoke, billing read path, and device listing.
  </step-8>

  <step-9 MODULE="M-034,M-035" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="pending">
    Define cutover and rollback procedure: DNS/IP/operator switch, go/no-go gate, old-server rollback, post-cutover monitoring, and incident handoff notes.
  </step-9>

  <step-10 MODULE="M-034,M-035" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="pending">
    Perform a non-production dry-run restore before relying on the procedure for a real incident; record blocked live checks separately.
  </step-10>

  <backup-bundle>
    <item-manifest>manifest.json with app version, schema version, created_at, artifact list, checksums, and table counts.</item-manifest>
    <item-postgres>postgres.dump containing users, subscriptions, payments, devices, VPN clients, audit events, plans, and migration state.</item-postgres>
    <item-runtime-env>Protected runtime env material needed to boot the replacement deployment; secret values must not be printed in logs.</item-runtime-env>
    <item-vpn-state>AWG profiles, server keys, peer state, subnet settings, and device-client linkage needed to preserve existing configs.</item-vpn-state>
    <item-evidence>table_counts.before.json, table_counts.after.json, checksums.sha256, migration_state.txt, and restore_notes.md.</item-evidence>
  </backup-bundle>

  <cutover-gates>
    <gate-1>All restore checks pass and counts match expected tolerances.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Backend, frontend, admin, database, Redis, billing read path, and auth smoke checks pass.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>RU/DE tunnel health and at least one existing user/device config path are validated.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Rollback target is still available or an explicit no-rollback decision is recorded.</gate-4>
  </cutover-gates>

  <rollback-gates>
    <gate-1>Abort cutover if checksums or table counts do not match.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Abort cutover if existing client configs would be invalidated without explicit operator-approved rotation.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Rollback to old servers if post-cutover health, auth, or VPN handshake checks fail.</gate-3>
  </rollback-gates>

  <verification>
    <check-1>Backup manifest includes all required artifacts and explicitly redacts secrets from logs.</check-1>
    <check-2>Restore dry-run compares users, subscriptions, payments, devices, and VPN clients before cutover.</check-2>
    <check-3>Existing deploy/install scripts are invoked as-is and are not edited by this phase.</check-3>
    <check-4>Recovery checklist includes abort and rollback steps.</check-4>
  </verification>

  <execution-artifacts>
    <artifact-1 module="M-034">docs/recovery/DR-PHASE-22.xml records incident modes, operator decision points, rollback eligibility, and local/live evidence boundaries.</artifact-1>
    <artifact-2 module="M-034,M-035">docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml records maintenance/freeze sequence, pre-backup evidence, table-count capture, and secret-redaction policy.</artifact-2>
    <artifact-3 module="M-035">docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml defines the portable bundle layout, manifest fields, required artifacts, and checksum rules.</artifact-3>
    <artifact-4 module="M-035,M-028">docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml defines restore integrity gates for schema/migration state, checksums, table counts, row invariants, and no-secret-log review.</artifact-4>
  </execution-artifacts>
</Phase-22>
