<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-30 NAME="KPprotoN Runtime Bridge" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.2.0" UPDATED="2026-05-14">
  <Goal>Connect KrotPN MTProto assignments to a runtime policy bridge that can activate issued SNI domains safely.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-044,M-042,M-043,M-008,M-012</Modules>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No shared 443 edge cutover yet.</item-1>
    <item-2>No user dashboard UI work yet.</item-2>
    <item-3>No deploy/install script redesign.</item-3>
  </NonGoals>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Define the bridge interface for apply-domain-policy, runtime health, startup replay, and reconciliation.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Choose integration shape for KPprotoN/mtproto_proxy runtime with pinned dependency or isolated service boundary.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Implement startup replay from M-042 assignments into runtime policy state with idempotent retries.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Implement degraded-mode semantics when the runtime bridge is unavailable during verified onboarding.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Wire a scheduler reconciliation task without impacting existing anti-abuse scheduler jobs.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="done-local">Add tests for policy apply success, bridge unavailable, replay after restart, and no-secret logging.</step-6>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_scheduler.py -v</command>
    <command>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-30.xml docs/verification/V-M-044.xml docs/verification-index.xml; mygrace lint</command>
  </Verification>
  <VerificationMatrix>
    <matrix-1 module="M-044" level="module-local">Fake-adapter tests for apply-domain-policy, runtime health, startup replay, reconciliation, degraded mode, and secret redaction.</matrix-1>
    <matrix-2 module="M-042,M-043" level="wave-level">Assignment registry and owner-safe provisioning tests remain green so bridge policy state follows Postgres assignment truth.</matrix-2>
    <matrix-3 module="M-008" level="wave-level">Scheduler tests prove MTProto policy sync is registered once and does not regress existing recurring jobs.</matrix-3>
    <matrix-4 module="M-012" level="phase-level">No deploy/install script changes are allowed in Phase-30; shared 443 edge and TLS/domain work are deferred to Phase-32.</matrix-4>
  </VerificationMatrix>
  <Telemetry>
    <marker-1>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][LOAD_POLICY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][POLICY_APPLIED]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][BRIDGE_UNAVAILABLE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-044][replay_active_assignments][REPLAY_POLICY]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-044][sync_mtproto_policy][SCHEDULER_SYNC]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-044][runtime_health][BRIDGE_DEGRADED]</marker-6>
  </Telemetry>
  <PreflightGates>
    <gate-1>Execution uses fake/local KPprotoN adapters only; no live Telegram, DNS, TLS, host networking, or shared 443 edge mutation.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Deploy/install scripts and nginx/docker-compose edge surfaces remain unchanged unless the operator explicitly opens Phase-32 work.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Bridge outage must produce explicit degraded MTProto state and must not block normal KrotPN login, verified onboarding, billing, or VPN config access.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Runtime logs, health payloads, and admin summaries must redact tg://proxy links, derived secrets, base secret, salt, tokens, and adapter credentials.</gate-4>
  </PreflightGates>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>Active assignments replay into policy state after backend or bridge restart.</item-1>
    <item-2>Bridge failure does not break normal KrotPN login or VPN config access.</item-2>
    <item-3>Verified users see an explicit pending/degraded proxy state if runtime activation is delayed.</item-3>
    <item-4>Runtime logs include stable markers but no full proxy link, token, or secret.</item-4>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Completion>
    <item-1>M-044 now exposes a secret-free runtime bridge boundary with apply-domain-policy, runtime health, startup replay, and scheduler reconciliation entry points.</item-1>
    <item-2>The Phase-30 integration shape is an isolated backend service boundary using fake/local adapters only; live edge, DNS, TLS, and shared 443 work remain deferred.</item-2>
    <item-3>Phase-30 backend verification passed locally: 21 targeted tests across runtime bridge, assignment registry, provisioning, and scheduler coverage.</item-3>
    <item-4>No deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose files were changed.</item-4>
  </Completion>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>KPprotoN Erlang dependency drift can make runtime behavior non-reproducible unless pinned.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Policy state can drift from Postgres unless reconciliation is designed early.</risk-2>
  </Risks>
</Phase-30>
