<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-47 NAME="MTProto CTA Subdomain Link Generation" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.0.0" MODULES="M-065,M-001,M-002,M-042,M-043,M-045,M-049,M-050,M-064" CREATED="2026-06-01" UPDATED="2026-06-01">
  <purpose>Implement marketing-oriented CTA subdomains for newly issued personal MTProto proxy links while preserving existing working proxies and the Phase-41 RU/DE fake-TLS data-plane.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>CTA prefix allow-list, 7-hex public user suffix derivation, explicit prefix validation, stable pseudo-random prefix choice, CTA SNI generation, owner payload consistency, backend tests, frontend/smoke guards, and MyGRACE metadata.</in>
    <out>Deploy/install scripts, nginx/docker-compose, wildcard TLS issuance, database schema migrations, MTProto runtime topology, promotion tag runtime, and automatic mass reissue of existing u-* assignments.</out>
  </scope>
  <example-output>https://t.me/proxy?server=kupi-vpn-4bb40fa.krotpn.xyz&amp;port=443&amp;secret=ee...</example-output>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-065,M-043" STATUS="done-local">Add the fixed CTA prefix allow-list: kupi-vpn, vpn-tut, beri-vpn, bez-blokirovok, hochu-bystree, and krot-vpn.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-065,M-002" STATUS="done-local">Implement public short-id derivation: use first 7 hex characters for hex-like user keys and a stable 7-hex hash suffix for numeric internal IDs.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-065,M-043" STATUS="done-local">Implement explicit prefix validation and stable pseudo-random prefix selection without accepting arbitrary DNS labels.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-065,M-043" STATUS="done-local">Generate wildcard-safe CTA SNI as cta-prefix-shortid.base-domain with collision nonce support and DNS label validation.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-065,M-042,M-043" STATUS="done-local">Integrate CTA SNI into new assignment creation while preserving existing active u-* assignments unless reissue is explicit.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-065,M-043,M-049,M-050" STATUS="done-local">Verify fake-TLS secret derivation, live policy apply expectations, and RU SNI router compatibility for the final CTA SNI.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-065,M-045,M-064" STATUS="done-local">Ensure user-cabinet tg:// and https://t.me links both use the CTA server value returned by the owner API.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-065" STATUS="done-local">Add targeted backend tests and Phase-47 static smoke for prefix allow-list, short-id derivation, link consistency, redaction, and protected deploy surfaces.</step-8>
    <step-9 MODULE="M-065" STATUS="done-local">Run backend provisioning tests, frontend build, Phase-47 smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and deploy/install diff guard.</step-9>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>Verified user -&gt; MTProtoProvisioningService -&gt; CTA prefix selector -&gt; public 7-hex suffix -&gt; cta-prefix-shortid.krotpn.xyz.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>CTA SNI -&gt; derive_fake_tls_secret -&gt; owner payload server/secret -&gt; tg://proxy and https://t.me/proxy links.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>CTA SNI assignment -&gt; runtime policy apply -&gt; RU SNI router -&gt; DE KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime.</flow-3>
  </data-flow>
  <mental-walkthroughs>
    <walkthrough-1>A newly verified user receives kupi-vpn-4bb40fa.krotpn.xyz; Telegram sees the same server in the fake-TLS secret and can connect through the existing RU/DE edge.</walkthrough-1>
    <walkthrough-2>An existing user with u-0195616cec89.krotpn.xyz logs in after Phase-47 and keeps the old working assignment because no automatic mass reissue occurs.</walkthrough-2>
    <walkthrough-3>An invalid explicit prefix such as custom-domain is rejected before SNI creation, so arbitrary hostnames cannot enter policy apply or logs.</walkthrough-3>
  </mental-walkthroughs>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1>CTA hostnames match one of the approved prefixes plus a 7-hex suffix under the configured base domain.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Raw numeric user IDs are not visible in generated public hostnames.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Existing active assignments remain stable and are not silently rotated.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Derived ee fake-TLS secret contains the final CTA SNI hex and does not use stale u-* server text for new assignments.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>No deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose files are changed.</gate-5>
  </phase-gates>
  <risks>
    <risk-1 severity="medium">CTA hostnames are more marketing-visible than neutral u-* hostnames, which may improve recall but can make blocked-word tuning more sensitive.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="high">Changing SNI generation breaks old proxy links if existing assignments are silently rewritten; Phase-47 forbids automatic mass rotation.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="high">Secret derivation must use the final CTA SNI because Telegram fake-TLS secret embeds the hostname in hex.</risk-3>
    <risk-4 severity="medium">Random prefix choice must be deterministic after issuance; true randomness belongs only to create/reissue time and must be persisted as SNI.</risk-4>
  </risks>
  <verification>
    <matrix>
      <module-local>Backend tests validate CTA prefix allow-list, short-id derivation for hex-like and numeric IDs, DNS label safety, explicit prefix rejection, collision nonce behavior, fake-TLS secret derivation from final SNI, and legacy u-* assignment preservation.</module-local>
      <wave-level>Frontend build and Phase-47 smoke validate owner payload consistency: server, secret, tg:// link, and https://t.me link all use the final CTA SNI without leaking real full links.</wave-level>
      <phase-level>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose diff guard validate metadata consistency and operational isolation.</phase-level>
      <runtime-safety>Runtime topology is not changed; policy apply expectations are verified by existing M-049/M-050 contracts and static checks that CTA SNI remains one wildcard-safe label under the configured base domain.</runtime-safety>
    </matrix>
    <commands>
      <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py -v</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase47-mtproto-cta-links-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-47.xml docs/modules/M-065.xml docs/verification/V-M-065.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
      <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
    </commands>
    <evidence>2026-06-01: backend provisioning tests passed 14/14 outside sandbox after sandbox aiosqlite hang, frontend build passed, Phase-47 smoke passed, protected deploy/install diff guard had no output, XML parse passed, and MyGRACE lint passed.</evidence>
  </verification>
</Phase-47>
