<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-68 NAME="User Dashboard Subscription Merge and Cabinet Compaction" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.1.0" MODULES="M-075,M-036,M-045,M-063,M-068,M-071,M-074,M-077,M-080,M-009" CREATED="2026-06-04" UPDATED="2026-06-04">
  <purpose>Make the authenticated user dashboard the compact primary working surface by removing low-value folds, moving subscription/tariff/calendar controls onto /dashboard, and preserving VPN, MTProto, config, and billing actions on mobile.</purpose>
  <scope>
    <in>User dashboard layout, MTProto card copy, user shell logo styling, subscription card/tariff/calendar presentation, user-cabinet button microinteractions, /dashboard/subscription route compatibility, frontend smoke contracts, and MyGRACE synchronization.</in>
    <out>Deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, VPN runtime, MTProto runtime, payment provider credentials, YooKassa webhook semantics, admin panel redesign, and backend price/device-limit ownership beyond approved tariff display names/descriptions.</out>
  </scope>
  <requirements>
    <requirement-1>The user shell logo must be frameless like the public/auth screens while staying visible in desktop sidebar and mobile top bar.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>The dashboard must remove phase57-command-center and phase62-secondary-fold surfaces from the main page without hiding primary actions.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>The MTProto card must remove "Индивидуальный Telegram proxy готов к использованию." and "Личный proxy"; it must show "Ваш бесплатный постоянный Telegram MTProto прокси" with Telegram MTProto visually emphasized.</requirement-3>
    <requirement-4>The subscription page content must be moved under the MTProto card on /dashboard; /dashboard/subscription must remain non-breaking through redirect, anchor, or equivalent compatibility handling.</requirement-4>
    <requirement-5>Pending trial copy must say "Конфиг уже доступен. Таймер на 4 дня стартует после первого подключения." and must not show the extra warning badge "Trial начнется после первого VPN подключения".</requirement-5>
    <requirement-6>Remove phase57-card-compact phase62-inline-details subscription included/features blocks and remove "Детали тарифа" detail folds from every tariff card.</requirement-6>
    <requirement-7>Move "Тарифные планы" above the calendar and remove helper copy about three tariffs, 30 days, and backend plan_id.</requirement-7>
    <requirement-8>Rename user-visible tariffs to KrotPN Self, KrotPN Family, and KrotPN Team while preserving slugs, prices, duration, device limits, sort order, and backend-authoritative checkout shape.</requirement-8>
    <requirement-9>Replace tariff icons and descriptions: Self uses "Персональный тариф"; Family uses "Тариф для семьи"; Team uses "Тариф для команды".</requirement-9>
    <requirement-10>The calendar must be renamed "Календарь подписки", remove "Активные даты", become miniature/compact, and show cross-month subscription ranges intuitively.</requirement-10>
    <requirement-11>All user-cabinet buttons should receive consistent Phase-59-style animated hover/active/copy feedback while respecting reduced-motion and avoiding layout shifts.</requirement-11>
    <requirement-12>The config page must remove config-diagnostics and data-phase57-raw-config surfaces while preserving QR, .conf download, copy, device create/rotate/revoke, and protected config access.</requirement-12>
  </requirements>
  <steps>
    <step-1 MODULE="M-075,M-036,M-009" STATUS="done-local">Audit Dashboard, Subscription, Config, Layout, CSS, and current Phase-57/62 smoke markers before editing to map removed, moved, and preserved surfaces.</step-1>
    <step-2 MODULE="M-080,M-075,M-071" STATUS="done-local">Apply frameless user-shell logo styling for desktop and mobile without changing brand assets or public/auth logo behavior.</step-2>
    <step-3 MODULE="M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Remove dashboard phase57-command-center and phase62-secondary-fold blocks, then preserve any still-needed primary actions through compact direct controls.</step-3>
    <step-4 MODULE="M-045,M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Rewrite MTProto card heading/copy, emphasize Telegram MTProto, keep tg:// app link, https://t.me browser link, manual server/port/secret copy, owner-only redaction, and 30s refresh.</step-4>
    <step-5 MODULE="M-063,M-068,M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Extract subscription status, tariff catalog, checkout action, and calendar rendering into reusable dashboard-owned blocks and place them under the MTProto card.</step-5>
    <step-6 MODULE="M-009,M-075" STATUS="done-local">Keep /dashboard/subscription as a compatibility route that redirects to /dashboard subscription block or renders the same compact block without duplicating UI ownership.</step-6>
    <step-7 MODULE="M-063,M-075" STATUS="done-local">Update pending-first-connection copy, remove the extra warning badge, remove included-copy details, and keep server-derived countdown fields.</step-7>
    <step-8 MODULE="M-068,M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Rename tariff display names/descriptions/icons and remove all tariff detail folds while preserving canonical slugs, prices, durations, limits, popularity, and plan_id-only checkout.</step-8>
    <step-9 MODULE="M-063,M-071,M-074" STATUS="done-local">Build the compact subscription calendar with cross-month range clarity, miniature sizing, no horizontal scroll, and accessible state text.</step-9>
    <step-10 MODULE="M-077,M-071,M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Normalize animated button treatments across dashboard/config/referrals/settings user cabinet controls with reduced-motion fallbacks.</step-10>
    <step-11 MODULE="M-066,M-075,M-036" STATUS="done-local">Remove config diagnostics and raw config fallback panels while preserving QR/download/copy/device management and Phase-48 .conf download safeguards.</step-11>
    <step-12 MODULE="M-075,M-036,M-045,M-063,M-068,M-074" STATUS="done-local">Update Phase-45/50/57/62/61 smoke contracts and run frontend build, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard during execution.</step-12>
  </steps>
  <data-flow>
    <flow-1>/dashboard loads subscription, plans, devices, VPN stats, and MTProto owner state through existing APIs, then renders MTProto first and subscription/tariffs/calendar directly below it.</flow-1>
    <flow-2>User chooses a tariff on /dashboard -> frontend posts plan_id only -> backend M-068/M-004 remains authoritative for price, duration, currency, and device limit.</flow-2>
    <flow-3>Legacy /dashboard/subscription navigation -> compatibility route -> same subscription block or anchored /dashboard section, avoiding duplicated state and stale copy.</flow-3>
    <flow-4>/dashboard/config keeps QR, download, copy, and device controls while removing diagnostic/raw-config surfaces from the visible cabinet.</flow-4>
  </data-flow>
  <mental-walkthroughs>
    <walkthrough-1>New verified user opens /dashboard on a phone: sees MTProto proxy, then subscription/tariffs/calendar without the old command center or secondary diagnostics.</walkthrough-1>
    <walkthrough-2>User with pending trial sees config-ready text and understands that the 4-day timer starts after first connection, without duplicate warning badges.</walkthrough-2>
    <walkthrough-3>User follows an old /dashboard/subscription link and still reaches the subscription controls without a broken route or duplicated bulky page.</walkthrough-3>
  </mental-walkthroughs>
  <verification-design>
    <gate-1>Frontend build and Phase-57/62 smokes must confirm removed dashboard/config/subscription surfaces do not reappear.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Phase-45 smoke must confirm pending-first-VPN copy, countdown fields, and compact subscription calendar remain correct.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Phase-50 smoke must confirm tariff slugs/prices/device limits stay unchanged while user-visible names/descriptions/icons change as approved.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-46/53/57 smokes must confirm MTProto owner links, Russian labels, redaction, and bounded refresh are preserved.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Phase-61 responsive smoke or screenshot proof must confirm no horizontal scroll, no text/icon overlap, and touch-safe buttons on phones/tablets.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Protected diff guard must fail the phase if deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/backend runtime or MTProto/VPN data-plane surfaces change unexpectedly.</gate-6>
  </verification-design>
  <verification>
    <commands>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase63-visible-logo-integration-smoke.mjs</command>
      <command status="pass-local">git diff --check; protected backend/deploy/runtime diff guard</command>
    </commands>
  </verification>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-04>Implemented shared frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx, embedded it below MTProto on /dashboard, kept /dashboard/subscription as a compatibility wrapper, removed visible dashboard command center/secondary fold and config raw/diagnostic surfaces, made the user shell logo frameless, and updated smoke contracts for the new ownership boundary.</local-2026-06-04>
    <verification-2026-06-04>PASS: user/admin builds, Phase-68 smoke, Phase-45/46/50/53/57/58/60/61/62/63/67 regression smokes, git diff --check, MyGRACE lint via Phase-60, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guards passed locally.</verification-2026-06-04>
  </execution-evidence>
  <risk-assessment>
    <risk-1 severity="high">Moving /dashboard/subscription onto /dashboard can break old navigation or tests unless the route remains compatible.</risk-1>
    <risk-2 severity="critical">Tariff display-name changes must not mutate stable slugs, prices, device limits, or backend-authoritative checkout metadata unexpectedly.</risk-2>
    <risk-3 severity="high">Removing raw config/diagnostics must not remove QR, .conf download, copy, device management, or first pending-trial config access.</risk-3>
    <risk-4 severity="medium">Button animations can create mobile layout shifts or reduced-motion issues unless bounded by existing M-077 constraints.</risk-4>
  </risk-assessment>
  <acceptance>/dashboard becomes the compact main cabinet with frameless logo, cleaned MTProto card, embedded subscription/tariffs/calendar, removed bulky secondary surfaces, preserved config actions, and passing frontend/MyGRACE verification.</acceptance>
</Phase-68>
