<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-63 NAME="Visible Logo Integration" STATUS="done-local">
  <objective>Integrate prepared KrotPN logos into visible premium surfaces where they improve brand identity.</objective>
  <modules>M-080,M-009,M-010,M-069,M-072,M-073,M-075,M-076</modules>
  <asset-source>/home/truffle/Загрузки/ДЛЯ КРОТА/logos</asset-source>
  <non-goals>Changing BIMI DNS semantics, claiming mailbox sender-avatar control, deploy/install changes.</non-goals>
  <steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Audit available logo PNG sizes from 16x16 through 1024x1024.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Select optimized source sizes for public hero/auth, user layout, admin layout, PWA, favicon, and email body use.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Define visible logo placement rules for mobile, tablet, and desktop.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Integrate logo into premium public/auth surfaces.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Integrate compact logo into user and admin shells where it does not crowd navigation.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="done-local">Coordinate email-logo use with Phase-64 and existing M-069/M-067 boundaries.</step-6>
    <step-7 STATUS="done-local">Run user/admin builds, logo smoke, screenshots, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected surface guard.</step-7>
    <step-8 STATUS="done-local">Record evidence in M-080/V-M-080.</step-8>
  </steps>
  <verification>V-M-080</verification>
  <acceptance>KrotPN logo appears consistently and compactly without asset bloat or BIMI/email-avatar confusion.</acceptance>
  <evidence>2026-06-04: Phase-63 selected the prepared 96x96 PNG as bounded visible mark, copied it to user/admin public brand assets, added reusable user/admin BrandMark components, integrated compact visible logos into public/auth, protected user shell, admin login, admin rail, and admin topbar, preserved existing email body logo and BIMI/provider boundaries, passed user/admin builds, Phase-63 smoke, Phase-55/56/57/58/60/61/62 regressions, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard. Implementation commit c385d62.</evidence>
</Phase-63>
