<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-21 NAME="MyGRACE Verification and Documentation Cleanup" STATUS="done" MODULES="M-033,M-006,M-007,M-017" CREATED="2026-05-10">
  <goal>
    Bring active MyGRACE documents and verification surfaces back in sync with the current Full Tunnel architecture
    without changing runtime behavior.
  </goal>

  <scope>
    <included>Indexes, per-module docs, per-verification docs, README handoff, obsolete test references, and active phase references.</included>
    <excluded>Runtime feature changes, deployment script changes, install script changes, and VPN topology changes.</excluded>
  </scope>

  <obsolete-routing-audit updated="2026-05-10">
    <active-cleanup>
      <item-1>backend/tests/test_route_decision_api.py still verifies deleted route-policy endpoints and imports removed routing models.</item-1>
      <item-2>backend/tests/test_admin_stats.py still expects policy_dns_observer on the admin router.</item-2>
      <item-3>backend/tests/test_dns_observer.py, test_domain_rule_store.py, test_route_policy_resolver.py, test_routing_policy_compat.py, and test_ru_ipset_updater.py target removed split-tunnel support modules.</item-3>
      <item-4>V-M-006 still points at deleted route-policy behavior and must be replaced with current admin/system/device verification.</item-4>
      <item-5>README and AGENTS project summary still use split-tunneling wording that can mislead handoff agents.</item-5>
    </active-cleanup>
    <historical-or-superseded>
      <item-1>Phase-1, Phase-2, Phase-3, Phase-4, Phase-15, Phase-16, and Phase-17 may retain historical references only when explicitly archived or superseded.</item-1>
      <item-2>V-M-007 and V-M-017 references to ipset/split-tunnel are valid only as regression assertions that removed artifacts do not return.</item-2>
      <item-3>Graph hotspots H-003 and H-004 are valid regression warnings for Full Tunnel cleanup.</item-3>
    </historical-or-superseded>
  </obsolete-routing-audit>

  <step-1 MODULE="M-033" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Audit active docs for stale M-013 through M-016 references and classify each as active, archived, or superseded.
  </step-1>

  <step-2 MODULE="M-033,M-017" RISK="CRITICAL" STATUS="done">
    Replace active split-tunnel/ipset/policy verification expectations with current Full Tunnel expectations.
  </step-2>

  <step-3 MODULE="M-006,M-033" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="done">
    Update admin verification so V-M-006 checks current admin/system/device behavior instead of deleted route-policy surfaces.
  </step-3>

  <step-4 MODULE="M-033" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="done">
    Make backend test collection clean by archiving or rewriting obsolete tests for removed routing modules.
  </step-4>

  <step-5 MODULE="M-033" RISK="MEDIUM" STATUS="done">
    Synchronize graph CrossLinks, plan-index, verification-index, README handoff, and per-entity files.
  </step-5>

  <step-6 MODULE="M-033" RISK="HIGH" STATUS="done">
    Run MyGRACE integrity verification and record which checks are local-only versus requiring live VPS evidence.
  </step-6>

  <verification>
    <check-1>All active XML files parse successfully.</check-1>
    <check-2>Every graph-index entry has a matching docs/modules file and verification ref.</check-2>
    <check-3>Backend pytest collection succeeds before feature work resumes.</check-3>
    <check-4>No runtime files are changed unless a later approved execution phase requires it.</check-4>
  </verification>

  <execution-evidence updated="2026-05-10">
    <local-check-1>Parsed 103 active XML files outside docs/archive with 0 failures.</local-check-1>
    <local-check-2>Dependency CrossLink audit reported 0 missing DEPENDS CrossLinks.</local-check-2>
    <local-check-3>Index count/file audit reported 0 errors for graph modules, plan phases, and verification entries.</local-check-3>
    <local-check-4>mygrace lint reported 0 errors and 0 warnings.</local-check-4>
    <local-check-5>Backend pytest collection reported 106 tests collected with 0 collection errors.</local-check-5>
    <live-vps-check-1>Live VPS evidence is not required for Phase-21 because changes are documentation, index, and test-archive cleanup only.</live-vps-check-1>
    <live-vps-check-2>Live VPS or restore-target evidence remains required for future disaster-recovery and deployment-readiness phases.</live-vps-check-2>
  </execution-evidence>
</Phase-21>
