<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-27 NAME="Email Verification Foundation" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.1.0" UPDATED="2026-05-13">
  <Goal>Create the foundation for verified email registration so no KrotPN access is issued before email ownership is proven.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-040,M-041,M-001,M-002,M-027</Modules>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No MTProto provisioning in this phase.</item-1>
    <item-2>No deploy/install script changes.</item-2>
    <item-3>No cookie-only session migration.</item-3>
  </NonGoals>
  <Steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Extend M-001 settings contract with email provider, verification TTL, allowed/blocked domains, and disposable-domain guard knobs.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Create M-040 email delivery adapter and verification templates using KPprotoN template lessons but KrotPN branding.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Create M-041 pending registration model/service with token hashing, TTL, replay protection, and normalized email storage.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Add email-risk checks: syntax, domain normalization, MX/DNS availability, configured disposable-domain denylist, and safe failure reasons.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Add focused backend tests and log markers without changing existing active /register behavior yet.</step-5>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_email_delivery.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py -v</command>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_security.py -v -k blacklist</command>
    <command>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/verification-index.xml docs/modules/M-040.xml docs/modules/M-041.xml docs/verification/V-M-040.xml docs/verification/V-M-041.xml</command>
    <command>mygrace lint</command>
  </Verification>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>Email provider failures are typed and do not create user access.</item-1>
    <item-2>Verification token values are stored hashed or otherwise non-recoverable from logs.</item-2>
    <item-3>Temporary or configured blocked domains are rejected before sending verification email.</item-3>
    <item-4>The existing live registration behavior remains untouched until Phase-28 cutover.</item-4>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Over-aggressive temp-mail checks can block real users; allowlist override must exist.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>SMTP existence probing is intentionally avoided because it is unreliable and privacy-hostile.</risk-2>
  </Risks>
  <Outcome>
    <item-1>M-040 email delivery foundation implemented with provider-neutral request shape, Resend/SMTP adapters, disabled-provider guard, localized templates, and fake-provider tests.</item-1>
    <item-2>M-041 pending registration foundation implemented with HMAC token hashing, TTL/replay safety, disposable-domain guard, allowlist override, optional DNS guard, and no active user/VPN/trial side effects.</item-2>
    <item-3>Active /api/v1/auth/register remains unchanged until Phase-28 cutover.</item-3>
  </Outcome>
</Phase-27>
