<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-28 NAME="Verified Registration Cutover" STATUS="done-local" VERSION="1.2.0">
  <Goal>Switch KrotPN registration to verified-email activation while preserving trial, VPN provisioning, referrals, and frontend onboarding.</Goal>
  <Modules>M-041,M-002,M-004,M-005,M-022,M-009</Modules>
  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>No MTProto runtime integration yet; this phase prepares the verified onboarding boundary.</item-1>
    <item-2>No Telegram auth behavior changes unless required to avoid regression.</item-2>
    <item-3>No deploy/install script changes.</item-3>
  </NonGoals>
  <Steps>
    <step-1>Change /api/v1/auth/register contract to create a pending registration and send verification email instead of issuing tokens immediately.</step-1>
    <step-2>Add /api/v1/auth/verify-email or equivalent endpoint that consumes the one-time token and creates the canonical user row.</step-2>
    <step-3>Move existing post-registration side effects behind successful verification: trial subscription, primary VPN device, VPN client provisioning, and referral linkage.</step-3>
    <step-4>Update frontend Register flow to show check-email, expired-link, resend, and verified-success states.</step-4>
    <step-5>Preserve session-security assumptions from M-039 and ensure login/refresh/logout compatibility remains green.</step-5>
    <step-6>Add regression tests proving unverified users do not get trial, VPN config, referral bonus, or JWT tokens.</step-6>
  </Steps>
  <Verification>
    <command>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py tests/test_manual_access_policy.py tests/test_device_api.py tests/test_referrals.py tests/test_telegram_auth.py tests/test_security.py -v</command>
    <command>node scripts/session-security-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command>node scripts/phase28-register-flow-smoke.mjs; cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-28.xml docs/verification/V-M-041.xml docs/verification/V-M-002.xml docs/verification/V-M-004.xml docs/verification/V-M-005.xml docs/verification/V-M-022.xml docs/verification/V-M-009.xml docs/verification-index.xml; mygrace lint</command>
  </Verification>
  <AcceptanceCriteria>
    <item-1>Unverified registration returns a pending/check-email response and does not create active access.</item-1>
    <item-2>Verified activation creates exactly one user, one trial if no history exists, and one primary VPN device path.</item-2>
    <item-3>Token replay, expired token, duplicate email, and blocked domain paths are deterministic.</item-3>
    <item-4>Frontend registration remains mobile-safe and avoids confusing users about trial availability.</item-4>
  </AcceptanceCriteria>
  <Completion>
    <item-1>/api/v1/auth/register now returns pending/check-email response without JWT or onboarding side effects.</item-1>
    <item-2>/api/v1/auth/verify-email consumes one-time token, creates verified user, then activates trial, primary device path, VPN provisioning call, and referral linkage once.</item-2>
    <item-3>User frontend now has Register pending/resend state and VerifyEmail success/expired/error route.</item-3>
    <item-4>Session smoke was updated so token storage starts at VerifyEmail success, not Register submit.</item-4>
  </Completion>
  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Changing /register response shape can break frontend and external clients if not staged carefully.</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Partially completed activation can duplicate trial/referral side effects unless idempotency is explicit.</risk-2>
  </Risks>
</Phase-28>
