<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-60 NAME="Premium Frontend QA Gates" STATUS="done-local">
  <objective>Create verification gates that prevent premium frontend work from shipping with layout, performance, accessibility, or MyGRACE regressions.</objective>
  <modules>M-078,M-009,M-010,M-036,M-037,M-038,M-070,M-071,M-073,M-075,M-076,M-077</modules>
  <non-goals>Feature implementation, deployment script changes, live server changes.</non-goals>
  <steps>
    <step-1 status="done-local">Define screenshot matrix for public, auth, user, admin, and reduced-motion routes.</step-1>
    <step-2 status="done-local">Define phone/tablet/desktop viewport set and no-overflow/no-overlap assertions.</step-2>
    <step-3 status="done-local">Define bundle, Lighthouse/Web Vitals, canvas CPU, and motion performance budgets.</step-3>
    <step-4 status="done-local">Define focus-visible, keyboard reachability, contrast, and reduced-motion assertions.</step-4>
    <step-5 status="done-local">Implement or specify Phase-60 smoke script contract.</step-5>
    <step-6 status="done-local">Verify protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime guard remains clean.</step-6>
    <step-7 status="done-local">Run XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, user/admin builds, and Phase-60 smoke.</step-7>
    <step-8 status="done-local">Record evidence in M-078/V-M-078.</step-8>
  </steps>
  <verification>V-M-078</verification>
  <acceptance>Premium frontend changes have explicit repeatable verification before release work continues.</acceptance>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs implemented with route/viewport matrix, no-overlap/responsive, reduced-motion/accessibility, build artifact budget, regression smoke, MyGRACE, and protected-surface gates.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend npm run build passed; primary JS 448516 bytes gzip 135543, primary CSS 40900 bytes gzip 8207.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend-admin npm run build passed; primary JS 780555 bytes gzip 219372, primary CSS 36787 bytes gzip 8148. Vite large-chunk warning remains inside the Phase-60 940KB admin budget.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-60 smoke passed and emitted screenshot static-route proof for public/auth, protected user, admin, and reduced-motion route matrices.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-52/55/56/57/58/59 regression smokes passed individually and through the Phase-60 gate.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime diff guard passed.</item>
  </evidence>
</Phase-60>
