<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Phase-62 NAME="Compactness and Deletion Audit" STATUS="done-local">
  <objective>Remove, collapse, or compact bulky frontend surfaces after premium responsive adaptation.</objective>
  <modules>M-075,M-076,M-038,M-073,M-074</modules>
  <non-goals>Removing required user/admin workflows, backend APIs, deploy/install scripts, or security controls.</non-goals>
  <steps>
    <step-1 STATUS="done-local">Inventory user, admin, public, and auth blocks that are duplicated, bulky, decorative, or low-value.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="done-local">Classify each candidate as remove, collapse, move secondary, compact, or keep.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="done-local">Apply user-cabinet compaction while preserving VPN, MTProto, subscription, devices, referrals, and settings.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="done-local">Apply admin-cockpit compaction while preserving operations, confirmations, analytics, and redaction.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="done-local">Apply public/auth compaction while preserving CTA, verification, reset, and tariff clarity.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="done-local">Create deletion-audit smoke markers for removed/collapsed surfaces and preserved workflows.</step-6>
    <step-7 STATUS="done-local">Run user/admin builds, Phase-62 smoke, screenshots, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected surface guard.</step-7>
    <step-8 STATUS="done-local">Record evidence in M-075/M-076/V-M-075/V-M-076.</step-8>
  </steps>
  <verification>V-M-075,V-M-076</verification>
  <acceptance>Frontend becomes less bulky while all primary workflows remain present and verifiable.</acceptance>
  <evidence>2026-06-04: Phase-62 compactness/deletion audit folded secondary dashboard diagnostics, config import guidance, config diagnostics, subscription included/features copy, public value/features copy, MTProto alert archive/storage, and server legacy compatibility behind compact details surfaces. Required primary workflows, public/auth clarity, admin confirmations, redaction, bounded inventories, responsive markers, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed. Implementation commit 3d09fa8.</evidence>
</Phase-62>
