<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Current project status for AI handoff -->
<current-status>
  <meta>
    <project-name>KrotPN</project-name>
    <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
    <status>active-development</status>
  </meta>

  <project-stage>
    <name>MVP implemented, now in hardening and operational cleanup</name>
    <summary>
      Продукт уже содержит работающие backend/frontend/admin/bot/deploy контуры,
      но пока находится не в фазе greenfield implementation, а в фазе stabilization:
      security, deploy, migration discipline, AI handoff and consistency.
    </summary>
  </project-stage>

  <what-is-working>
    <item>Backend domain structure and API surface exist.</item>
    <item>User frontend builds successfully in current local environment.</item>
    <item>Admin frontend code exists as separate app.</item>
    <item>VPN service supports route-aware logic with legacy compatibility.</item>
    <item>Admin route-policy controls and migration-safe routing analytics are implemented.</item>
    <item>Billing, referrals and Telegram bot are implemented at code level.</item>
    <item>Release v2.4.27 is published and includes device-bound access control, per-plan device limits, detect-first handshake anomaly detection, admin peer control, a live Postgres handshake-timestamp hotfix, API exposure of plan device_limit, and the earlier backend-driven manual provisioning plus live awg0 peer activation.</item>
    <item>RU and DE AWG interfaces are now managed through systemd and survive service restarts cleanly.</item>
    <item>DE host successfully rebooted into kernel 6.8.0-106-generic and AWG recovered automatically after boot.</item>
    <item>Fresh RU and DE servers were deployed and validated on March 26, 2026 with live AWG tunnel handshake and healthy backend/frontend/admin HTTPS surfaces on RU.</item>
    <item>Manual internal client issuance through deploy/create-client.sh now produces configs through backend CLI and applies peers to live awg0 state on RU.</item>
    <item>New RU host-level awg0 config watcher automatically syncs peer changes from backend-driven provisioning, so both manual and web-issued clients become active without manual awg commands.</item>
    <item>Release v2.11.0-awg-obfuscation-stable was deployed from GitHub main and operator-validated on RU/DE VPS with AWG stealth obfuscation, profile parity, RU-DE handshake, new client handshake, DE egress, and upgrade preservation.</item>
    <item>Phase-19 anti-ping-pong abuse detection is implemented locally: observe-mode roaming tolerance, Redis-backed endpoint history, soft auto-rotation path, admin anti-abuse context, and V-M-031 verification passed on 2026-04-20.</item>
    <item>Phase-20 configurable VPN subnets and 1000-device capacity is live-tested: release v2.13.0-vpn-network-capacity-stable deployed successfully on VPS, fresh deploy defaults use 172.29.0.0/22 for clients and 172.29.255.0/30 for RU/DE relay, capacity validation rejects /24 for 1000 devices, and address-pool migration requires VPN_NETWORK_ROTATE=1.</item>
    <item>Phase-23 compact mobile user cabinet passed local build and Chrome CDP mobile smoke for dashboard, config, and subscription routes.</item>
    <item>Phase-24 compact mobile admin console passed local build and Chrome/CDP mobile smoke for overview, users, devices, and analytics with confirmation-safe device actions.</item>
    <item>Phase-25 session-security gates passed locally: static auth guard, admin refresh-token lifecycle cleanup, and token blacklist unit tests.</item>
    <item>Phase-26 stabilization handoff records local evidence, protected deploy/install surfaces, and live-required recovery blockers.</item>
    <item>Release v2.14.0-stabilization-stable was operator-deployed from local PC to clean VPS servers and manually validated as working on 2026-05-12.</item>
    <item>Phase-27 email verification foundation passed local verification on 2026-05-13: provider-neutral email delivery, pending registration, HMAC token storage, domain guards, replay/expiry checks, and no /register cutover.</item>
    <item>Phase-28 verified registration cutover is locally closed as of 2026-05-19: /register is pending-only, /verify-email activates user access once, trial/VPN/referral side effects are delayed until email proof, frontend check-email/verify states build, and the former V-M-004/V-M-022 route/API debt was resolved by aligning stale tests to canonical /api/v1 prefixes.</item>
    <item>Phase-29 MTProto provisioning core passed local verification on 2026-05-14: restore-safe assignment registry, Alembic migration metadata, deterministic SNI, KPprotoN-compatible fake-TLS secret vector, tg://proxy assembly, verified-user guard, idempotent reuse, and explicit reissue policy.</item>
    <item>Phase-30 KPprotoN runtime bridge passed local verification on 2026-05-14: fake/local adapter boundary, startup replay, degraded bridge semantics, secret-free runtime health, MTProto scheduler reconciliation, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-31 MTProto user cabinet UX passed local verification on 2026-05-14: owner-only /api/v1/mtproto/proxy endpoint, compact dashboard proxy card, Telegram open/copy actions, safe unverified/pending/reissue states, frontend build, static mobile/API smoke, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-32 domain TLS edge passed local/static verification on 2026-05-14: krotpn.xyz settings, HTTP to HTTPS redirect contract, wildcard HTTPS fallback, compose config, protected deploy/install guard, rollback/live-smoke checklist, and M-044/M-043/M-040 regression tests.</item>
    <item>Phase-33 MTProto admin ops passed local verification on 2026-05-14: admin-only redacted assignment list/detail/health, confirmation-safe reissue/revoke with runtime SNI policy removal, safe audit events, compact frontend-admin /mtproto page, backend regression tests, frontend build, static smoke, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-34 MTProto integration stabilization passed local verification on 2026-05-14 and its production DNS/TLS/shared-443 Telegram smoke is now closed by Phase-41 live evidence.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 operator wildcard TLS installer passed local/static verification on 2026-05-17 and clean VPS production validation on 2026-05-19: install.sh asks for domain/fullchain1.pem/privkey1.pem paths, deploy validates operator wildcard TLS material before compose startup, production self-signed fallback is blocked unless dev mode is explicit, and nginx can use an ignored runtime domain config.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 reviewer follow-up on 2026-05-17 fixed clean VPS preflight risk by bootstrapping openssl on RU when needed, rejecting certificate source paths under /opt/KrotPN, and strengthening Phase-35 smoke with dynamic installer validator checks.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 live clean VPS deploy revealed backend startup failure from blank MTProto secrets; 2026-05-17 hotfix generates MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX and MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT during deploy and treats blank optional MTProto env values as safely unset.</item>
    <item>Phase-36 Resend deploy email-provider wiring passed local execution on 2026-05-17 and later clean-deploy registration proof: install.sh asks for a redacted Resend API key and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender, deploy writes EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend/RESEND_API_KEY/RESEND_API_URL/EMAIL_FROM into .env, local smoke verifies request shape/provider_disabled guards/secret redaction, and operator registration via email succeeds on VPS.</item>
    <item>Phase-37 live MTProto shared-443 fix is implemented locally on 2026-05-18: mtproto-runtime is added as a host-network edge service, backend has a token-protected HTTP policy adapter, provisioning applies SNI policy before returning active payloads, nginx HTTPS fallback moves to 8443, deploy generates runtime policy-token/env wiring, and deploy persists Telegram upstream routes through awg-client.</item>
    <item>Phase-38 DE-backed MTProto edge is historical partial-live on 2026-05-18: RU public 443 is HAProxy SNI router, HTTPS reaches private RU nginx fallback on 9443, public admin remains on 8443, DE runtime listens on 443, private policy health is OK, and HAProxy reports the DE MTProto backend UP. Its remaining Telegram proof gap is superseded by Phase-41.</item>
    <item>Phase-39 MTProto availability closure is historical partial-live on 2026-05-18: local/static smoke, 34 backend MTProto regression tests, frontend build, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; redacted live smoke proved active assignment, healthy policy_count, public RU:443 route, validated fake-TLS accept, private DE fallback 9443, and reachable Telegram downstream. Its remaining client proof gap is superseded by Phase-41.</item>
    <item>Phase-40 official MTProxy data-plane and individual user secrets passed local execution on 2026-05-19: official-mtproxy runtime scaffold, Phase-40 RU HTTPS-vs-MTProxy routing, per-user dd-secret owner payloads, redacted secret manifest sync, admin revoke/reissue sync, deploy wiring, and 49 targeted regression/static tests pass. The official MTProxy production path is superseded by Phase-41.</item>
    <item>Phase-40 live MTProxy stability hotfix on 2026-05-19 fixed repeated identical manifest apply restarts: DE official mtproto-proxy keeps running across scheduler/apply cycles, exposes private HTTP stats, uses DE NAT info, and live policy health is healthy. The path remains rollback/reference only after Phase-41.</item>
    <item>Phase-41 KPprotoN fake-TLS production data-plane rollback passed local and live verification on 2026-05-19: official MTProxy is superseded for production, owner payloads return to per-user u-*.krotpn.xyz with ee fake-TLS links, provisioning/admin/scheduler use KPprotoN runtime bridge again, deploy selects the DE KPprotoN runtime plus RU SNI router, and local backend/static/Erlang/compose verification passed.</item>
    <item>Phase-41 live MTProto fix on 2026-05-19 found two blockers: the old seriyps/mtproto_proxy lock and a blank proxy ad tag. mtproto-runtime now pins upstream commit 154a8fb, deploy defaults MTPROTO_AD_TAG to 32 zero hex chars, active assignment replay succeeded, issued-link mtp_ping passed through RU SNI router to DE KPprotoN runtime on DC +1 through +5, and operator clean-deploy testing confirmed both VPN and Telegram Desktop/mobile MTProto proxy work.</item>
    <item>Legacy V-M-029 Phase-16 rebranding verification is closed as superseded by V-M-012/Phase-41 as of 2026-05-19; current deploy-surface gates passed locally and Phase-41 clean-deploy live proof is the active release evidence.</item>
    <item>Phase-42 MTProto usage analytics and promotion tag control passed local execution on 2026-05-19 and operator clean-deploy validation on 2026-05-23: metadata-only usage storage, mtproto_proxy metric backend, active-SNI sampler, private runtime telemetry snapshot/drain, backend ingestion, analytics service, admin API, compact admin UI, observe-only abuse signals, and masked @MTProxyBot promotion tag control are implemented; the operator confirmed registration via @MTProxybot, MTPROTO_AD_TAG restart application, and applied status.</item>
    <item>Phase-43 MTProto admin analytics UX, abuse alerts, and 90-day IP observability passed local execution on 2026-05-20: encrypted admin-only IP history, user/proxy search and detail, current/last/all IP views, timeseries graphs, CPU/RAM runtime metrics, abuse alert inbox, acknowledge/resolve/disable/block actions, storage-budget retention jobs, compact frontend-admin UI, backend tests, frontend build, Erlang compile, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and Phase-43 static smoke passed.</item>
    <item>Phase-43 live-feedback fix on 2026-05-20 passed local verification: MTProto runtime now emits tls_domain/client_ipv4 ip_observation events, backend stores current/last IP without inflating usage counters, abuse alerts require hard multi-IP/concurrency evidence, and admin MTProto UI adds paginated large-list navigation plus compact area graphs.</item>
    <item>MTProto reboot hotfix on 2026-05-23 diagnosed DE awg0 missing after host reboot, enabled awg-quick@awg0 live, restored private policy health, replayed both active user SNI assignments, and added local deploy/runtime/UI regression guards.</item>
    <item>MTProto/VPN reboot resilience fix on 2026-05-23 diagnosed false-green panels after reboot: RU lost transient vpnclients route table/NAT, DE lost NAT, and DE mtproto_proxy had no_pool,2 from incomplete Telegram downstream bootstrap. Live hotfix restored routing/NAT and policy replay; the current RU/DE hosts now have enabled/active krotpn-vpn-runtime.service, DE runtime was rebuilt, and redacted live smoke passed fake-TLS accept plus Telegram downstream reachability.</item>
    <item>Operator clean-deploy and reboot validation on 2026-05-24 confirmed that after the normal startup delay the website, admin panel, VPN, and issued KPprotoN MTProto proxies recover and work after both RU and DE hosts restart.</item>
    <item>MTProto admin UI fix on 2026-05-23 passed local verification: visible technical Signals panel/count was removed from the Abuse screen while alert APIs stay wired, and open alert actions now expose Russian hover descriptions for review, acknowledge, resolve, disable, and IP-block decisions.</item>
    <item>MTProto admin IP history UI fix on 2026-05-23 passed local verification: the investigation drawer no longer renders visible CIDR network masks, and the IP history list is more compact with internal mouse scrolling for long address history.</item>
    <item>Release target v2.24.0-tariffs-branding-stable is the current stable baseline for GitHub main/Releases after the Phase-44 through Phase-51 local release train: email onboarding/password recovery, first-VPN-handshake trial activation, user MTProto link polish, CTA MTProto hostnames, .conf download hardening, BIMI asset delivery, canonical paid tariffs, and favicon/Resend email-logo branding. Earlier Phase-41 and reboot-resilience live evidence remains the active production VPN/MTProto runtime baseline.</item>
    <item>Phase-44 email onboarding UX and password recovery passed local execution on 2026-06-01: branded verification/reset email templates, spam-folder guidance, removal of stale trial/VPN registration copy, strong-password enforcement, one-time password reset tokens, duplicate-email recovery CTA, frontend build, backend auth/email/migration tests, and Phase-44 static smoke passed without deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-45 first-VPN-handshake trial activation passed local execution on 2026-06-01: default trial duration is four days, verified users receive pending VPN trial access, first config remains available, first observed VPN handshake starts the countdown exactly once, subscription API returns server-side days/hours/minutes and active date range, dashboard/subscription UI show pending/countdown/calendar states, backend suite passed 35/35, frontend build and Phase-45 smoke passed, and deploy/install scripts were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-46 user cabinet password and MTProto link UX polish passed local execution on 2026-06-01: registration shows a safe password format example, Telegram proxy actions separate tg:// app link from https://t.me browser link, MTProto labels are Russian, status refresh is bounded at 30 seconds, frontend build and Phase-46 smoke passed, and deploy/install scripts were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-47 MTProto CTA subdomain link generation passed local execution and hotfixes on 2026-06-01: new verified users receive CTA-prefixed one-label MTProto hostnames such as krot-vpn-xxxx.krotpn.xyz, numeric user IDs are hashed into 4-hex public suffixes, explicit prefixes are allow-listed, fake-TLS secrets bind to the final CTA SNI, active legacy u-* assignments are preserved, and the RU HAProxy SNI ACL now routes legacy u-12hex, existing CTA-prefix-7hex, and new CTA-prefix-4hex issued hostnames to the DE KPprotoN runtime. Local Phase-38/41/47 smoke and targeted backend tests passed; install.sh, deploy scripts, nginx, docker-compose, TLS issuance, and runtime topology were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-48 VPN config download MIME and filename hardening passed local execution on 2026-06-01: /api/v1/vpn/config/download now returns application/octet-stream attachment responses with filename and filename-star .conf metadata, nosniff and no-store/private headers, config body bytes are preserved, frontend-created config Blobs use application/octet-stream, backend tests passed 10/10, frontend build and Phase-48 static smoke passed, and deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose surfaces were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-49 BIMI sender branding asset deployment passed local execution on 2026-06-02: the KrotPN BIMI SVG is normalized for Tiny P/S, served from frontend/public/.well-known/bimi/krotpn.svg, frontend nginx allows the BIMI well-known path before hidden-file denial, README documents default._bimi DNS, frontend build copies the SVG unchanged into dist, Phase-49 smoke passed, and protected deploy/install surfaces were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-50 three paid tariffs passed local execution on 2026-06-02: backend now converges the canonical 30-day KrotPN 1/6/9 tariff matrix at 369/693/936 RUB, checkout accepts plan_id only and derives YooKassa amount/metadata server-side, incompatible lower-limit checkout is blocked before payment creation, paid webhook cancels pending trial and updates subscription/device limits, user subscription UI shows compact device-aware tariff cards, admin Plans shows a protected canonical matrix without accidental CRUD controls, backend tests passed 29/29, frontend/admin builds and Phase-50 smoke passed, and protected deploy/install surfaces were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-51 favicon and Resend email-logo branding passed local execution on 2026-06-02: user and admin frontend builds now include real favicon.ico plus PNG fallbacks, the user PWA includes apple/PWA icon assets, verification/reset HTML emails render the public logo at /brand/email-logo.png from FRONTEND_URL, backend email tests passed 5/5, Phase-51 source and dist smoke passed, XML/MyGRACE/diff gates passed, and protected deploy/install surfaces were untouched.</item>
    <item>Phase-52 KrotPN Matrix visual system foundation passed local execution on 2026-06-03: user and admin route trees now mount a shared VisualShell with fixed pointer-safe Matrix canvas, scanline overlay, vignette, Matrix palette tokens, focus-visible rules, and reduced-motion policy; Phase-52 smoke, user/admin builds, Chrome mobile/desktop/reduced-motion screenshot audit, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install guards passed.</item>
  </what-is-working>

  <what-is-fragile>
    <item>Deployment scripts and secrets handling.</item>
    <item>Host-level VPN and routing dependencies.</item>
    <item>Legacy VPNServer compatibility during topology migration.</item>
    <item>Remote credentials handled through temporary operator materialization remain a deployment risk.</item>
    <item>Verification reproducibility across environments.</item>
    <item>MTProto public edge integration now has local/static and clean-VPS live proof through Phase-41; future shared 443/TLS/domain changes still require operator DNS, wildcard TLS, and rollback window readiness.</item>
    <item>Phase-32 shared 443 production smoke is closed by Phase-41 clean VPS evidence; future public 443 changes still require DNS, trusted wildcard TLS material, and rollback window discipline.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 wildcard TLS deploy path is now covered by Phase-41 clean VPS evidence; future certificate replacement remains operator-sensitive.</item>
    <item>Phase-36 Resend delivery is operator-confirmed for registration on clean deploy; future risk is Resend free-tier limits, sender/domain verification drift, or key rotation.</item>
    <item>Phase-37 RU-local MTProto edge remains superseded by Phase-38/39 DE-backed edge work; use Phase-39 evidence for current Telegram availability triage instead of the earlier RU-local downstream blocker.</item>
    <item>Phase-38 and Phase-39 stay historical partial-live phases because their original acceptance gates were superseded; Phase-41 is now the production MTProto closure path.</item>
    <item>Phase-40 is partial-live and superseded by Phase-41: clean deploy, official runtime health, secret sync, unchanged-manifest stability, private stats, and DE NAT info were proven on VPS, but official MTProxy does not match the required per-user SNI/no-restart product model.</item>
    <item>Phase-41 is passed-live: KrotPN provisioning returns ee fake-TLS links and live diagnostics prove policy replay, RU SNI routing, fake-TLS accept, valid non-empty proxy ad tag, issued-link mtp_ping req_pq success, and operator-confirmed Telegram Desktop/mobile connectivity after clean deploy.</item>
    <item>Phase-42 analytics/promotion tag are passed-live for the promotion tag path: active connections, handshakes, closes, protocol errors, req_pq hints, and global bytes are wired from the live runtime; exact per-user byte attribution under concurrent active SNI domains remains a future data-plane-hook limitation.</item>
    <item>Phase-43 analytics are partially passed-live: raw IP data is encrypted and admin-only with 90-day retention, and the clean-deploy validation confirmed real client IP visibility for MTProto users. Resource-metric tuning, graph polish, and TTL IP block runtime enforcement remain future hardening items.</item>
    <item>Phase-45 is passed-local for 4-day pending VPN trial activation on first successful VPN handshake, idempotency, no paid-subscription regression, days/hours/minutes countdown, and subscription calendar UX without deploy/install changes; live clean-deploy validation remains optional before release promotion.</item>
    <item>Phase-47 is passed-local-hotfix for CTA MTProto SNI/link generation and RU SNI router compatibility; live clean-deploy Telegram proof for a CTA-issued hostname is the next operator validation before stable promotion.</item>
    <item>Phase-48 is passed-local for deterministic HTTP/header and frontend Blob behavior; optional live validation remains manual Android Chrome/iOS Safari proof that downloaded files stay as .conf on real devices.</item>
    <item>Phase-49 is passed-local for BIMI asset delivery and DNS runbook; live curl, default._bimi DNS propagation, and mailbox avatar rendering remain operator/provider-side validation after release deployment.</item>
    <item>Phase-50 is passed-local for tariff catalog, checkout, YooKassa payload shape, device-limit guard, UI/API contract, and protected-surface isolation; optional live validation remains clean-deploy review of the three tariffs plus a real or YooKassa test-mode payment.</item>
    <item>Phase-51 is passed-local for favicon/PWA asset delivery and Resend HTML email-logo rendering; optional live validation remains curl/browser proof for https://krotpn.xyz/favicon.ico and https://krotpn.xyz/brand/email-logo.png plus a real delivered Resend email with remote images enabled.</item>
    <item>Phase-52 is passed-local for the shared Matrix visual foundation on login shells; Phase-53 has now applied that foundation to the user cabinet, and Phase-54 admin console redesign now has verification-designed gates for dense admin tables, MTProto analytics, users, devices, plans, and operational charts.</item>
    <item>Phase-53 is passed-local for the user cabinet Matrix redesign: compact auth screens, protected user Layout, dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, settings, Loading state, MTProto card, trial/calendar, and tariff surfaces are retuned with frontend build, Phase-53 smoke, production-preview screenshots, reduced-motion proof, and protected deploy/install isolation.</item>
    <item>Emergency relocation is documented but still blocked until a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target exist for dry-run evidence.</item>
    <item>Cookie-only auth migration is planned but not executed because it requires explicit approval and HTTPS or production-like smoke evidence.</item>
  </what-is-fragile>

  <rollout-gates>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-1" status="passed">
      <summary>Local routing-focused backend verification and admin frontend build pass.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-2" status="passed">
      <summary>Live RU and DE hosts validated with ipset, awg, awg-quick, container startup, HTTPS surfaces and tunnel connectivity after deploy-script hotfixes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-3" status="passed">
      <summary>Admin UI treats route policy as the preferred control surface, and live rollout evidence now exists for the host-managed routing path.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-18-awg-obfuscation" status="passed">
      <summary>Deploy-time AWG stealth obfuscation validated on live RU/DE VPS from GitHub main; CLIENT_PROFILE and RELAY_PROFILE parity, handshakes, client egress and non-rotation upgrade preservation passed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-19-anti-ping-pong-abuse" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local target verification passed: anti-abuse classifier, handshake monitor integration, scheduler interval, cooldown enforcement, audit events and admin anti-abuse context.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-20-vpn-network-addressing-capacity" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local target verification passed and operator-confirmed VPS deployment test passed for release v2.13.0-vpn-network-capacity-stable on 2026-04-20.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-22-emergency-relocation" status="blocked-live">
      <summary>Runbooks and backup manifest contract exist, but restore dry-run requires a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-23-compact-user-cabinet" status="passed-local">
      <summary>User mobile UI local build and viewport smoke passed on 2026-05-10.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-24-compact-admin-console" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Admin mobile UI local build, viewport smoke, and device confirmation guard passed on 2026-05-10.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-25-session-security" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Session security static gate, admin refresh-token cleanup, and blacklist tests passed locally on 2026-05-10; cookie-only migration still requires explicit approval.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-26-stabilization-handoff" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Operator handoff and verification matrix created without touching deploy/install scripts.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="release-v2.14.0-stabilization-stable" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Operator-confirmed clean VPS deployment passed on 2026-05-12; release promoted from local-stabilization prerelease to stable.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-27-email-verification-foundation" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-27 backend tests passed for email delivery and pending verified-registration foundation; active /register remains unchanged until Phase-28.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-28-verified-registration-cutover" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Primary Phase-28 backend, frontend, session smoke, billing route/API, device API, VPN compatibility, referral, MTProto integration, and MyGRACE gates pass locally after stale /api test routes were aligned with /api/v1.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-29-mtproto-provisioning-core" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-29 backend tests passed for assignment registry, migration metadata, deterministic provisioning, verified-user guard, idempotency, and reissue policy; no deploy/install scripts were changed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-30-kpproton-runtime-bridge" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-30 backend tests passed for runtime policy apply, startup replay, degraded bridge handling, safe health summaries, scheduler reconciliation, and M-042/M-043 regression coverage; no deploy/install scripts were changed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-31-mtproto-user-cabinet" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-31 backend tests, frontend build, static mobile/API smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; owner-only MTProto proxy data is now visible in the user cabinet without deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-32-domain-tls-edge" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local Phase-32 static gates passed for krotpn.xyz settings, nginx redirect/fallback contract, compose config, cutover runbook, and protected deploy/install guard; Phase-41 clean VPS evidence closes live DNS/TLS/MTProto shared 443 smoke.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-33-mtproto-admin-ops" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-33 backend tests, frontend-admin build, static smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; admins can inspect redacted MTProto state and run confirmation-safe reissue/revoke with runtime SNI policy removal and without deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-34-mtproto-integration-stabilization" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local Phase-34 backend integration, frontend/admin static smoke, backup/restore docs coverage, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; Phase-41 clean VPS evidence closes live krotpn.xyz DNS/TLS/shared-443/Telegram client smoke.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-35-operator-wildcard-tls-installer" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local Phase-35 shell syntax/static gates passed and Phase-41 clean VPS evidence confirms the operator-provided wildcard TLS path works for production HTTPS and MTProto edge.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-36-resend-deploy-email-provider" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local execution passed for Resend installer/deploy env wiring, backend Settings acceptance, request-shape coverage, provider_disabled regression guards, and redaction; clean VPS registration via email is operator-confirmed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-37-live-mtproto-shared-443-runtime" status="superseded-by-phase-38">
      <summary>Local implementation addressed missing runtime pieces and RU Telegram routes, but the RU-local runtime path was superseded by Phase-38/41 DE-backed SNI routing and KPprotoN pass-live proof.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-38-de-backed-mtproto-edge" status="superseded-by-phase-41">
      <summary>Live RU/DE edge proof passed for public HTTPS, admin 8443, DE listener 443, private policy health, and HAProxy DE backend UP; final assignment replay and Telegram Desktop/mobile proof are closed by Phase-41.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-39-mtproto-availability-closure" status="superseded-by-phase-41">
      <summary>Local and redacted live smoke passed for issued assignment, policy health, RU public 443, fake-TLS accept, DE fallback 9443, and Telegram downstream reachability; final client proof is closed by Phase-41.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-40-official-mtproxy-data-plane" status="superseded-by-phase-41">
      <summary>Local Phase-40 execution passed for official MTProxy runtime scaffold, per-user dd-secret sync, redacted admin/user paths, and RU HTTPS-vs-MTProxy routing; the production path is superseded by Phase-41 KPprotoN fake-TLS.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-41-kpproton-faketls-rollback" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local execution restores KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI as the production MTProto path; live diagnostics fixed the old mtproto_proxy lock and blank ad-tag req_pq blocker, issued-link mtp_ping passes, and operator clean-deploy testing confirms Telegram Desktop/mobile proxy connectivity plus VPN.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="mtproto-reboot-policy-replay-hotfix" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Live RU/DE reboot diagnosis found DE awg0, RU vpnclients policy table/NAT, DE NAT, and incomplete MTProto downstream bootstrap risks; local code now guards DE awg0 boot persistence, runtime POLICY_LISTEN_IP wait, idempotent policy apply, krotpn-vpn-runtime.service route/NAT restore, complete Telegram DC fallback config, and single-message pending UI. Operator clean-deploy and reboot validation on 2026-05-24 confirmed website, admin panel, VPN, and issued KPprotoN MTProto proxies recover after startup delay.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-42-mtproto-analytics-promotion-tag" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local Phase-42 execution passed for metadata-only MTProto analytics, runtime telemetry bridge, admin API/UI redaction, observe-only abuse signals, and safe @MTProxyBot promotion tag control; operator clean-deploy validation on 2026-05-23 confirmed promo tag registration/application with applied state.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-43-mtproto-admin-analytics-alerts-ip-observability" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-43 execution passed for compact admin analytics UX, encrypted 90-day admin-only IP observability, alert inbox/actions with Russian hover help, hidden visible Signals noise, storage retention jobs, backend/API/UI regressions, Erlang compile, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and static redaction smoke; live deployment validation remains the next evidence step.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-44-email-onboarding-password-recovery" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for branded verification/reset emails, spam-folder guidance, strong-password enforcement, password reset, duplicate-email recovery CTA, required log markers, redaction, migration metadata, frontend build, and no deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-45-first-vpn-handshake-trial-activation" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for 4-day pending trial activation by first successful VPN handshake, first-config access, paid/active subscription non-regression, server-time countdown, calendar UX, required log markers, redaction, migration metadata, backend regression suite, frontend build, UX smoke, and no deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-46-user-cabinet-auth-mtproto-ux-polish" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for password format example UX, MTProto tg:// app link vs https://t.me browser link split, Russian proxy labels, bounded status refresh, Phase-46 static smoke, frontend build, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and no deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-47-mtproto-cta-subdomain-link-generation" status="passed-local-short-suffix">
      <summary>Local execution and hotfixes passed for CTA prefix allow-list, 4-hex public short IDs for new assignments, one-label wildcard-safe SNI, final-SNI fake-TLS secret binding, legacy u-* and existing 7-hex CTA assignment preservation, owner tg:// and https://t.me link consistency, RU SNI router 4/7-hex CTA ACL compatibility, redaction, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, frontend build, Phase-38/41/47 smoke, targeted backend tests, and protected install/deploy-script/nginx/docker-compose topology guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-48-vpn-config-download-mime-hardening" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for application/octet-stream attachment downloads, Content-Disposition filename and filename-star .conf metadata, nosniff/no-store headers, safe filename sanitation, body preservation, auth compatibility, frontend Blob MIME, redaction, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, backend tests 10/10, frontend build, Phase-48 static smoke, and protected deploy/install diff guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-49-bimi-sender-branding" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for BIMI Tiny P/S SVG normalization, frontend public asset delivery, frontend nginx /.well-known/bimi allow-rule before hidden-file deny, README DNS instructions, frontend build dist-copy proof, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, Phase-49 smoke, and protected deploy/install diff guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-50-paid-tariff-catalog" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for canonical KrotPN 1/6/9 tariff convergence, server-derived YooKassa amount/metadata, pre-payment downgrade guard, paid webhook pending-trial cancellation, device-limit enforcement for 1/6/9, compact user/admin tariff UI, backend tests 29/29, frontend/admin builds, Phase-50 smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install diff guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-51-favicon-email-logo-branding" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for user/admin favicon assets, user PWA icons, public /brand/email-logo.png, Resend verification/reset HTML logo rendering from FRONTEND_URL, backend email tests 5/5, frontend/admin builds, Phase-51 source and dist smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install diff guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-52-matrix-visual-foundation" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for shared user/admin MatrixBackground and VisualShell, Matrix palette tokens, CRT scanlines, vignette layering, focus-visible and reduced-motion policies, Phase-52 static smoke, user/admin builds, Chrome screenshots at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, reduced-motion 390x844, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install guard.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-53-user-cabinet-matrix-redesign" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for compact Matrix user auth and cabinet routes, removed heavy login hero, preserved auth/VPN/MTProto/trial/tariff/config-download contracts, added scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs, passed frontend build and smoke, captured production-preview mobile/desktop/reduced-motion screenshots with virtual-time-budget, and kept install.sh/deploy/nginx/docker-compose/runtime surfaces untouched.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-54-admin-console-matrix-redesign" status="verification-designed">
      <summary>Verification design is ready for the admin Matrix redesign: V-M-010/V-M-037/V-M-047/V-M-058/V-M-068/V-M-070/V-M-071 now require frontend-admin build, scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs, route smoke for /login, /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, and /analytics, mobile/desktop/reduced-motion screenshot review, MTProto redaction/confirmation gates, canonical Plans guard, XML/MyGRACE/diff checks, and protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime isolation.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="release-v2.24.0-tariffs-branding-stable" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Stable release target includes Phase-44 through Phase-51 local verification: backend email, trial, tariff, billing, device, VPN compatibility, DB migration, MTProto provisioning, frontend/admin builds, Phase-45/46/47/48/49/50/51 smoke gates, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install guards. Operator clean-deploy validation remains the next live evidence step after GitHub push.</summary>
    </gate>
  </rollout-gates>

  <immediate-priorities>
    <priority rank="1">Execute Phase-54 admin console Matrix redesign using the completed verification design and Phase-52/53 foundation, with compact checks for MTProto analytics, users, devices, plans, servers, and operational tables.</priority>
    <priority rank="2">Run clean-deploy validation for Phase-53 user cabinet Matrix redesign after GitHub push, including authenticated dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings review against a real backend session.</priority>
    <priority rank="3">Run clean-deploy validation for the current stable baseline from GitHub main, with review of three tariffs, registration email logo rendering, favicon delivery, and a real or YooKassa test-mode payment when credentials are available.</priority>
    <priority rank="4">Continue Phase-43 admin analytics hardening with real redacted runtime data: graph refresh polish, resource metrics, alert notifications, and TTL IP block runtime enforcement.</priority>
    <priority rank="5">Run Phase-22 non-production restore rehearsal with a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target before production release.</priority>
    <priority rank="6">Decide whether to approve cookie-only auth migration and provide HTTPS or production-like auth smoke target.</priority>
  </immediate-priorities>

  <known-risks>
    <risk severity="critical">Weak/default admin credentials in deployment scripts.</risk>
    <risk severity="critical">Remote credentials handled through sshpass/base64 temporary materialization.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Tokens stored in localStorage in frontends.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Runtime DB compatibility migrations instead of disciplined migration workflow.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Strong dependence on host filesystem and host tools for VPN behavior.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Disaster recovery cannot be considered incident-ready until live or non-production restore rehearsal evidence exists.</risk>
    <risk severity="medium">MTProto production availability is now operator-confirmed after Phase-41, but future runtime/deploy changes must preserve issued-link mtp_ping plus Telegram Desktop/mobile proof before release.</risk>
  </known-risks>

  <handoff-instructions>
    <step>Read this file first.</step>
    <step>Read docs/graph-index.xml second and then only the relevant docs/modules/M-XXX.xml files.</step>
    <step>Read docs/plan-index.xml and then only the relevant docs/plans/Phase-N.xml files.</step>
    <step>Read docs/verification-index.xml and then only the relevant docs/verification/V-M-XXX.xml files.</step>
    <step>Only then inspect the code of the module you are changing.</step>
    <step>After completing work, update the relevant MyGRACE docs if system behavior, priorities or verification changed.</step>
  </handoff-instructions>
</current-status>
