<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Current project status for AI handoff -->
<current-status>
  <meta>
    <project-name>KrotPN</project-name>
    <updated>2026-05-18</updated>
    <status>active-development</status>
  </meta>

  <project-stage>
    <name>MVP implemented, now in hardening and operational cleanup</name>
    <summary>
      Продукт уже содержит работающие backend/frontend/admin/bot/deploy контуры,
      но пока находится не в фазе greenfield implementation, а в фазе stabilization:
      security, deploy, migration discipline, AI handoff and consistency.
    </summary>
  </project-stage>

  <what-is-working>
    <item>Backend domain structure and API surface exist.</item>
    <item>User frontend builds successfully in current local environment.</item>
    <item>Admin frontend code exists as separate app.</item>
    <item>VPN service supports route-aware logic with legacy compatibility.</item>
    <item>Admin route-policy controls and migration-safe routing analytics are implemented.</item>
    <item>Billing, referrals and Telegram bot are implemented at code level.</item>
    <item>Release v2.4.27 is published and includes device-bound access control, per-plan device limits, detect-first handshake anomaly detection, admin peer control, a live Postgres handshake-timestamp hotfix, API exposure of plan device_limit, and the earlier backend-driven manual provisioning plus live awg0 peer activation.</item>
    <item>RU and DE AWG interfaces are now managed through systemd and survive service restarts cleanly.</item>
    <item>DE host successfully rebooted into kernel 6.8.0-106-generic and AWG recovered automatically after boot.</item>
    <item>Fresh RU and DE servers were deployed and validated on March 26, 2026 with live AWG tunnel handshake and healthy backend/frontend/admin HTTPS surfaces on RU.</item>
    <item>Manual internal client issuance through deploy/create-client.sh now produces configs through backend CLI and applies peers to live awg0 state on RU.</item>
    <item>New RU host-level awg0 config watcher automatically syncs peer changes from backend-driven provisioning, so both manual and web-issued clients become active without manual awg commands.</item>
    <item>Release v2.11.0-awg-obfuscation-stable was deployed from GitHub main and operator-validated on RU/DE VPS with AWG stealth obfuscation, profile parity, RU-DE handshake, new client handshake, DE egress, and upgrade preservation.</item>
    <item>Phase-19 anti-ping-pong abuse detection is implemented locally: observe-mode roaming tolerance, Redis-backed endpoint history, soft auto-rotation path, admin anti-abuse context, and V-M-031 verification passed on 2026-04-20.</item>
    <item>Phase-20 configurable VPN subnets and 1000-device capacity is live-tested: release v2.13.0-vpn-network-capacity-stable deployed successfully on VPS, fresh deploy defaults use 172.29.0.0/22 for clients and 172.29.255.0/30 for RU/DE relay, capacity validation rejects /24 for 1000 devices, and address-pool migration requires VPN_NETWORK_ROTATE=1.</item>
    <item>Phase-23 compact mobile user cabinet passed local build and Chrome CDP mobile smoke for dashboard, config, and subscription routes.</item>
    <item>Phase-24 compact mobile admin console passed local build and Chrome/CDP mobile smoke for overview, users, devices, and analytics with confirmation-safe device actions.</item>
    <item>Phase-25 session-security gates passed locally: static auth guard, admin refresh-token lifecycle cleanup, and token blacklist unit tests.</item>
    <item>Phase-26 stabilization handoff records local evidence, protected deploy/install surfaces, and live-required recovery blockers.</item>
    <item>Release v2.14.0-stabilization-stable was operator-deployed from local PC to clean VPS servers and manually validated as working on 2026-05-12.</item>
    <item>Phase-27 email verification foundation passed local verification on 2026-05-13: provider-neutral email delivery, pending registration, HMAC token storage, domain guards, replay/expiry checks, and no /register cutover.</item>
    <item>Phase-28 verified registration cutover primary gates passed local verification on 2026-05-13: /register is pending-only, /verify-email activates user access once, trial/VPN/referral side effects are delayed until email proof, and frontend check-email/verify states build. Full wave status is partial-local after 2026-05-14 refresh because V-M-004 and V-M-022 cross-module route/API gates currently fail.</item>
    <item>Phase-29 MTProto provisioning core passed local verification on 2026-05-14: restore-safe assignment registry, Alembic migration metadata, deterministic SNI, KPprotoN-compatible fake-TLS secret vector, tg://proxy assembly, verified-user guard, idempotent reuse, and explicit reissue policy.</item>
    <item>Phase-30 KPprotoN runtime bridge passed local verification on 2026-05-14: fake/local adapter boundary, startup replay, degraded bridge semantics, secret-free runtime health, MTProto scheduler reconciliation, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-31 MTProto user cabinet UX passed local verification on 2026-05-14: owner-only /api/v1/mtproto/proxy endpoint, compact dashboard proxy card, Telegram open/copy actions, safe unverified/pending/reissue states, frontend build, static mobile/API smoke, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-32 domain TLS edge passed local/static verification on 2026-05-14: krotpn.xyz settings, HTTP to HTTPS redirect contract, wildcard HTTPS fallback, compose config, protected deploy/install guard, rollback/live-smoke checklist, and M-044/M-043/M-040 regression tests.</item>
    <item>Phase-33 MTProto admin ops passed local verification on 2026-05-14: admin-only redacted assignment list/detail/health, confirmation-safe reissue/revoke with runtime SNI policy removal, safe audit events, compact frontend-admin /mtproto page, backend regression tests, frontend build, static smoke, and no deploy/install changes.</item>
    <item>Phase-34 MTProto integration stabilization passed local verification on 2026-05-14: verified email activation to owner MTProto assignment integration, static frontend/admin redaction smoke, MTProto backup/restore documentation coverage, and release handoff checklist were added without deploy/install/edge surface changes. Live DNS/TLS/shared-443 smoke remains operator-required.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 operator wildcard TLS installer passed local/static verification on 2026-05-17: install.sh now asks for domain, fullchain1.pem and privkey1.pem paths, deploy validates operator wildcard TLS material before compose startup, production self-signed fallback is blocked unless dev mode is explicit, and nginx can use an ignored runtime domain config. Clean VPS deploy with real wildcard certificate files remains operator-required.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 reviewer follow-up on 2026-05-17 fixed clean VPS preflight risk by bootstrapping openssl on RU when needed, rejecting certificate source paths under /opt/KrotPN, and strengthening Phase-35 smoke with dynamic installer validator checks.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 live clean VPS deploy revealed backend startup failure from blank MTProto secrets; 2026-05-17 hotfix generates MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX and MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT during deploy and treats blank optional MTProto env values as safely unset.</item>
    <item>Phase-36 Resend deploy email-provider wiring passed local execution on 2026-05-17: install.sh now asks for a redacted Resend API key and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender, deploy writes EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend/RESEND_API_KEY/RESEND_API_URL/EMAIL_FROM into .env, and local smoke verifies request shape, provider_disabled regression guards, and secret redaction. Live mailbox proof remains operator-blocked until Resend domain verification completes.</item>
    <item>Phase-37 live MTProto shared-443 fix is implemented locally on 2026-05-18: mtproto-runtime is added as a host-network edge service, backend has a token-protected HTTP policy adapter, provisioning applies SNI policy before returning active payloads, nginx HTTPS fallback moves to 8443, deploy generates runtime policy-token/env wiring, and deploy persists Telegram upstream routes through awg-client.</item>
    <item>Phase-38 DE-backed MTProto edge is partial-live on 2026-05-18: RU public 443 is HAProxy SNI router, HTTPS reaches private RU nginx fallback on 9443, public admin remains on 8443, DE runtime listens on 443, private policy health is OK, and HAProxy reports the DE MTProto backend UP. Telegram Desktop proof remains operator-required.</item>
  </what-is-working>

  <what-is-fragile>
    <item>Deployment scripts and secrets handling.</item>
    <item>Host-level VPN and routing dependencies.</item>
    <item>Legacy VPNServer compatibility during topology migration.</item>
    <item>Remote credentials handled through temporary operator materialization remain a deployment risk.</item>
    <item>Verification reproducibility across environments.</item>
    <item>MTProto public edge integration has local/static coverage through Phases 31-34, but shared 443/TLS/domain live proof is still deferred until operator DNS, wildcard TLS, and rollback window are ready.</item>
    <item>Phase-32 shared 443 production smoke remains blocked until DNS, trusted wildcard TLS material, and an operator rollback window are available.</item>
    <item>Phase-35 clean VPS wildcard TLS deploy smoke remains operator-live until prepared fullchain1.pem/privkey1.pem files are present on the RU server and public HTTPS is verified.</item>
    <item>Phase-36 live Resend mailbox smoke remains pending until the Resend API key is available and krotpn.xyz/noreply@krotpn.xyz verification is complete in Resend.</item>
    <item>Phase-37 live Telegram availability proof is blocked-live: RU mtproto-edge policy API starts, but mtproto_proxy still fails downstream Telegram handshakes after scoped routes via awg-client; nginx public 443 was restored on RU to keep the web product available while the MTProto edge remains unavailable.</item>
    <item>Phase-38 is partial-live: RU public web, direct admin 8443, DE runtime listener, private policy health, and RU-to-DE HAProxy reachability are verified on VPS; assignment replay and Telegram Desktop available status remain pending.</item>
    <item>Emergency relocation is documented but still blocked until a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target exist for dry-run evidence.</item>
    <item>Cookie-only auth migration is planned but not executed because it requires explicit approval and HTTPS or production-like smoke evidence.</item>
  </what-is-fragile>

  <rollout-gates>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-1" status="passed">
      <summary>Local routing-focused backend verification and admin frontend build pass.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-2" status="passed">
      <summary>Live RU and DE hosts validated with ipset, awg, awg-quick, container startup, HTTPS surfaces and tunnel connectivity after deploy-script hotfixes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="routing-phase-4-step-3" status="passed">
      <summary>Admin UI treats route policy as the preferred control surface, and live rollout evidence now exists for the host-managed routing path.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-18-awg-obfuscation" status="passed">
      <summary>Deploy-time AWG stealth obfuscation validated on live RU/DE VPS from GitHub main; CLIENT_PROFILE and RELAY_PROFILE parity, handshakes, client egress and non-rotation upgrade preservation passed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-19-anti-ping-pong-abuse" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local target verification passed: anti-abuse classifier, handshake monitor integration, scheduler interval, cooldown enforcement, audit events and admin anti-abuse context.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-20-vpn-network-addressing-capacity" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Local target verification passed and operator-confirmed VPS deployment test passed for release v2.13.0-vpn-network-capacity-stable on 2026-04-20.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-22-emergency-relocation" status="blocked-live">
      <summary>Runbooks and backup manifest contract exist, but restore dry-run requires a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-23-compact-user-cabinet" status="passed-local">
      <summary>User mobile UI local build and viewport smoke passed on 2026-05-10.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-24-compact-admin-console" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Admin mobile UI local build, viewport smoke, and device confirmation guard passed on 2026-05-10.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-25-session-security" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Session security static gate, admin refresh-token cleanup, and blacklist tests passed locally on 2026-05-10; cookie-only migration still requires explicit approval.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-26-stabilization-handoff" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Operator handoff and verification matrix created without touching deploy/install scripts.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="release-v2.14.0-stabilization-stable" status="passed-live">
      <summary>Operator-confirmed clean VPS deployment passed on 2026-05-12; release promoted from local-stabilization prerelease to stable.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-27-email-verification-foundation" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-27 backend tests passed for email delivery and pending verified-registration foundation; active /register remains unchanged until Phase-28.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-28-verified-registration-cutover" status="partial-local">
      <summary>Primary Phase-28 backend, frontend, session smoke, and MyGRACE gates passed, but full wave closure is partial until V-M-004 billing route/API tests and V-M-022 VPN compatibility route tests pass.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-29-mtproto-provisioning-core" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-29 backend tests passed for assignment registry, migration metadata, deterministic provisioning, verified-user guard, idempotency, and reissue policy; no deploy/install scripts were changed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-30-kpproton-runtime-bridge" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-30 backend tests passed for runtime policy apply, startup replay, degraded bridge handling, safe health summaries, scheduler reconciliation, and M-042/M-043 regression coverage; no deploy/install scripts were changed.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-31-mtproto-user-cabinet" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-31 backend tests, frontend build, static mobile/API smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; owner-only MTProto proxy data is now visible in the user cabinet without deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-32-domain-tls-edge" status="partial-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-32 static gates passed for krotpn.xyz settings, nginx redirect/fallback contract, compose config, cutover runbook, and protected deploy/install guard; live DNS/TLS/MTProto shared 443 smoke remains operator-required.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-33-mtproto-admin-ops" status="passed-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-33 backend tests, frontend-admin build, static smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; admins can inspect redacted MTProto state and run confirmation-safe reissue/revoke with runtime SNI policy removal and without deploy/install changes.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-34-mtproto-integration-stabilization" status="partial-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-34 backend integration, frontend/admin static smoke, backup/restore docs coverage, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; live krotpn.xyz DNS/TLS/shared-443/Telegram client smoke remains operator-required.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-35-operator-wildcard-tls-installer" status="partial-local">
      <summary>Local Phase-35 shell syntax, static installer TLS smoke, edge guard smoke, domain TLS pytest, docker compose config, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed; clean VPS deploy with prepared wildcard TLS files remains operator-required.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-36-resend-deploy-email-provider" status="partial-local">
      <summary>Local execution passed for Resend installer/deploy env wiring, backend Settings acceptance, request-shape coverage, provider_disabled regression guards, and redaction; controlled-mailbox live smoke waits for Resend domain verification and real API key.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-37-live-mtproto-shared-443-runtime" status="blocked-live">
      <summary>Local implementation addresses the missing runtime pieces and RU Telegram routes, but mtproto_proxy still fails downstream handshakes; nginx public 443 rollback keeps HTTPS available until the upstream/proxy runtime blocker is resolved.</summary>
    </gate>
    <gate id="phase-38-de-backed-mtproto-edge" status="partial-live">
      <summary>Live RU/DE edge proof passed for public HTTPS, admin 8443, DE listener 443, private policy health, and HAProxy DE backend UP; assignment replay and Telegram Desktop proof remain operator-live.</summary>
    </gate>
  </rollout-gates>

  <immediate-priorities>
    <priority rank="1">Finish Phase-38 live proof by retesting an issued Telegram Desktop MTProto proxy and confirming active assignment replay after backend/runtime restart.</priority>
    <priority rank="2">Complete Phase-36 live Resend mailbox smoke after the operator provides the Resend API key and confirms krotpn.xyz/noreply@krotpn.xyz verification in Resend.</priority>
    <priority rank="3">Fix Phase-28 refresh findings: V-M-004 billing route/API tests and V-M-022 VPN compatibility route tests currently return 404 in their full per-module gates.</priority>
    <priority rank="4">Complete remaining Phase-32/Phase-34/Phase-35 live edge smoke after Phase-38 public 443 routing is stable, trusted wildcard TLS is installed, an issued MTProto SNI is available, and an operator rollback window is available.</priority>
    <priority rank="5">Run Phase-22 non-production restore rehearsal with a trusted backup bundle and isolated restore target.</priority>
    <priority rank="6">Decide whether to approve cookie-only auth migration and provide HTTPS or production-like auth smoke target.</priority>
    <priority rank="7">Keep deploy/install scripts unchanged unless the operator explicitly requests deployment-surface work.</priority>
    <priority rank="8">Improve repeatable local verification for backend, user frontend, and admin frontend.</priority>
    <priority rank="9">Tune false-positive thresholds before enabling any automatic anti-sharing block policy beyond admin-reviewed detect-first mode.</priority>
  </immediate-priorities>

  <known-risks>
    <risk severity="critical">Weak/default admin credentials in deployment scripts.</risk>
    <risk severity="critical">Remote credentials handled through sshpass/base64 temporary materialization.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Tokens stored in localStorage in frontends.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Runtime DB compatibility migrations instead of disciplined migration workflow.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Strong dependence on host filesystem and host tools for VPN behavior.</risk>
    <risk severity="high">Disaster recovery cannot be considered incident-ready until live or non-production restore rehearsal evidence exists.</risk>
  </known-risks>

  <handoff-instructions>
    <step>Read this file first.</step>
    <step>Read docs/graph-index.xml second and then only the relevant docs/modules/M-XXX.xml files.</step>
    <step>Read docs/plan-index.xml and then only the relevant docs/plans/Phase-N.xml files.</step>
    <step>Read docs/verification-index.xml and then only the relevant docs/verification/V-M-XXX.xml files.</step>
    <step>Only then inspect the code of the module you are changing.</step>
    <step>After completing work, update the relevant MyGRACE docs if system behavior, priorities or verification changed.</step>
  </handoff-instructions>
</current-status>
