<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- GRACE Requirements for KrotPN — Contract-first requirements, actors, use cases, constraints, risks -->
<RequirementsAnalysis VERSION="1.0.0">
  <Project>
    <name>KrotPN</name>
    <annotation>Commercial VPN service on AmneziaWG with user dashboard, admin panel, billing, referrals, Telegram bot, and two-node RU/DE network topology</annotation>
    <keywords>VPN, WireGuard, split-tunneling, routing, billing, subscriptions, Telegram bot, admin panel, FastAPI, Vue.js, YooKassa, Docker, AWG</keywords>
  </Project>

  <Actors>
    <actor-User>End user who registers, subscribes, receives VPN config, and connects to the VPN service</actor-User>
    <actor-Administrator>Service operator managing users, tariffs, nodes, routes, policy rules, and analytics</actor-Administrator>
    <actor-System>Automated backend services for auth, billing, webhook processing, DNS refresh, route sync</actor-System>
    <actor-TelegramBot>Telegram bot client that mediates auth, config delivery, and subscription status for users</actor-TelegramBot>
    <actor-PaymentProvider>External YooKassa payment system processing subscriptions</actor-PaymentProvider>
  </Actors>

  <UseCases>
    <UC-001>
      <Name>Domain-first route selection</Name>
      <Actor>System</Actor>
      <Action>Evaluates routing policy by domain before IP-based geography</Action>
      <Goal>Accept routing decision by domain policy earlier than by general IP geography</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Domain is known for the traffic flow; policy rules exist in the system</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Exact-domain rule has priority over wildcard-domain rule. Wildcard-domain rule has priority over CIDR rule. Without explicit policy, current RU baseline is preserved.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-006, DF-007</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-001>

    <UC-002>
      <Name>Foreign CDN domain with changing IPs</Name>
      <Actor>System</Actor>
      <Action>Resolves domain to DE exit node even when IPs rotate due to CDN or DNS changes</Action>
      <Goal>Domain with DE policy stays routed through DE despite IP changes</Goal>
      <Preconditions>DNS binding is active; TTL is known and respected</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>DNS binding updates on TTL expiry. Expired bindings do not remain active indefinitely. IP changes do not break policy semantics for known domains.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-007</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-002>

    <UC-003>
      <Name>Admin-managed routing policy</Name>
      <Actor>Administrator</Actor>
      <Action>Creates, modifies, disables, and reviews routing policy rules</Action>
      <Goal>Admin can manage routing policy via API and UI with runtime sync</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Admin is authenticated; admin UI and API are operational</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Admin API and UI reflect effective route target and decision reason. Policy changes trigger runtime sync without losing unrelated rules.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>high</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-005</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-003>

    <UC-004>
      <Name>Backward-compatible fallback behavior</Name>
      <Actor>System</Actor>
      <Action>Falls back to RU-vs-non-RU baseline when domain policy coverage is incomplete</Action>
      <Goal>Do not break existing routing while domain rules are rolled out incrementally</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Domain policy coverage is partial; legacy RU baseline is active</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Unknown domain without explicit policy goes to CIDR evaluation then current RU baseline. Phased rollout is possible without mandatory mass override of existing rules.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>high</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-006</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-004>

    <UC-005>
      <Name>Email registration and trial provisioning</Name>
      <Actor>User</Actor>
      <Action>Registers by email, receives trial subscription and VPN client</Action>
      <Goal>User gets VPN access with minimal steps: register, trial, config, connect</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Email is valid; system can send confirmation or skip verification</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>User receives trial subscription, VPN client config (text/file/QR), and can connect successfully.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-001</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-005>

    <UC-006>
      <Name>Telegram authentication</Name>
      <Actor>User</Actor>
      <Action>Logs in via Telegram widget or bot-mediated auth</Action>
      <Goal>Same access to config and subscription as email auth</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Telegram account exists; bot is operational</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>User authenticated via Telegram receives identical access to VPN config and subscription status.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-002</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-006>

    <UC-007>
      <Name>Paid subscription activation</Name>
      <Actor>User, PaymentProvider</Actor>
      <Action>Selects plan, creates payment, webhook confirms, subscription activates</Action>
      <Goal>Paid subscription provides full VPN access and billing continuity</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Plan exists; payment provider is configured; webhook endpoint is reachable</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Payment confirmed via webhook → subscription activated → VPN access maintained or reactivated. Billing records consistent.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-003</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-007>

    <UC-008>
      <Name>Admin operations dashboard</Name>
      <Actor>Administrator</Actor>
      <Action>Reviews users, tariffs, node status, routes, policy rules, and analytics</Action>
      <Goal>Full visibility into service state for operational management</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Admin authenticated; admin frontend and API operational</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Admin UI displays consistent user counts, tariff data, node health, route status, policy rules, and basic business metrics.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>high</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-005</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-008>

    <UC-009>
      <Name>Non-conflicting VPN addressing and capacity sizing</Name>
      <Actor>Administrator</Actor>
      <Action>Deploys KrotPN with non-10.0.0.0/8 VPN networks and selects a capacity-safe client address pool</Action>
      <Goal>KrotPN coexists with OpenVPN using 10.0.0.0/8 and can serve 500/1000 client devices</Goal>
      <Preconditions>Operator controls deployment env settings; RU/DE nodes can be reconfigured through deploy scripts</Preconditions>
      <AcceptanceCriteria>Fresh deployment can use 172.x tunnel networks. A 1000-device profile rejects /24 pools and accepts a pool with at least 1000 usable client addresses. Existing client configs are not silently invalidated during upgrade.</AcceptanceCriteria>
      <Priority>critical</Priority>
      <RelatedFlows>DF-P20-FRESH-DEPLOY, DF-P20-CAPACITY</RelatedFlows>
    </UC-009>
  </UseCases>

  <NonGoals>
    <item-1>Native mobile applications (iOS/Android)</item-1>
    <item-2>Full self-service support center and ticketing</item-2>
    <item-3>Deep packet inspection or payload-level traffic inspection</item-3>
    <item-4>Enterprise-grade observability stack and autoscaling in current phase</item-4>
    <item-5>Multi-region deployment beyond RU/DE two-node topology</item-5>
  </NonGoals>

  <Constraints>
    <constraint-1>Two-node deployment: RU entry + DE exit, Docker Compose based</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Secrets must never appear in logs or client-side storage (localStorage tokens must be migrated)</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>VPN and routing code is host-coupled (not purely containerized) — iptables, ipset, AWG require host-level access</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Single PostgreSQL database, single Redis instance per deployment</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Migration from legacy VPNServer to VPNNode/VPNRoute must be backward-compatible</constraint-5>
  </Constraints>

  <Risks>
    <risk-1>Weak secrets in deploy scripts (sshpass, base64-encoded tokens, hardcoded credentials)</risk-1>
    <risk-2>Runtime database migrations without Alembic workflow may corrupt schema</risk-2>
    <risk-3>Long-running DNS-bound routing may leak stale addresses after TTL expiry if cleanup fails</risk-3>
    <risk-4>Webhook delivery failures from YooKassa may leave subscriptions in inconsistent state</risk-4>
    <risk-5>Host-coupled routing code makes testing and local development environment-dependent</risk-5>
    <risk-6>Referral bonus processing edge cases (self-referral, circular chains, duplicate bonuses)</risk-6>
  </Risks>

  <OpenQuestions>
    <question-1>Should Alembic migrations be fully automated or require explicit admin approval for schema changes?</question-1>
    <question-2>What is the exact threshold for anti-sharing violations before auto-suspension?</question-2>
    <question-3>Should Telegram bot support full subscription management or remain config-delivery-only?</question-3>
    <question-4>How to handle VPN config versioning when user switches plans or nodes change?</question-4>
    <question-5>Should domain-aware routing policy support user-custom rules or remain admin-only?</question-5>
  </OpenQuestions>
</RequirementsAnalysis>
