<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-024 MODULE="M-024" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass">
  <module>device-admin-control</module>
  <checks>Admin endpoints can list devices, view anomaly and recent anti-abuse context, and block or unblock or revoke a specific device peer while preserving user-level auth boundaries.</checks>
  <test-files>backend/tests/test_admin_device_control.py</test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_admin_device_control.py -v</commands>
  <anchors>VPN_DEVICE_BLOCKED VPN_DEVICE_UNBLOCKED VPN_DEVICE_REVOKED recent_anti_abuse_event_types</anchors>
  <phase-24-contract-guard>
    <guard-1>Frontend device actions must keep one-device targeting for block, unblock, rotate, and revoke.</guard-1>
    <guard-2>UI confirmation text must identify the target device/user before mutation and must not imply whole-account disablement.</guard-2>
    <guard-3>If backend device-control files or frontend endpoint bindings change during Phase-24, rerun this verification before marking V-M-037 pass-local.</guard-3>
  </phase-24-contract-guard>
  <levels>
    <module-local>Run backend device admin tests if M-024 files or frontend-admin device API bindings change.</module-local>
    <wave-level>During Phase-24 UI waves, static review confirms action buttons call confirmation logic before existing M-024 endpoint bindings.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Final Phase-24 evidence records confirmation-safe UI plus either no backend/device-control diff or a passing V-M-024 rerun.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="VPN_DEVICE_BLOCKED">Admin blocks specific device peer without affecting other devices</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="recent_anti_abuse_event_types">Admin device payload exposes recent anti-abuse event context for operator triage</scenario>
    <scenario kind="failure" trace="VPN_DEVICE_BLOCKED">Enforcement bypasses auth or disables whole user account instead of targeted device</scenario>
    <scenario kind="failure" trace="PHASE24_DIRECT_MUTATION">Frontend row controls execute block, unblock, rotate, or revoke without an explicit confirmation surface</scenario>
  </scenarios>
  <observability>
    <telemetry-1>Device-control evidence records device id surrogate, action name, confirmation state, result status, and refreshed list behavior.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>Evidence must not contain peer private keys, full VPN configs, bearer tokens, or raw endpoint IPs when screenshots/text logs are saved.</telemetry-2>
  </observability>
  <phase-24-evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-10: Phase-24 did not modify backend/app/admin/router.py or M-024 backend enforcement logic.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-10: Device UI action smoke confirmed a one-device confirmation surface before mutation and observed no mutation request before confirm.</evidence-2>
  </phase-24-evidence>
</V-M-024>
