<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-036 MODULE="M-036" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase46-phase53-pass-local-phase68" VERSION="1.5.0" PHASE-68="pass-local" PHASE-69="verification-designed" PHASE-70="verification-designed">
  <module>mobile-user-cabinet</module>
  <checks>User frontend must become compact, phone-friendly, and focused on VPN config, subscription, device workflows, and Phase-45 pending trial countdown/calendar UX.</checks>
  <test-files>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/components/Loading.tsx frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</test-files>
  <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; Phase-23 mobile smoke for /, /config, and /subscription at 360x740, 390x844, and 430x932; node scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; assert documentElement.scrollWidth &lt;= innerWidth and primary config path &lt;= 2 taps</commands>
  <levels>
    <module-local>TypeScript/Vite build must pass for the user frontend after each execution step that changes Phase-23 files.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Authenticated mobile route smoke must cover dashboard, config/device, and subscription workflows after UI shell and page changes are merged.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Final Phase-23 evidence must record viewport results, config action reachability, and unchanged backend API shapes.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <verification-matrix>
    <route-home path="/">
      Check VPN status, subscription state, primary config CTA, and active device summary appear on first mobile screen or after one navigation tap.
    </route-home>
    <route-config path="/config">
      Check create device, rotate device, revoke device, QR, copy, and .conf download controls remain present without wide table or raw-config page overflow.
    </route-config>
    <route-subscription path="/subscription">
      Check current subscription state, days left, plan price, duration, and renewal/payment button remain readable on all mobile viewports.
    </route-subscription>
    <route-phase45-subscription path="/subscription">
      Check pending-first-VPN state, server-derived days/hours/minutes, and active subscription date calendar remain compact and do not show stale 3-day trial copy.
    </route-phase45-subscription>
    <route-empty-states path="/,/config,/subscription">
      Check loading, forbidden/no-config, no-devices, no-plans, expired-subscription, and request-error states keep an actionable next step.
    </route-empty-states>
  </verification-matrix>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Frontend build passes.</check-1>
    <check-2>Mobile dashboard, config, devices, and subscription paths have no document-level horizontal scroll or overlapping text.</check-2>
    <check-3>Config download/QR action is reachable within one or two taps.</check-3>
    <check-4>Subscription and device state remain visible without oversized decorative sections.</check-4>
    <check-5>Create device, rotate device, revoke device, QR, copy, and .conf download controls remain present.</check-5>
    <check-6>Existing backend API request/response shapes are unchanged in Phase-23.</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-45 dashboard and subscription pages render pending activation, remaining days/hours/minutes, and calendar marker from the subscription API fields.</check-7>
    <check-8>Phase-46 MTProto dashboard card keeps dual-link actions, Russian labels, and bounded status refresh compact in the mobile cabinet.</check-8>
    <check-9>Phase-53 Matrix redesign keeps dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, and settings compact without decorative route bloat or nested cards.</check-9>
    <check-10>Phase-53 route smoke confirms primary VPN/config/MTProto/subscription actions are reachable within one or two taps on phone viewports.</check-10>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-53-matrix-route-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Dashboard first screen prioritizes VPN state, primary config action, MTProto proxy state, subscription countdown, and device slots over decorative content.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Config route keeps QR, copy, .conf download, create, rotate, and revoke controls compact and unchanged at the API layer.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Subscription route keeps countdown, calendar, current plan, and tariff CTA readable with stable dimensions.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Referrals and settings routes use compact rows and safe wrapping for long emails, referral links, device names, and status labels.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Loading, empty, success, warning, and error states do not resize fixed controls or hide primary actions.</gate-5>
  </phase-53-matrix-route-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Authenticated user opens the cabinet on a phone and immediately sees VPN status, config action, subscription state, and active device summary.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">User opens config flow, selects or creates a device, then reaches QR, copy, and .conf download without desktop-only layout.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">User with expired or missing subscription sees a clear renewal/payment action instead of dead config controls.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Primary VPN action is buried behind desktop-only navigation or a large decorative layout.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">A mobile viewport introduces horizontal scroll, hidden controls, clipped critical text, or overlapping action buttons.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Simplification removes device-bound rotate/revoke/config retrieval behavior.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="success">Pending trial user sees that the four-day timer starts after first VPN connection; activated trial user sees remaining days, hours, minutes, and highlighted active dates.</scenario-7>
  </scenarios>
  <critical-invariants>
    <invariant-1>No backend API endpoint, request body, or response shape changes are introduced by Phase-23.</invariant-1>
    <invariant-2>Destructive device actions remain visually secondary and confirmation-safe when implemented.</invariant-2>
    <invariant-3>Expired or missing subscription never leaves the user without a visible payment/renewal path.</invariant-3>
    <invariant-4>Deploy, install, Docker, nginx, and remote-server automation files remain out of scope.</invariant-4>
  </critical-invariants>
  <viewport-gates>
    <viewport-1 width="360" height="740">Home, config, subscription, and device controls visible without horizontal scroll.</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2 width="390" height="844">Primary VPN config path is reachable within one or two taps.</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3 width="430" height="932">Long user email, device name, device key, plan name, and status labels do not overlap controls.</viewport-3>
  </viewport-gates>
  <observability>
    <telemetry-1>Viewport smoke evidence must include route, viewport, scrollWidth, innerWidth, and checked primary action.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>Evidence must not include access tokens, refresh tokens, raw VPN private keys, raw .env values, or full config contents.</telemetry-2>
    <telemetry-3>When browser automation is unavailable, manual evidence must still record the same route and viewport fields.</telemetry-3>
  </observability>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[FrontendUser][Phase23][BUILD_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[FrontendUser][Phase23][MOBILE_VIEWPORT_SAFE]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[FrontendUser][Phase23][PRIMARY_CONFIG_REACHABLE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[FrontendUser][Phase23][API_SHAPE_UNCHANGED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MobileUserCabinet][Phase53][ROUTE_VIEWPORT_SAFE]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MobileUserCabinet][Phase53][PRIMARY_ACTIONS_REACHABLE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MobileUserCabinet][Phase53][STATE_SURFACES_STABLE]</marker-7>
  </required-log-markers>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>Record frontend build result.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>Record viewport smoke result with scrollWidth not greater than innerWidth for the tested routes.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>Record action reachability for config QR/download/copy from mobile home.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>Record that device create/rotate/revoke controls and subscription payment entry are still present.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-10: npm run build passed; Chrome CDP smoke passed for /, /config, /subscription at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932 with no horizontal scroll and required actions present.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-01: frontend npm run build passed and node scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs passed for pending trial copy, countdown fields, active-date calendar marker, and stale 3-day copy guard.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-06-01: frontend npm run build passed and node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs passed for password example, MTProto dual links, Russian labels, and bounded status refresh.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-06-03: frontend npm run build and node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs passed for Matrix dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings route structure, primary action reachability, state surfaces, and protected deploy/install isolation.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-06-04: Phase-68 frontend build and dashboard/subscription smoke passed after /dashboard became the compact MTProto-first cabinet with subscription, tariff, and calendar controls directly below it.</evidence-9>
  </evidence>
  <autonomous-execution-safety status="allowed-after-build-and-mobile-smoke">
    Autonomous execution may proceed inside Phase-23 user frontend files if each step preserves module contracts, keeps deploy/install out of scope, and records build plus viewport evidence before commit.
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-68-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>User cabinet layout verification for the merged dashboard/subscription flow.</scope>
    <gate-1>Sidebar/top logo must use the unframed visual treatment and must not crowd mobile navigation.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Primary dashboard content order must be MTProto first, subscription second, without decorative command-center or secondary-fold bloat.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>All cabinet buttons must keep compact Matrix microinteractions, visible focus, disabled states, and reduced-motion fallback.</gate-3>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-68-verification-design>
  <phase-69-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Referral UI verification for masked invite identity and truthful bonus state.</scope>
    <gate-1>Recent invite rows must show partially masked referred email instead of generic "Реферал #N".</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Referral UI must not reveal full referred email, payment IDs, backend user IDs, or hidden bonus internals.</gate-2>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-69-verification-design>
  <phase-70-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Config page compactness and QR reachability verification.</scope>
    <gate-1>Config page must remove diagnostic/raw-config panels while preserving QR, download, copy, and device configuration workflows.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Mobile config route must have no horizontal scroll and no clipped QR/action controls.</gate-2>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-70-verification-design>
</V-M-036>
