<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-071 MODULE="M-071" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase52-phase53-phase54-phase55-phase56-phase59-pass-local-phase67-pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase70-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72-pass-local-phase73-pass-local-phase74" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-55="pass-local" PHASE-56="pass-local" PHASE-59="pass-local" PHASE-67="pass-local" RAINFIX="pass-local" PHASE-68="pass-local" PHASE-70="pass-local" PHASE-71="pass-local" PHASE-72="pass-local" PHASE-73="pass-local" PHASE-74="pass-local">
  <scope>
    <phase>Phase-52</phase>
    <purpose>Verify the Matrix style system foundation for compact, readable, mobile-safe user and admin shells.</purpose>
    <module-ref>docs/modules/M-071.xml</module-ref>
  </scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="54-pass-local">scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="55-pass-local">scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="56-pass-local">scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="59-pass-local">scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="rainfix-pass-local">scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="67-pass-local">scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="70-pass-local">scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="71-pass-local">scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="72-pass-local">scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="73-pass-local">scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="74-pass-local">scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-2>
    <check-3>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4>Viewport smoke: 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1440x900.</check-4>
    <check-5>Reduced-motion smoke: all transform-heavy, flicker-heavy, and scanline-heavy effects are disabled or simplified.</check-5>
    <check-6>git diff --name-only -- install.sh deploy nginx docker-compose.yml</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-53 viewport smoke: auth, dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, settings, reduced-motion dashboard, and desktop user route screenshots.</check-7>
    <check-8>Phase-54 local static viewport/style smoke: admin login, dashboard, users, devices, MTProto, servers, plans, analytics, reduced-motion markers, compact primitives, and protected route source guards; authenticated screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up.</check-8>
    <check-9>Phase-55 premium art-direction smoke: shared premium tokens, no radial/orb backgrounds, logo rules, reduced-motion markers, screenshot artifacts, and protected deploy/install guard.</check-9>
    <check-10>Phase-56 public/auth smoke and screenshots: compact public landing, logo auth lockups, canonical tariff preview, reduced-motion proof, and protected deploy/install guard.</check-10>
    <check-11>Phase-59 motion smoke: motion budget tokens, route transitions, feedback/status classes, reduced-motion fallback, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</check-11>
    <check-12 status="pass-local-phase67">Phase-67 auth/splash smoke: no visible auth card frame, large unframed logo, red focus border, icon-safe inputs, elegant buttons, side-by-side secondary actions, responsive safety, and reduced-motion fallback.</check-12>
    <check-13 status="pass-local-rainfix">Matrix rain CSS reliability smoke: fallback layer exists in user/admin VisualShell/CSS, canvas and fallback use mobile overscan, reduced-motion keeps a static visible fallback, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard remains clean.</check-13>
    <check-14 status="pass-local-phase74">Phase-74 style smoke asserted admin login icon padding, bounded admin rail, content-scroll CSS markers, and no scroll/pointer interception from Matrix layers.</check-14>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-53-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User cabinet routes use Matrix palette/tokens while preserving compact operational layout and avoiding nested cards.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>VPN config actions, QR/download/copy, MTProto secrets, countdown/calendar, tariff prices, referral links, and settings forms remain readable.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Focus states remain visible on buttons, links, inputs, segmented controls, copy actions, tariff CTAs, and navigation tabs.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Reduced-motion disables flicker-heavy/transform-heavy effects and keeps the Matrix identity as a static readable surface.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Palette review confirms cyan, magenta, amber, red, and neutral accents remain available and the UI is not a one-note green surface.</gate-5>
  </phase-53-style-gates>
  <phase-54-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Admin console routes use Matrix palette/tokens while preserving dense operational layout and avoiding nested card bloat.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Admin tables, forms, graph panels, MTProto IP history, alert controls, tariff rows, node/route forms, and status badges remain readable.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Focus states remain visible on login inputs, sidebar/mobile navigation, filters, pagination, confirmation buttons, alert buttons, and form controls.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Reduced-motion disables flicker-heavy/transform-heavy effects and keeps the admin shell readable as a static Matrix surface.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Palette review confirms cyan, magenta, amber, red, neutral, and green accents remain balanced so the admin UI is not a one-note green surface.</gate-5>
  </phase-54-style-gates>
  <phase-55-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User and admin CSS expose premium Matrix palette, type, density, shadow, focus, and logo tokens.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Decorative radial/orb shell backgrounds are removed while Matrix identity remains visible.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion fallback simplifies grid/scanline effects and preserves readability.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-55 screenshot artifacts cover phone, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion login shells.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Protected deploy/install/runtime surfaces remain untouched.</gate-5>
  </phase-55-style-gates>
  <phase-56-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Public/auth CSS primitives expose compact premium Matrix landing, tariff preview, logo, and auth lockup styles.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Public/auth screenshots cover phone, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion viewports without visible overlap or hidden CTA.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Protected deploy/install/runtime surfaces remain untouched.</gate-3>
  </phase-56-style-gates>
  <phase-59-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User and admin CSS expose short motion budget tokens and Matrix route/feedback/status motion classes.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Reduced-motion fallback disables Phase-59 transforms/animations while preserving the static Matrix identity.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>CSS smoke rejects scroll hijack, pointer interception, long motion budget, negative letter spacing, viewport font sizing, and protected backend/deploy/runtime diffs.</gate-3>
  </phase-59-style-gates>
  <phase-74-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Admin login icon-bearing inputs must reserve enough padding for icon, placeholder, and typed value across hover/focus/error states.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Admin rail CSS must expose bounded height/overflow markers and must not extend past the usable content height.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Admin content CSS must expose a normal vertical scroll surface so wheel/touch scrolling works over content, with Matrix background layers remaining pointer-safe.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Removing visible Tariffs navigation must not leave empty visual gaps, orphaned active states, or oversized route placeholders.</gate-4>
  </phase-74-style-gates>
  <phase-67-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Auth routes must not render the visible matrix-auth-card frame or framed logo lockup.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Auth input focus/active state must use the planned red treatment and must not regress to blue/cyan focus on /login, /register, /forgot-password, or /reset-password.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Input icons, placeholders, typed values, password controls, and button text must not overlap at Phase-67 phone, tablet, desktop, or reduced-motion viewports.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Primary/secondary auth buttons must remain compact, touch-safe, animated within the motion budget, and disabled/simplified under reduced-motion.</gate-4>
  </phase-67-style-gates>
  <rainfix-style-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User and admin CSS must expose .matrix-rain-fallback and matrixCssRainFallback.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>.matrix-canvas must use 100dvh+128px min-height and normal blend mode so browser-specific blend/viewport behavior cannot hide the rain.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion must leave a static fallback visible rather than removing the Matrix background entirely.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>CSS smoke must reject accidental removal of CSS_RAIN_FALLBACK_READY and MOBILE_OVERSCAN_READY markers.</gate-4>
  </rainfix-style-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Shared Matrix tokens apply to both frontends without breaking compact operational layout rules from M-038.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">CRT scanlines, neon flicker, and glitch accents are visible but do not obscure forms, tables, proxy cards, tariffs, alerts, or primary actions.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Focus states are visible over the Matrix background for links, buttons, inputs, tabs, menus, and confirmation controls.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Mobile shells have no document-level horizontal scroll, no nested card bloat, and stable compact control dimensions.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Long emails, CTA proxy hostnames, secrets, config labels, tariff prices, and admin row actions wrap or truncate intentionally inside stable containers.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Color scan confirms the final theme is not a one-note green surface: cyan, magenta, neutral, warning, and danger accents remain available.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <visual-checks>
    <viewport-1>360x740</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2>390x844</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3>430x932</viewport-3>
    <viewport-4>768x1024</viewport-4>
    <viewport-5>1440x900</viewport-5>
    <check-1>No horizontal scroll.</check-1>
    <check-2>No icon/placeholder overlap in forms.</check-2>
    <check-3>No status badge, button, table, chart, proxy secret, or tariff text overlap.</check-3>
    <check-4>Visible focus states remain clear over Matrix background and scanline overlays.</check-4>
    <check-5>Primary VPN, MTProto, tariff, registration, and admin actions are visible and readable.</check-5>
  </visual-checks>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][TOKENS_PRESENT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][REDUCED_MOTION_POLICY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][VIEWPORT_NO_OVERFLOW]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][FOCUS_VISIBLE]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][USER_ROUTES_READABLE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][NO_TEXT_OVERLAP]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][BALANCED_PALETTE]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase54][ADMIN_ROUTES_READABLE]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase54][NO_TEXT_OVERLAP]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase54][BALANCED_PALETTE]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase54][REDUCED_MOTION_ADMIN]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[PremiumArtDirection][phase55][TOKENS_READY]</marker-13>
    <marker-14>[PremiumArtDirection][phase55][BALANCED_PALETTE]</marker-14>
    <marker-15>[PremiumArtDirection][phase55][DENSITY_SAFE]</marker-15>
    <marker-16>[PremiumArtDirection][phase55][SCREENSHOT_MATRIX_REVIEWED]</marker-16>
    <marker-17>[PremiumPublicSite][phase56][AUTH_STATES_READABLE]</marker-17>
    <marker-18>[PremiumPublicSite][phase56][SCREENSHOT_MATRIX_REVIEWED]</marker-18>
    <marker-19>[MatrixMotion][phase59][MOTION_BUDGET_READY]</marker-19>
    <marker-20>[MatrixMotion][phase59][REDUCED_MOTION_PASS]</marker-20>
    <marker-21>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase67][FRAMELESS_AUTH_READY]</marker-21>
    <marker-22>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase67][RED_FOCUS_READY]</marker-22>
    <marker-23>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase67][AUTH_NO_OVERLAP]</marker-23>
    <marker-24>[MatrixVisualRuntime][fix][CSS_RAIN_FALLBACK_READY]</marker-24>
    <marker-25>[MatrixVisualRuntime][fix][MOBILE_OVERSCAN_READY]</marker-25>
    <marker-26>[MatrixStyle][phase74][ADMIN_LOGIN_ICON_NO_OVERLAP]</marker-26>
    <marker-27>[MatrixStyle][phase74][ADMIN_RAIL_BOUNDED]</marker-27>
    <marker-28>[MatrixStyle][phase74][ADMIN_SCROLL_SURFACE_SAFE]</marker-28>
  </required-log-markers>
  <evidence-levels>
    <module-local>Static smoke validates CSS tokens, class primitives, reduced-motion selectors, focus selectors, and protected-surface guard.</module-local>
    <wave-level>User and admin builds validate shared style integration in both apps.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Viewport screenshots validate readability, no overlap, no horizontal scroll, and balanced Matrix palette.</phase-level>
  </evidence-levels>
  <redaction>
    <rule-1>Visual smoke must not print real tokens, proxy secrets, tg links, VPN config contents, admin tokens, raw user IP history, or screenshot binary data.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Allowed output: route name, viewport, layout metrics, CSS selector presence, screenshot path, and redacted console marker counts.</rule-2>
  </redaction>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>medium</level>
    <allowed>Implement frontend-only CSS token system, shell classes, focus states, and smoke checks inside M-071 boundaries.</allowed>
    <blocked>Changing data contracts, auth/session storage, billing/VPN/MTProto behavior, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or backend runtime behavior.</blocked>
    <handoff-trigger>Stop and report if the theme makes operational content unreadable, creates horizontal scroll, hides primary actions, or conflicts with reduced-motion policy.</handoff-trigger>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <acceptance>
    <target-1>Frontend and frontend-admin builds pass.</target-1>
    <target-2>Phase-52 smoke passes with token, reduced-motion, viewport, focus, and protected-surface checks.</target-2>
    <target-3>Mobile and desktop screenshots show Matrix style without text overlap, control overlap, or one-note color dominance.</target-3>
    <target-4>No deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime topology changes are present.</target-4>
  </acceptance>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">
    <command-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <summary>Admin CSS exposes icon-safe input padding, bounded rail, content overflow-y scroll, and pointer-safe scroll markers without changing backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend surfaces.</summary>
  </phase-74-evidence>
  <evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-3>
      <command-4>Chrome headless screenshot audit for user/admin /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion 390x844.</command-4>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-reduced-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-reduced-390x844.png</screenshot-paths>
      <viewport-review>Login shells stayed readable, Matrix layer was visible, focus and reduced-motion selectors are present, and no obvious icon/text overlap was observed on captured login viewports.</viewport-review>
      <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology diff.</protected-surface>
    </local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>Chrome production-preview screenshots with virtual-time-budget for /login, /register, /reset-password, desktop /login, and reduced-motion /login.</command-3>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-mobile-v5.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/register-mobile-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/reset-mobile-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-desktop-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-mobile-reduced-motion.png</screenshot-paths>
      <viewport-review>Auth screenshots were readable after final animation frame, no visible input/icon overlap was observed, and Phase-53 static smoke covered protected dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings route surfaces that redirect without local auth session.</viewport-review>
      <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology diff.</protected-surface>
    </phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
      <result>DESIGNED</result>
      <summary>Phase-54 style gates require compact Matrix admin route surfaces, readable tables/charts/forms, focus-visible controls, reduced-motion proof, no horizontal overflow, no text/icon overlap, balanced palette, and protected-surface isolation.</summary>
    </phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
      <command-2>node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-2>
      <summary>Static style proof passed for compact Matrix admin primitives, login shell, route markers, bounded lists, chart frames, no oversized login hero/large radius/tracking drift, focus/reduced-motion markers, balanced palette markers, and protected-surface isolation.</summary>
      <follow-up>Authenticated screenshot review for protected admin routes remains clean-deploy follow-up.</follow-up>
    </phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-55-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs --expect-screenshots=/tmp/krotpn-phase55-screenshots</command-3>
      <summary>Premium art-direction smoke passed for user/admin shared tokens, no radial/orb backgrounds, compact density, logo rules, reduced-motion policy, screenshot artifact validation, and protected deploy/install guard.</summary>
    </phase-55-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-56-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>Chrome production-preview screenshots for public/auth routes at phone, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion viewports.</command-3>
      <summary>Public/auth style smoke passed for compact landing, visible logo, readable auth forms, canonical tariff preview, reduced-motion markers, and protected deploy/install guard.</summary>
    </phase-56-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</command-2>
      <command-3>node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</command-3>
      <summary>Phase-59 CSS smoke passed for motion budget, microinteraction/status/route classes, reduced-motion fallback, pointer/focus markers, no scroll hijack, and protected backend/deploy/runtime isolation.</summary>
    </phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-67-local-2026-06-04>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</command-3>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/splash-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/login-390x844-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/register-390x844-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/forgot-390x844-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/reset-390x844-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/login-1440x900-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase67-shots/login-reduced-390x844-final.png</screenshot-paths>
      <summary>Phase-67 CSS/auth polish passed for frameless auth surfaces, large unframed logo, red focus treatment, compact secondary actions, mobile wrapping, reduced-motion simplification, and protected backend/deploy/runtime isolation.</summary>
    </phase-67-local-2026-06-04>
    <rainfix-local-2026-06-04>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</command-3>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-rainfix-user-login-390.png /tmp/krotpn-rainfix-user-register-390.png /tmp/krotpn-rainfix-admin-login-390.png /tmp/krotpn-rainfix-user-login-1440.png</screenshot-paths>
      <summary>CSS fallback and overscan passed static and browser checks; user/admin mobile screenshots show Matrix rain behind content through the bottom edge without visible black cutoff.</summary>
    </rainfix-local-2026-06-04>
  </evidence>
  <phase-68-execution-evidence>2026-06-04: Phase-68 CSS and route smokes passed for frameless user-shell logo, compact dashboard subscription panel, responsive tariff grid, compact cross-month calendar, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</phase-68-execution-evidence>
  <phase-68-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Matrix style verification for compact dashboard/subscription refactor.</scope>
    <gate-1>Dashboard, MTProto, subscription, tariff, calendar, referral, and settings controls must keep compact Matrix styling without nested-card bloat.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Buttons must have visible hover/focus/active feedback, red-accent focus where auth style conventions apply, and reduced-motion fallback.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Calendar and tariff controls must not use hero-scale typography, viewport-scaled fonts, negative letter spacing, or oversized radius.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-68-verification-design>
  <phase-70-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>QR/config visual compactness verification.</scope>
    <gate-1>QR presentation may be visually simplified only by changing rendering options, never by changing config payload content.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Removed config diagnostic/raw blocks must not leave empty visual gaps, broken spacers, or hidden actionable content.</gate-2>
    <commands>node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-70-verification-design>
  <phase-70-evidence status="pass-local">2026-06-04: Phase-70 smoke passed; QR page compaction stayed inside Config.tsx route-local sizing/spacing, with no new global CSS bloat or deploy/runtime drift.</phase-70-evidence>
  <phase-71-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Matrix style verification for master-detail config UX and requested user-cabinet polish.</scope>
    <gate-1>Selected-device rows, detail panel, sticky mobile actions, icon-only close, and calendar boundary pulse must remain compact and readable.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>User-cabinet logo must not render a square green frame around the transparent PNG.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion must disable or soften flicker/pulse/transform effects while preserving visible state.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-71-verification-design>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Frontend build and Phase-71 smoke passed for Phase-71 CSS markers: master-detail rows, selected row state, sticky actions, icon-only QR close, frameless user logo, calendar boundary pulse, and reduced-motion fallback.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Matrix style verification for compact mobile bottom navigation, desktop calendar density, and Russian-only Settings cleanup.</scope>
    <gate-1>Bottom navigation must use compact Matrix styling, visible focus states, safe-area padding, and stable dimensions without nested-card bloat.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Desktop calendar density must shrink through spacing/grid/token changes without viewport-scaled fonts, negative letter spacing, or unreadable date cells.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Removing Settings language controls must not leave blank panels, broken spacing, or orphaned language selector styles visible in user routes.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-72-verification-design>
  <phase-72-required-markers status="observed-local">
    <marker-1>[MobileUserCabinet][phase72][BOTTOM_NAV_SAFE]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixStyle][phase72][CALENDAR_DENSITY_READY]</marker-2>
  </phase-72-required-markers>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-72 smoke, Phase-59 motion smoke, and Phase-61 responsive smoke passed for compact bottom dock styling, focus/active states, reduced-motion safety, and smaller desktop subscription calendar density.</phase-72-evidence>
  <phase-73-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Matrix style verification for compact config copy, Amnezia guidance, and selected-device controls.</scope>
    <gate-1>"KPN Конфигурация", AmneziaVPN .conf import guidance, AmneziaWG QR action, .conf download, Copy, and device-limit tariff copy must remain readable without icon/text/button overlap.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Removing the selected-device helper sentence must not leave empty layout gaps, hidden actions, or oversized explanatory panels.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion and bottom-dock safe-area rules from Phase-72 must still protect the config route and QR modal.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-73 must not introduce viewport-scaled fonts, negative letter spacing, nested cards, one-note palette drift, or decorative bloat.</gate-4>
    <commands>node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-73-verification-design>
  <phase-73-required-markers status="observed-local">
    <marker-1>[MatrixStyle][phase73][CONFIG_COPY_COMPACT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixStyle][phase73][QR_GUIDANCE_READABLE]</marker-2>
  </phase-73-required-markers>
  <phase-73-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">
    <command-1>node scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <summary>KPN copy, AmneziaVPN .conf guidance, selected-device AmneziaWG QR, and tariff-limit copy stay inside existing compact Matrix page/modal primitives with no new global CSS bloat.</summary>
  </phase-73-evidence>
  <phase-74-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Matrix style verification for admin login icon safety, admin shell scroll repair, and bounded rail geometry.</scope>
    <gate-1>Phase-74 must not introduce text/icon overlap, viewport-scaled fonts, negative letter spacing, nested cards, or one-note palette drift.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Rail/content scroll fixes must preserve reduced-motion policy and pointer-safe Matrix canvas/fallback layers.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Static CSS smoke is required before claiming browser-safe admin scroll behavior.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-74-verification-design>
</V-M-071>
