<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-055 MODULE="M-055" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase42" PHASE-43="verification-designed" VERSION="1.4.0">
  <module>mtproto-runtime-telemetry-bridge</module>
  <checks>Runtime emits and drains metadata-only telemetry through mtproto_proxy metrics, active-SNI sampling, and a private token-protected boundary without breaking MTProto traffic.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_runtime_telemetry_bridge.py</file>
    <file status="planned-phase43">backend/tests/test_mtproto_ip_observability.py</file>
    <file status="planned-phase43">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase42-mtproto-telemetry-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local">mtproto-runtime</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-05-19: node scripts/phase42-mtproto-telemetry-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_runtime_telemetry_bridge.py -v; cd mtproto-runtime &amp;&amp; rebar3 compile</commands>
  <evidence>Runtime telemetry snapshot/drain tests, live metric-backend/sampler static smoke, scheduler regression, and mtproto-runtime compile passed locally.</evidence>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Use fake runtime events and private API fixtures to verify token checks, snapshot, drain, cursoring, overflow counters, redaction, and degraded runtime behavior.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run with V-M-054 to prove drained events become idempotent usage rows and with V-M-056 to prove stale runtime state is visible in analytics.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Live release remains blocked until Phase-41 req_pq and Telegram Desktop/mobile proof standards pass after telemetry hooks are enabled.</phase-level>
    <phase-43-level>Runtime changes must prove trustworthy client IP source handling, source_ip_unavailable fallback, proxy CPU/RAM/uptime metrics, and unchanged Telegram proxy availability.</phase-43-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <phase-43-checks>
    <check-1>Client IP is emitted only when runtime can identify the real client endpoint, not RU/DE router internals.</check-1>
    <check-2>When client IP is unavailable or untrusted, telemetry carries source_ip_unavailable and no guessed address.</check-2>
    <check-3>Runtime resource metrics include proxy CPU percent, RAM bytes, uptime, dropped_events, and buffer status.</check-3>
    <check-4>Resource metric collection failure degrades admin health only and does not restart or block the MTProto listener.</check-4>
  </phase-43-checks>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Handshake, close, bytes, error, active_connection, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, and req_pq proof events use safe metadata fields only.</check-1>
    <check-2>Private telemetry endpoints reject missing or wrong runtime tokens and return no telemetry on unauthorized calls.</check-2>
    <check-3>Snapshot reads current counters without draining events.</check-3>
    <check-4>Drain returns cursor-ordered events and acknowledges only the returned batch.</check-4>
    <check-5>Bounded buffer overflow increments dropped_events and never blocks policy apply or MTProto listener behavior.</check-5>
    <check-6>Policy metadata maps known SNI to assignment_id and user_id while unknown SNI stays masked.</check-6>
    <check-7>Backend ingestion tolerates runtime outage and marks analytics stale or degraded only.</check-7>
    <check-8>mtproto_proxy metric_backend records bytes, protocol errors, protocol-ok, and connection counters into bounded sampler counters.</check-8>
    <check-9>Sampler records per-SNI active/handshake/close deltas from policy counters and avoids false per-user byte attribution when multiple domains are active.</check-9>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Handshake, close, bytes, error, active_connection, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, and req_pq proof events are represented with safe fields.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Missing or wrong runtime token returns unauthorized and no telemetry leaks.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Buffer overflow increments dropped_events but does not block policy apply or MTProto listener behavior.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Backend ingestion tolerates runtime outage and marks analytics stale/degraded only.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Telemetry hook changes do not alter the issued-link fake-TLS secret, SNI route, or Telegram client acceptance contract.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Concurrent-domain traffic remains global_runtime unless a deeper data-plane hook can provide exact per-SNI bytes.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7>Phase-43 client IP and resource metrics are emitted with safe source confidence and do not change issued-link fake-TLS behavior.</scenario-7>
  </scenarios>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Runtime telemetry must exclude full tg links, fake-TLS secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, private keys, and full promotion tags.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Runtime logs may include stable counters and masked SNI only.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Unauthorized telemetry responses must not reveal whether an assignment exists.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker>[M-055][runtime_telemetry][EMIT_EVENT]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][telemetry_snapshot][SNAPSHOT]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][telemetry_drain][DRAIN_EVENTS]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][telemetry_ingest][INGEST_SUMMARY]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][runtime_telemetry][DROP_OVERFLOW]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][runtime_resource_metrics][RESOURCE_SNAPSHOT]</marker>
    <marker>[M-055][runtime_telemetry][SOURCE_IP_UNAVAILABLE]</marker>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>Runtime smoke may use local synthetic fixtures and fake private tokens.</safe-local>
    <blocked-live>Changing live runtime telemetry hooks or restarting DE runtime requires operator approval and post-change req_pq proof.</blocked-live>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-055>
