<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-041 MODULE="M-041" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local" VERSION="1.2.0">
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-27>Foundation only: pending registration primitives, token hashing, TTL/replay protection, email risk checks, and compatibility evidence while active /register stays unchanged.</phase-27>
    <phase-28 status="planned-next">Cutover: /register must return pending verification state and must not create active KrotPN access before email ownership is proven.</phase-28>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file phase="27">backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py</file>
    <file phase="28">backend/tests/test_verified_registration.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Risk-check and pending-token tests run without live email provider, DNS mutability, VPN provisioning, or MTProto runtime.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Phase-27 must be verified together with M-040 email delivery fake-provider tests.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Existing active /register behavior is a protected compatibility boundary until Phase-28.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">Allowed email input normalizes consistently and creates a pending verification record without issuing JWT, trial, VPN, referral, or MTProto side effects.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Verification tokens are stored hashed or otherwise non-recoverable; plaintext tokens never persist.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Expired, replayed, malformed, duplicate, and blocked-domain paths are rejected safely.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Temporary/disposable and configured blocked domains are rejected before M-040 email sending is called.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Allowlist policy can override broad deny rules for operator-approved domains.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="compatibility">Phase-27 does not wire the new pending-registration flow into active /register yet.</check-6>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-28-cutover-gates>
    <gate-1>Unverified /register no longer creates active user access or JWT tokens.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Verified activation creates user, trial, VPN device, VPN client, referral effects, and later MTProto assignment exactly once.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verification token replay cannot duplicate trial, referral, VPN, or MTProto side effects.</gate-3>
  </phase-28-cutover-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">User submits allowed email to the pending registration service and receives safe check-email state.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="failure">Temporary email domain is blocked before verification email is sent.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Malformed, expired, replayed, and duplicate pending-registration tokens fail with safe reasons.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Pending registration path cannot emit JWT tokens or provision KrotPN resources in Phase-27.</scenario-4>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-041][request_registration][EMAIL_RISK_CHECK]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-041][request_registration][STORE_PENDING]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-041][email_risk_check][BLOCK_DOMAIN]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-041][verify_registration][CONSUME_TOKEN]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-041][verify_registration][TOKEN_REPLAYED]</marker-5>
    <marker-6 phase="28">[M-041][verify_registration][ACTIVATE_USER]</marker-6>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Mask email local parts in logs and never log verification tokens, token hashes, password values, or raw risk-provider payloads.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Failure reasons may be operator-readable but must not expose whether an unrelated account exists.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>safe-with-boundary</level>
    <reason>Phase-27 is safe for local execution if tests prove no /register cutover, no deploy/install edits, no live email provider calls, and no VPN/MTProto side effects.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-13: backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py passed locally, covering disposable-domain blocking before email send, allowlist override, env domain parsing, HMAC token storage, one-time consume, expiry, zero user side effects, and active /register compatibility boundary.</evidence-1>
  </evidence>
</V-M-041>
