<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-004 MODULE="M-004" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase45" VERSION="1.4.0" PHASE-69="verification-designed">
  <module>billing</module>
  <checks>Payment and webhook flows remain isolated from registration cutover, complimentary internal access stays outside payment-provider logic, and Phase-28 trial creation is delayed until verified email activation.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_verified_registration.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_trial_activation.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_security.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_manual_access_policy.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_plan_api.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_billing_security.py tests/test_manual_access_policy.py tests/test_billing_plan_api.py -v</commands>
  <anchors>BILLING_WEBHOOK_ACCEPTED BILLING_SUBSCRIPTION_UPDATED TRIAL_CREATED TRIAL_SKIPPED_EXISTING_HISTORY</anchors>
  <phase-28-trial-gates>
    <gate-1>Pending email registration cannot create trial subscription, payment, or billing history rows.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Verified activation creates exactly one trial only when no previous trial or active subscription history blocks eligibility.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verify token replay and duplicate activation retries cannot create a second trial.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Existing YooKassa webhook, payment confirmation, and plan admin behavior remains green.</gate-4>
  </phase-28-trial-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success" trace="TRIAL_CREATED">Eligible verified user receives one trial after activation.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success" trace="TRIAL_SKIPPED_EXISTING_HISTORY">Ineligible verified user does not receive a duplicate trial.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success" trace="BILLING_WEBHOOK_ACCEPTED">YooKassa webhook accepted with valid signature.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success" trace="BILLING_SUBSCRIPTION_UPDATED">Subscription state updated after payment confirmation.</scenario-4>
  </scenarios>
  <refresh-findings>
    <finding-1 severity="historical" date="2026-05-14">Full V-M-004 command failed locally with 404 responses in billing webhook and billing plan API route tests because those tests still used stale /api paths.</finding-1>
    <finding-2 severity="resolved" date="2026-05-19">The 404 failures were stale test route expectations using /api instead of the canonical /api/v1 billing prefixes. Router-level webhook and plan API tests were aligned and the full V-M-004 command now passes locally.</finding-2>
  </refresh-findings>
  <evidence>2026-05-13: Phase-28 backend suite passed locally and proved pending registration creates no trial while verified activation creates one eligible trial once. 2026-05-19: Full V-M-004 command passed locally after aligning billing route tests with /api/v1 prefixes. 2026-06-01: Phase-45 backend suite passed and proves verified activation creates a pending four-day trial, first VPN handshake starts it once, countdown fields are server-derived, and paid subscriptions are not overwritten.</evidence>
  <phase-69-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Billing webhook and subscription service verification for referral reward activation.</scope>
    <gate-1>Confirmed payment must call the referral reward path only after payment state is trusted.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Payment retries, duplicate notifications, and manual reprocessing must remain idempotent.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Referral bonus extension must not alter canonical tariff prices, paid subscription duration, or device limits.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Pending referral entitlement must integrate with first-VPN-connection activation without starting from registration time.</gate-4>
    <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; pytest tests/test_billing_service.py tests/test_trial_activation.py tests/test_referrals.py tests/test_billing_plan_api.py</commands>
  </phase-69-verification-design>
</V-M-004>
