<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-049 MODULE="M-049" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-live-phase41" VERSION="1.5.1">
  <module>mtproto-live-edge-runtime</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-37 status="superseded-by-phase-38">Live MTProto edge runtime fix for clean-VPS Telegram proxy unavailability; local verification passed, but RU mtproto_proxy downstream handshakes were superseded by the DE-backed runtime path.</phase-37>
    <phase-38 status="superseded-by-M-050">Phase-38 keeps reusable runtime and policy bridge artifacts but replaces RU-only live traffic ownership with a DE-backed runtime behind an RU SNI router.</phase-38>
    <phase-41 status="pass-live">Phase-41 reuses M-049 as the production KPprotoN fake-TLS data-plane on DE, updates the locked upstream proxy, enforces a non-empty ad tag, and has operator Telegram Desktop/mobile proof.</phase-41>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_api.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_policy_handler.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_core_api.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_web.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/apps/kpproton_proxy/src/mtproto/kpproton_proxy_bridge.erl</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/rebar.lock</file>
    <file>deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file phase="41-pass-local">scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1>cd mtproto-runtime &amp;&amp; rebar3 compile</command-1>
    <command-2>rm -rf /tmp/krotpn-mtproto-runtime-check &amp;&amp; rsync -a --exclude='_build' --exclude='rebar3.crashdump' mtproto-runtime/ /tmp/krotpn-mtproto-runtime-check/ &amp;&amp; cd /tmp/krotpn-mtproto-runtime-check &amp;&amp; rebar3 as prod release</command-2>
    <command-3>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_mtproto_api.py -v</command-3>
    <command-4>bash -n deploy/deploy-on-server.sh install.sh</command-4>
    <command-5>node scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase34-mtproto-stabilization-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</command-5>
    <command-6>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-37.xml docs/modules/M-049.xml docs/verification/V-M-049.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-6>
    <command-7 status="pass-live">operator-live: RU/DE edge health, port ownership, HTTPS fallback, existing active SNI replay, and Telegram Desktop/mobile available status passed after clean deploy.</command-7>
    <command-8 status="pass-live">live: mtp_ping req_pq probe passed against one issued fake-TLS link on DC +1 through +5 after DE runtime rebuild and non-empty PROXY_AD_TAG wiring.</command-8>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Erlang compile/release, backend HTTP adapter pytest, provisioning live-apply pytest, static runtime smoke, bash syntax, compose config, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint.</module-local>
    <wave-level>M-044, M-046, and M-048 checks must pass together because runtime policy, port ownership, and deploy env are a single production behavior.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>RU/DE smoke proves the SNI router and DE mtproto-edge route are healthy, issued SNI is loaded into live policy, issued-link mtp_ping passes, and Telegram client proof is operator-confirmed.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">mtproto-runtime builds and exposes token-protected apply, revoke, and health routes.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">docker-compose defines mtproto-edge in host network mode with PROXY_PORT=443, cert mounts, policy token, and domain-fronting fallback.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">RU nginx no longer binds public 443 and instead serves the HTTPS fallback on private 9443 while admin remains public 8443.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">deploy writes MTPROTO_RUNTIME_POLICY_URL, MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN, MTPROTO_POLICY_PORT, EDGE_SHARED_443_ENABLED, and EDGE_HTTPS_FALLBACK_PORT.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">backend HTTP adapter posts apply/revoke and gets health with the token header while redacting token and proxy secrets.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="deterministic">provisioning applies the SNI to runtime before returning an active user payload.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="deterministic">Telegram core bootstrap fetches are bounded and static fallback artifacts are returned when core.telegram.org is slow, blocked, yields no downstreams, or yields a filtered config missing common Telegram DC pools.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="deterministic">Deploy persists Telegram MTProto upstream routes through awg-client for 149.154.160.0/20, 91.108.4.0/22, 91.108.56.0/22, and 91.105.192.0/23.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="operator-live">RU server has mtproto-edge healthy, TCP 443 owned by the edge, TCP 8443 owned by nginx fallback, and policy_count includes issued active SNI after replay.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="operator-live" status="passed">Telegram Desktop/mobile mark the issued proxy available from the existing user dashboard link.</check-10>
    <check-11 evidence="phase-38-design">Phase-38 must not delete Phase-37 runtime artifacts; it reuses policy API and runtime code while moving production traffic to DE.</check-11>
    <check-12 evidence="phase-41-deterministic">DE KPprotoN runtime accepts per-SNI fake-TLS policy and does not require official MTProxy secret manifests for user issuance.</check-12>
    <check-13 evidence="deterministic">mtproto_proxy is locked to commit 154a8fb8e6ef85460f502d4b74434a22a5836937 with modern fake-TLS ping/backpressure fixes needed for live req_pq diagnostics.</check-13>
    <check-14 evidence="operator-live" status="passed">DE KPprotoN runtime uses non-empty PROXY_AD_TAG; zero tag is accepted and live mtp_ping proves Telegram proxy_req responses are returned.</check-14>
    <check-15 evidence="deterministic">Runtime entrypoint waits for POLICY_LISTEN_IP before release boot, and policy apply replaces an existing SNI before adding it again.</check-15>
    <check-16 evidence="deterministic">Runtime fallback proxy config includes DC +/-1, +/-2, +/-3, +/-4, +/-5, and +/-203 so mtproto_proxy cannot remain nominally healthy while real clients fail with no_pool for a common Telegram DC.</check-16>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Fresh deploy starts mtproto-edge with wildcard TLS and no public 443 conflict.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Existing active assignment SNI is applied to the live policy table without changing its secret or link.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">MTProto bootstrap returns local fallback secret/config when Telegram core is unavailable or filtered bootstrap is incomplete, allowing mtproto_proxy to bind 443 with common DC pools.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Normal https://krotpn.xyz traffic is forwarded to nginx fallback and still reaches frontend, API, and admin surfaces.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Missing runtime token, unreachable policy API, invalid SNI, or policy API auth failure returns degraded state and never claims an active usable proxy.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Port bind conflict or broken fallback requires rollback to previous nginx-only edge before user traffic is advertised.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="success">Phase-38 reuses runtime policy semantics but no longer requires RU mtproto_proxy downstream handshakes for production Telegram availability.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="success">Phase-41 DE runtime applies a new issued SNI without restarting the data-plane process.</scenario-8>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-049][kpproton_policy_handler][AUTH]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-049][kpproton_policy_handler][APPLY_POLICY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-049][kpproton_policy_handler][REVOKE_POLICY]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-049][kpproton_policy_handler][HEALTH]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-PROXY-BRIDGE][bootstrap][STATIC_SECRET_FALLBACK]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-PROXY-BRIDGE][bootstrap][STATIC_CONFIG_FALLBACK]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][POST_APPLY]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-043][get_or_create_assignment_payload][APPLY_RUNTIME_POLICY]</marker-8>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never print MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, derived fake-TLS secrets, full tg://proxy links, private keys, JWTs, refresh tokens, Resend API keys, or email verification tokens.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Live evidence may include service names, port ownership roles, status codes, aggregate policy_count, and redacted SNI suffix only.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <live-smoke-gates>
    <gate-1>docker ps shows mtproto-edge and backend healthy.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>RU ss output shows public TCP 443 owned by the SNI router and nginx HTTPS fallback on 9443; DE ss output shows mtproto-edge/beam owns TCP 443.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Local/private policy health succeeds only with MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>MTProto bootstrap secret/config endpoints respond within the configured proxy startup timeout.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Existing active assignment SNI apply returns success through the local policy API or scheduler replay.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>curl https://krotpn.xyz returns a healthy frontend response without TLS bypass.</gate-6>
    <gate-7 status="passed">Operator Telegram Desktop/mobile retest marks the proxy available and usable.</gate-7>
    <gate-8>Phase-38 handoff verifies M-050 owns the replacement live gates before M-049 is considered superseded in production.</gate-8>
    <gate-9>Phase-41 handoff verifies M-049 owns the KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime after official MTProxy is disabled from production.</gate-9>
  </live-smoke-gates>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>local-plus-authorized-live-hotfix</level>
    <safe-local>Compile, release, pytest, bash syntax, static smoke, compose config, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Future production RU/DE restarts, public 443 ownership changes, and Telegram Desktop/mobile availability proof for release-impacting changes.</requires-operator>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-18: Local diagnosis confirmed issued assignment existed but no live MTProto runtime process owned public 443.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-18: Live RU first run showed policy health but no TCP 443 bind because core bootstrap timed out; bounded fallback bootstrap is now in scope.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Telegram upstream routes through awg-client restored TCP reachability, but mtproto_proxy downstream handshakes still closed; nginx public 443 rollback preserved web availability.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Phase-38 verification moves live availability proof to V-M-050 while preserving Phase-37 artifacts as reusable runtime components.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution keeps mtproto-runtime buildable and policy-handler tests intact while default compose no longer starts RU mtproto-edge as the public 443 owner.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design restores M-049 as the DE KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime and requires comparison against CodexKPprotoN_for_KPN behavior.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local execution passed rebar3 compile and static smoke proving the active production path uses KPprotoN runtime/policy semantics, with live Telegram proof still operator-required.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Live diagnosis showed assignment policy, public RU route, fake-TLS accept, and Telegram downstream nonce probe passed, but issued-link req_pq timed out on the old e343e30 mtproto_proxy lock. The fix updates the dependency lock to 154a8fb for rebuild and live retest.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Live diagnosis after the upstream lock update proved the remaining blocker was blank PROXY_AD_TAG. With zero 32-hex tag, scheduler replay applied assignment_id=1 and mtp_ping for the issued fake-TLS link returned OK on DC +1 through +5.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy validation confirmed VPN and Telegram Desktop/mobile MTProto proxy work from the Phase-41 issued link.</evidence-10>
    <evidence-11>2026-05-23: Local smoke and static pytest cover POLICY_LISTEN_IP wait and idempotent SNI replace-before-add after live reboot diagnosis.</evidence-11>
    <evidence-12>2026-05-23: Live promo-tag/reboot diagnosis found no_pool,2 in DE runtime logs; kpproton_core_api now requires complete common Telegram DC pools and uses an expanded static fallback plus a 1000ms downstream probe timeout. The current DE runtime was rebuilt and redacted Phase-39 live smoke passed fake-TLS accept with Telegram downstream proxy_for_count=24.</evidence-12>
    <evidence-13>2026-05-24: Operator clean-deployed the release candidate from GitHub, rebooted both RU/DE hosts, and confirmed issued KPprotoN fake-TLS proxies recovered and worked after the normal startup delay. Complete Telegram downstream fallback is accepted as the stable production runtime path.</evidence-13>
  </evidence>
</V-M-049>
