<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-054 MODULE="M-054" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="verification-designed" VERSION="1.1.0">
  <module>mtproto-usage-telemetry</module>
  <checks>Usage event, session, rollup, last-seen, and abuse-signal persistence is idempotent, bounded, restore-safe, and secret-free.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file planned="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>planned-local: cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Exercise Alembic migration metadata, repository idempotency, last-seen updates, session state transitions, rollup writes, and retention pruning with synthetic telemetry fixtures.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run with V-M-055 and V-M-056 so runtime ingestion writes M-054 rows and analytics can consume them without schema drift.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-42 cannot pass unless M-054 proves day, week, month, top-user, last-seen, traffic, error, and active-session evidence without storing raw secrets or full proxy links.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Migration creates event, session, rollup, last-seen, and abuse-signal storage with indexes needed by admin filters.</check-1>
    <check-2>runtime_event_id uniqueness makes batch ingestion idempotent and prevents duplicate traffic/session counts.</check-2>
    <check-3>Known assignment handshake updates last_seen and opens or refreshes an active session without storing SNI secrets.</check-3>
    <check-4>Close and error events end sessions, preserve duration, and increment safe error counters.</check-4>
    <check-5>Unknown and rejected SNI events store safe reason codes, masked SNI values, and no derived proxy secrets.</check-5>
    <check-6>Client address analytics use HMAC/hash or coarse prefix fields by default, not raw public IP values.</check-6>
    <check-7>Hourly, daily, weekly, and monthly rollups preserve byte counters, connection count, duration, and errors.</check-7>
    <check-8>Raw event retention is bounded while rollups remain available for admin reporting and future restore checks.</check-8>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Known assignment handshake updates last_seen and creates or updates a session without storing secrets.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Unknown and rejected SNI events are stored with safe reason codes and masked identifiers.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Hourly, daily, weekly, and monthly rollups preserve traffic, connection count, duration, and error counters.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Duplicate runtime event ids do not double-count usage.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Retention pruning deletes old raw events but leaves aggregate rollups intact.</scenario-5>
  </scenarios>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <field-runtime-event-id>Stable opaque id from runtime for idempotency.</field-runtime-event-id>
    <field-assignment-id>Known assignment id when SNI maps to an issued proxy.</field-assignment-id>
    <field-user-id>Safe internal user id when assignment is known.</field-user-id>
    <field-event-type>handshake, close, bytes, error, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, active_connection, or req_pq_proof.</field-event-type>
    <field-counters>bytes_in, bytes_out, duration_ms, connection_count, error_code, and observed_at.</field-counters>
    <field-client-identity>ip_hash or ip_prefix only; raw public IP is excluded by default.</field-client-identity>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>No full tg links, fake-TLS secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, private keys, or full promotion tags.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Unknown SNI values must be masked before persistence and before logs.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Any fixture containing secret-like values must assert that repository outputs and logs redact them.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker>[M-054][ingest_telemetry_batch][WRITE_EVENTS]</marker>
    <marker>[M-054][ingest_telemetry_batch][IDEMPOTENT_SKIP]</marker>
    <marker>[M-054][update_last_seen][LAST_SEEN]</marker>
    <marker>[M-054][rollup_usage][ROLLUP_WINDOW]</marker>
    <marker>[M-054][apply_retention][RETENTION_PRUNE]</marker>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>Local migrations and repository tests may run against disposable test databases.</safe-local>
    <blocked-live>Live retention pruning or schema migration requires explicit operator-approved backup and maintenance window.</blocked-live>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-054>
