<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-043 MODULE="M-043" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="verification-designed-phase41" VERSION="1.7.0">
  <module>mtproto-provisioning</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-29 status="pass-local">Deterministic MTProto provisioning core implemented and verified locally.</phase-29>
    <phase-34 status="planned">Stabilization gate must prove verified users can receive one free indefinite owner proxy while unverified users and stale rotation states remain safe.</phase-34>
    <phase-38 status="verification-designed">Existing SNI, base secret, salt, and tg link stability must survive the runtime target move from RU-only to DE-backed edge.</phase-38>
    <phase-41 status="verification-designed">Provisioning must return KPprotoN fake-TLS ee owner payloads and explicitly reissue official dd credential-mode assignments.</phase-41>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py -v</commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Pure deterministic SNI, secret derivation, tg://proxy assembly, validation, and idempotency tests use fixed vectors and fake repository/session adapters.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Runs with V-M-042 so issue/reissue persists only restore-safe assignment data and can rebuild owner-safe payloads.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-29 cannot pass if unverified users can get a proxy, raw secrets are logged, or fake-TLS vectors are only shape-tested without golden assertions.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">SNI generation is stable and wildcard-safe for krotpn.xyz.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Derived fake-TLS credential differs from raw base secret and matches golden vectors.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Repeated issuance is idempotent and returns the same canonical assignment.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="failure-path">Missing, blank, malformed, or rotated base secret/salt returns explicit reissue-required or config-error states without partial persistence or backend startup crash.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="security">The generated tg://proxy payload is returned only to the owner-safe service response and is not persisted or logged raw.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="cross-module">Pending email registration and unverified users cannot trigger MTProto assignment issuance.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="phase-34-integration">Verified-email activation plus owner dashboard access produces one idempotent MTProto assignment and owner-only tg://proxy response.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="phase-38-deterministic">Changing runtime policy target to DE does not change SNI generation, fake-TLS derivation, proxy port, or owner tg://proxy payload for existing assignments.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="phase-41-deterministic">New owner payloads use server=u-*.krotpn.xyz and secret=ee...; official dd payloads are not treated as active production links.</check-9>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-34-stabilization-gates>
    <gate-1>Free MTProto assignment is indefinite by KrotPN subscription/trial lifetime and does not expire with the three-day KrotPN VPN trial.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Base secret and salt remain test-only in automated gates; production secrets are never required or printed during Phase-34 local verification.</gate-2>
  </phase-34-stabilization-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Verified user receives a personal tg://proxy link with derived per-SNI credential.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Reopening the account dashboard rebuilds the same owner-safe payload from assignment state.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Explicit reissue after rotation creates a new assignment state or rotation marker according to M-042 policy.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Missing or blank base secret, missing or blank salt, or invalid secret format blocks issuance safely.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Unsafe SNI characters, wrong domain, duplicate SNI collision, or invalid port fail deterministically.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Unverified, inactive, or missing users do not receive assignment rows or tg://proxy payloads.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="success">Existing assignment payload is rebuilt unchanged while the runtime bridge applies policy to the DE edge.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="success">Phase-41 reissue converts a superseded official assignment into a KPprotoN fake-TLS owner payload without leaking raw secrets.</scenario-8>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][GENERATE_SNI]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][DERIVE_SECRET]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][PERSIST_ASSIGNMENT]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][REUSE_ASSIGNMENT]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-043][derive_fake_tls_secret][GOLDEN_VECTOR]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][REISSUE_REQUIRED]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-043][issue_user_proxy][REJECT_UNVERIFIED_USER]</marker-7>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never log full tg://proxy links, derived secret, base secret, or salt.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Logs may include user id, assignment id, masked SNI, credential mode, and rotation marker only.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>safe-local-deterministic-only</level>
    <reason>Phase-29 M-043 can be executed autonomously with fake repository adapters and local DB tests; no live Telegram connectivity, DNS mutation, runtime edge changes, or deploy/install edits are allowed.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: V-M-043 target tests passed locally inside the combined Phase-29 pytest run.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: Blank MTProto env values regression test added after clean VPS deploy exposed backend startup failure from empty secrets.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Phase-38 verification requires no user proxy link reissue when moving policy apply to the DE-backed runtime.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design restores fake-TLS ee payload assertions and supersedes official dd payloads for production.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
</V-M-043>
