<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-066 MODULE="M-066" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="verification-designed">
  <purpose>Verify Phase-48 .conf download MIME hardening across backend headers, frontend Blob creation, and protected operational surfaces.</purpose>
  <checks>application/octet-stream attachment response, filename and filename-star .conf metadata, nosniff, no-store/private cache control, byte-preserved config body, frontend Blob MIME alignment, auth preservation, and no deploy/install changes.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/app/vpn/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>scripts/phase48-config-download-mime-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command status="verification-designed">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py -v</command>
    <command status="verification-designed">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="verification-designed">node scripts/phase48-config-download-mime-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="verification-designed">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-48.xml docs/modules/M-066.xml docs/verification/V-M-066.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
    <command status="verification-designed">mygrace lint</command>
  </commands>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>/api/v1/vpn/config/download returns Content-Type application/octet-stream and never text/plain for attachment downloads.</check-1>
    <check-2>Content-Disposition contains attachment, filename=&quot;*.conf&quot;, and filename*=UTF-8''*.conf with no .txt suffix.</check-2>
    <check-3>X-Content-Type-Options is nosniff and Cache-Control is private/no-store so browsers do not reinterpret the payload as text.</check-3>
    <check-4>Config body remains equivalent to the generated WireGuard/Amnezia config text after UTF-8 encoding.</check-4>
    <check-5>Frontend download Blob creation uses application/octet-stream and the download attribute ends in .conf for all config download branches.</check-5>
    <check-6>Pending-trial first config access, QR display, raw config copy, and device provisioning API compatibility remain intact.</check-6>
    <check-7>Smoke fails if Phase-48 changes install.sh, deploy scripts, nginx, docker-compose, TLS material, or VPN profile generation logic.</check-7>
    <check-8>Filename sanitation rejects path separators, duplicate .conf/.txt suffixes, control characters, non-ASCII surprises, and empty names before headers are built.</check-8>
    <check-9>Backend and frontend tests never print private keys, full config bodies, Authorization headers, tokens, or generated QR payloads.</check-9>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Backend tests cover headers, filename sanitation, auth preservation, body byte preservation, pending-trial first-config access, and no regression in JSON/QR/raw config routes.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Frontend build and static smoke cover Blob MIME, download attribute names, object URL cleanup, no .conf.txt fallback, and unchanged user-facing config workflow.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose diff guard prove documentation consistency and operational isolation.</phase-level>
    <live-optional>Manual Android Chrome/iOS Safari download proof is useful after prerelease deploy, but local execution can pass with deterministic HTTP/header and frontend static evidence.</live-optional>
  </verification-levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Android Chrome downloads krotpn-user.conf from the backend endpoint and does not receive text/plain metadata that would invite .txt renaming.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">A frontend-managed device config download creates an octet-stream Blob and suggests krotpn-device.conf.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">A verified pending-trial user can still retrieve the first VPN config, with only attachment metadata changed.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">QR, copy-to-clipboard, raw config display, and JSON config retrieval stay text-friendly while only the attachment download response is octet-stream.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Any response header, filename helper, or frontend branch emits .conf.txt, text/plain, unsafe path separators, duplicate suffixes, or missing nosniff.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Any Phase-48 diff touches deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/TLS files or changes generated config content.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Runtime telemetry is not required for Phase-48 because the change is deterministic HTTP metadata and frontend Blob construction, not VPN tunnel behavior.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Backend logs may include secret-free filename policy decisions, route name, response MIME, and safe failure code; they must not include config body, private key, preshared key, Authorization header, access/refresh token, or QR payload.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>Smoke output must be aggregate marker-only evidence and must not print generated configs, object URLs containing secrets, or live user identifiers.</requirement-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <required-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-066][build_config_download_response][DOWNLOAD_HEADERS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-066][sanitize_config_download_filename][FILENAME_SAFE]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-066][download_vpn_config][ATTACHMENT_RESPONSE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-066][phase48_config_download_mime][STATIC_GUARD]</marker-4>
  </required-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Do not log raw private keys, full config bodies, access tokens, refresh tokens, email tokens, MTProto secrets, or deployment secrets in tests or smoke output.</rule-1>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Allowed after plan and verification approval because Phase-48 is restricted to response metadata, frontend Blob type, tests, and static smoke while deployment and VPN profile generation remain out of scope.</autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-066>
