<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-058 MODULE="M-058" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase43" PHASE-43="pass-local" VERSION="1.5.0">
  <module>mtproto-admin-analytics-ui</module>
  <checks>Frontend-admin exposes compact MTProto analytics and promotion tag controls without secret leakage, hidden existing controls, or mobile layout regressions.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-05-21: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build; cd .. &amp;&amp; node scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</commands>
  <evidence>Frontend-admin build passed and Phase-42/Phase-43 static smokes confirm compact Overview/Users/Abuse/Settings UI, removed Recent events, paginated proxy/user lists, compact area graphs, source-IP unavailable state, auto-refresh markers, alert review actions, open inbox/archive split, no-dot empty states, and redaction guards.</evidence>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Build frontend-admin and run static UI smoke for route wiring, API names, redaction strings, confirmation flows, and mobile viewport overflow.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run after V-M-057 to prove UI contracts match backend schemas for analytics and promotion tag state.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-42 cannot close unless admin can scan global and per-proxy analytics from mobile without exposing secrets or losing existing MTProto ops controls.</phase-level>
    <phase-43-level>Phase-43 cannot execute unless UI gates cover removed Recent events, Overview/Users/Abuse/Settings layout, long Top users, graphs, auto-refresh, raw-IP investigation scope, and mobile compactness.</phase-43-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <phase-43-checks>
    <check-1>Recent events section is absent from the visible admin MTProto analytics page.</check-1>
    <check-2>Overview, Users, Abuse, and Settings surfaces fit mobile widths without nested cards or horizontal overflow.</check-2>
    <check-3>Top users supports 25, 50, and 100 item views with scrollable compact rows.</check-3>
    <check-4>User detail drawer shows issued_at, last_seen_at, current IP, last IP, all IPs for 90 days, sessions, traffic, duration, and errors.</check-4>
    <check-5>Graphs render traffic, connections, active connections, duration, and errors without layout shift during auto-refresh.</check-5>
    <check-6>CPU/RAM/runtime metric tiles auto-refresh and show stale/unavailable states clearly.</check-6>
    <check-7>Raw IP strings render only inside the admin investigation drawer and are excluded from static smoke fixtures, summaries, and logs.</check-7>
    <check-8>Assignment inventory and user investigation search expose bounded page sizes with next/previous controls for large proxy sets.</check-8>
    <check-9>Abuse open inbox queries only open alerts and archive surfaces acknowledged/resolved alert history.</check-9>
    <check-10>Abuse empty states are padded for readability and do not end with stray punctuation.</check-10>
  </phase-43-checks>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Admin can scan global summary, traffic windows, top users, active connections, errors, runtime health, and availability proof on mobile.</check-1>
    <check-2>Per-proxy detail exposes last seen, session count, duration, traffic, errors, and abuse signals without hiding reissue/revoke controls.</check-2>
    <check-3>Filters for day, week, month, event type, status, and assignment do not cause horizontal overflow at 360px width.</check-3>
    <check-4>Abuse signals are clearly labeled observe-only.</check-4>
    <check-5>Promotion tag editing requires explicit confirmation and renders only masked current tag after save.</check-5>
    <check-6>Static smoke confirms no full tg links, fake-TLS secrets, runtime tokens, raw promotion tags, or raw IP values render in the UI bundle.</check-6>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Admin can scan global summary, traffic windows, top users, active connections, and error counts on mobile.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Per-proxy detail is reachable without hiding reissue/revoke controls.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Abuse signals are clearly labeled observe-only.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Static smoke confirms no full tg links, secrets, tokens, raw promotion tags, or raw IP values render in the UI.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Promotion tag form handles valid, invalid, pending_restart, applied, and failed states.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Phase-43 admin opens a high-abuse alert, reviews user/IP/session detail, and disables the selected proxy through confirmation UI.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7>Auto-refresh updates summary, alerts, top users, graph data, and resource metrics without duplicating requests or resizing controls.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8>Admin acknowledges, resolves, disables, or blocks from an alert; the alert leaves the open list and remains reviewable in the archive.</scenario-8>
  </scenarios>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>UI renders masked SNI and masked promotion tags only.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Full proxy links remain limited to user-owned cabinet flows, not admin analytics lists.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Raw IP values may appear only in explicit admin investigation drawer fixtures; runtime token, full tag, base secret, salt, private keys, and proxy secrets may never appear in generated bundles or page render fixtures.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][REDACTED_RENDER]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][FILTER_USAGE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][PROMOTION_TAG_CONFIRM]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][RECENT_EVENTS_REMOVED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][USER_DETAIL_DRAWER]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][AUTO_REFRESH]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][ALERT_REVIEW]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][ALERT_ARCHIVE]</marker>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>Frontend build and static smoke are safe to run locally.</safe-local>
    <blocked-live>Visual/live admin validation against production data requires operator approval and redacted screenshots only.</blocked-live>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-058>
