<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-078 MODULE="M-078" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase60-planned-phase65" PHASE-60="pass-local" PHASE-65="planned">
  <scope>Phase-60 verification for premium frontend QA gates across public, auth, protected user, protected admin, Matrix runtime, motion, responsive, performance, accessibility, MyGRACE, and protected-surface boundaries. Phase-65 release-candidate gate remains planned and consumes this evidence later.</scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="65-planned">scripts/phase65-premium-rc-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>frontend/src/App.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Login.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/VerifyEmail.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/main.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-078.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-60.xml</file>
    <file>docs/verification/V-M-078.xml</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 status="passed-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2 status="passed-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-2>
    <check-3 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-4>
    <check-5 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</check-5>
    <check-6 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</check-6>
    <check-7 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</check-7>
    <check-8 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-8>
    <check-9 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</check-9>
    <check-10 status="static-route-proof">Public/auth route matrix covered by Phase-60 static-route proof: /, /login, /register, /forgot-password, /reset-password, /verify-email across the 360/390/430/768/1024/1440 viewport contract plus reduced-motion routes.</check-10>
    <check-11 status="static-route-proof">Protected user route matrix covered by Phase-60 static-route proof: /dashboard, /dashboard/config, /dashboard/subscription, /dashboard/referrals, /dashboard/settings. Authenticated clean-deploy screenshots remain follow-up evidence.</check-11>
    <check-12 status="static-route-proof">Admin route matrix covered by Phase-60 static-route proof: /login, /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, /analytics. Authenticated clean-deploy screenshots remain follow-up evidence.</check-12>
    <check-13 status="passed-local">Layout assertions passed: no document-level horizontal scroll markers, no visible icon/text/control/status overlap markers, bounded table/list/graph classes, stable fixed-format controls, and no pointer interception by Matrix/canvas/overlay layers.</check-13>
    <check-14 status="passed-local">Performance budgets passed: user JS 448516 bytes gzip 135543, user CSS 40900 bytes gzip 8207, admin JS 780555 bytes gzip 219372, admin CSS 36787 bytes gzip 8148; no unexpected dist asset exceeded Phase-60 limits.</check-14>
    <check-15 status="explicit-fallback">Lighthouse/Web Vitals local preview run was not executed; Phase-60 smoke emitted [PremiumQAGates][phase60][LIGHTHOUSE_UNAVAILABLE] no-local-preview-lighthouse-run and enforced bundle/static budgets instead.</check-15>
    <check-16 status="passed-local">Motion/runtime budget passed: Phase-59 motion tokens stay &lt;= 220 ms for route/feedback transitions, no scroll hijacking, no setInterval-driven decorative loops, Matrix canvas pointer-events-none, reduced-motion fallback, and inactive-tab markers remain present.</check-16>
    <check-17 status="passed-local">Accessibility gates passed by static markers: focus-visible selectors, keyboard focus markers, reduced-motion media emulation, readable button/status/input tokens, no keyboard trap patterns, and no visible instruction-text markers.</check-17>
    <check-18 status="passed-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/modules/M-078.xml docs/plans/Phase-60.xml docs/verification/V-M-078.xml</check-18>
    <check-19 status="passed-local">mygrace lint</check-19>
    <check-20 status="passed-local">git diff --check</check-20>
    <check-21 status="passed-local">git diff --name-only HEAD -- install.sh docker-compose.yml nginx deploy deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml .env.example backend/app backend/tests mtproto-runtime official-mtproxy telegram-bot is empty</check-21>
  </module-checks>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend and frontend-admin production builds passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs passed with all required PremiumQAGates markers.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-52, Phase-55, Phase-56, Phase-57, Phase-58, and Phase-59 regression smokes passed individually and through the Phase-60 gate.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-60 static-route proof covers public/auth, protected user, admin, and reduced-motion matrices; authenticated clean-deploy screenshots remain a follow-up because local auth fixtures are not materialized.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</item>
  </evidence>
  <verification-matrix>
    <target-1 evidence="build-and-static">User and admin builds compile without TypeScript errors and produce budget-readable dist artifacts.</target-1>
    <target-2 evidence="screenshot-and-static">Public/auth static-route proof covers premium Matrix style, visible logo/CTA, readable email-proof copy, canonical tariff preview, no-overlap markers, and reduced-motion fallback markers.</target-2>
    <target-3 evidence="screenshot-and-static">Protected user static-route proof covers dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings workflows, copy/download/proxy feedback, subscription calendar, device controls, and MTProto redaction markers.</target-3>
    <target-4 evidence="screenshot-and-static">Protected admin static-route proof covers dashboard/users/devices/MTProto/analytics/servers/plans workflows, redaction, confirmation guards, bounded inventories, and runtime readonly frames.</target-4>
    <target-5 evidence="performance">Bundle size, asset size, Lighthouse fallback, canvas/motion, and route animation budgets are explicit and fail truthfully when unavailable or exceeded.</target-5>
    <target-6 evidence="accessibility">Focus-visible, keyboard reachability markers, reduced-motion, contrast tokens, no pointer interception, no scroll hijack, and no keyboard trap patterns are enforced.</target-6>
    <target-7 evidence="governance">XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, regression smokes, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard pass before Phase-60 is marked done-local.</target-7>
  </verification-matrix>
  <success-scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">A local QA run produces deterministic build, smoke, screenshot/static-route, performance, accessibility, MyGRACE, and protected-surface evidence for Phase-53 through Phase-59 premium frontend work.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">When authenticated fixtures are unavailable, Phase-60 evidence clearly says which protected screenshots are static-route proof and which clean-deploy screenshots remain follow-up.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Performance and motion budgets are conservative enough for current user/admin bundles while strict enough to catch accidental bloat, long animations, blank canvas, or pointer-intercepting overlays.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Regression smoke confirms Phase-52/55/56/57/58/59 contracts still pass under the unified QA gate.</scenario-4>
  </success-scenarios>
  <failure-scenarios>
    <failure-1 kind="failure">Any target viewport shows horizontal scroll, text/control/status overlap, hidden CTA/action, unreadable form/table/chart, blank Matrix canvas, or broken reduced-motion fallback.</failure-1>
    <failure-2 kind="failure">Phase-60 smoke claims authenticated screenshot coverage without a real authenticated fixture or clean-deploy evidence.</failure-2>
    <failure-3 kind="failure">Bundle, asset, Lighthouse/Web Vitals, canvas, or motion budgets are missing, unavailable without explicit fallback, or exceeded without a recorded blocker.</failure-3>
    <failure-4 kind="failure">Keyboard traversal cannot reach nav/actions/forms/tabs/dialogs, focus-visible is hidden, or any modal/confirmation traps focus incorrectly.</failure-4>
    <failure-5 kind="failure">Smoke output, screenshots, console captures, or docs expose MTProto secrets, full proxy links, VPN config contents, bearer/refresh/reset/verify tokens, real emails, raw IP exports, payment/provider identifiers, database URLs, or API keys.</failure-5>
    <failure-6 kind="failure">Phase-60 modifies backend API, auth/session, billing catalog, VPN/MTProto runtime, deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose, telegram-bot, or secret-handling surfaces.</failure-6>
  </failure-scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][BUILDS_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][SCREENSHOT_MATRIX_READY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][NO_OVERLAP_PASS]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][RESPONSIVE_PASS]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][REDUCED_MOTION_PASS]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][ACCESSIBILITY_PASS]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][PERFORMANCE_BUDGET_PASS]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][REGRESSION_SMOKES_PASS]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][MYGRACE_PASS]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[PremiumQAGates][phase60][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-10>
    <marker-11 phase="65-planned">[PremiumRCGate][phase65][RELEASE_READY]</marker-11>
  </required-log-markers>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Allowed output: route names, viewport names, selector names, synthetic fixture IDs, screenshot file paths, bundle byte/gzip sizes, Lighthouse category scores, Web Vitals numbers, budget names, unavailable-tool reason, and pass/fail markers.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Forbidden output: MTProto ee secrets, full tg:// or https://t.me proxy links, WireGuard/AWG config contents, bearer/refresh/reset/verify tokens, real user/admin emails, raw IP history exports, payment IDs, YooKassa/Resend keys, database URLs, API keys, private keys, or screenshot binary data.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>Screenshots must use synthetic or redacted data only. Live clean-deploy screenshots require operator approval and must not include secrets, raw config, raw IP history exports, or provider keys.</requirement-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1 level="module-local">M-078 Phase-60 smoke proves screenshot matrix specification, responsive/no-overlap assertions, performance budgets, accessibility/reduced-motion checks, regression smoke wiring, MyGRACE checks, and protected-surface guard.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 level="wave">M-009, M-010, M-036, M-037, M-038, M-070, M-071, M-073, M-075, M-076, and M-077 regression smokes remain satisfied after QA gate implementation.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 level="phase">User/admin builds, Phase-60 smoke, Phase-52/55/56/57/58/59 smokes, screenshot/static-route evidence, performance/accessibility budgets, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard pass before Phase-60 can be marked done-local.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 level="future-phase">Phase-65 release candidate gate remains planned and must not be marked release-ready by Phase-60 evidence alone.</gate-4>
  </phase-gates>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Safe for autonomous local execution if changes stay inside QA scripts, screenshot/performance tooling, package metadata needed to run those scripts, and MyGRACE docs. Stop if execution appears to require backend API changes, auth/session changes, billing catalog mutation, VPN/MTProto runtime changes, deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose changes, telegram-bot changes, production server access, or secret-handling changes.</autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-078>
