<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-046 MODULE="M-046" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="partial-live" VERSION="1.6.0">
  <module>krotpn-domain-tls-edge</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-32 status="partial-local">Domain, HTTPS redirect, wildcard TLS, and shared 443 routing verification for krotpn.xyz passed local/static gates; live smoke remains operator-required.</phase-32>
    <phase-34 status="partial-local">Stabilization gate reuses local/static edge checks and keeps production DNS, wildcard TLS, shared 443, and real Telegram client smoke as explicit operator-live evidence.</phase-34>
    <phase-35 status="partial-local">Approved installer wildcard TLS changes provide deploy-supported operator certificate reuse and runtime nginx domain rendering while preserving shared-443 live gates.</phase-35>
    <phase-37 status="partial-live">Shared 443 is implemented by mtproto-edge owning public TCP 443 and forwarding normal HTTPS to nginx fallback on 8443.</phase-37>
    <phase-38 status="pass-local">Shared 443 is redefined as RU SNI router ownership with web SNI to RU nginx fallback and issued MTProto SNI to the DE runtime.</phase-38>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py</file>
    <file>scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>.env.example</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-32.xml</file>
    <file>docs/edge/PHASE-32-CUTOVER.xml</file>
    <file phase="34-handoff">docs/handoff/PHASE-34-RELEASE-CHECKLIST.xml</file>
    <file phase="34-static">scripts/phase34-mtproto-stabilization-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="37-static">scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="37-runtime">mtproto-runtime</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py -v</command-1>
    <command-2>sh -c 'if [ -e .env ]; then DB_PASSWORD=phase32-compose-check docker compose config; else ln -s .env.example .env &amp;&amp; trap "rm -f .env" EXIT &amp;&amp; DB_PASSWORD=phase32-compose-check docker compose config; fi'</command-2>
    <command-3>node scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs</command-3>
    <command-4>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-32.xml docs/modules/M-046.xml docs/verification/V-M-046.xml docs/verification-index.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-4>
    <command-5>node scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</command-5>
    <command-6>operator-live smoke after DNS and wildcard certificate readiness: HTTP redirect, HTTPS frontend/API/admin health through 8443 fallback, issued MTProto SNI route, Telegram Desktop available status, rollback rehearsal notes.</command-6>
    <command-7 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</command-7>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>M-046 static tests prove krotpn.xyz domain settings, redirect rules, wildcard certificate paths, single 443 owner contract, and protected deploy/install script boundaries.</module-local>
    <wave-level>M-012 compose validation and M-044 runtime bridge tests remain in scope so shared 443 does not break existing deploy composition or MTProto policy replay.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Production-like smoke proves real DNS, trusted wildcard TLS, HTTPS fallback, and at least one issued MTProto SNI before public advertisement.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">M-001 settings expose canonical krotpn.xyz frontend/domain values, MTProto base domain krotpn.xyz, and proxy port 443 without logging secrets.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">HTTP requests for krotpn.xyz and www.krotpn.xyz permanently redirect to https://krotpn.xyz without serving mixed HTTP content.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">TLS configuration expects trusted wildcard coverage for krotpn.xyz and *.krotpn.xyz and does not accept self-signed certs for production edge claims.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Docker compose resolves one explicit owner for public 443, avoiding simultaneous nginx and MTProto bind conflicts.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Normal HTTPS fallback keeps frontend, /api, and /admin routes reachable with X-Forwarded-Proto=https semantics.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="deterministic">MTProto SNI routing accepts only issued user SNI names from the M-044 runtime policy and never exposes base secrets or derived secrets in traces.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="static-guard">Phase-32/34 verification fails if deploy scripts or install.sh drift outside explicitly approved Phase-35 wildcard TLS installer scope.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="rollback">Rollback evidence shows how to restore previous nginx-only 443 behavior if shared edge routing fails.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="phase-34-live-required">Phase-34 cannot claim production readiness until HTTPS, admin, API, one issued MTProto SNI, unknown SNI behavior, and rollback readiness are live-smoked.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="phase-37-deterministic">nginx no longer binds listen 443 ssl; mtproto-edge is the public 443 owner and nginx HTTPS fallback listens on 8443.</check-10>
    <check-11 evidence="phase-38-deterministic">RU SNI router is the only public TCP 443 owner, web SNI routes to RU nginx 8443, and MTProto SNI routes to DE runtime.</check-11>
    <check-12 evidence="phase-38-rollback">Rollback path restores nginx-only public 443 before any failed Telegram retest is advertised to users.</check-12>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-34-stabilization-gates>
    <gate-1>Local execution may run static edge checks only; no DNS, certificate, nginx, docker-compose, deploy, install, or live server changes are allowed without operator scope.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Release handoff must record whether live shared 443 smoke passed, remains blocked, or is explicitly waived with risk ownership.</gate-2>
  </phase-34-stabilization-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">http://krotpn.xyz and http://www.krotpn.xyz redirect permanently to https://krotpn.xyz.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">https://krotpn.xyz serves the user frontend and https://krotpn.xyz/api traffic reaches the backend through the HTTPS fallback route.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">https://krotpn.xyz/admin remains reachable for the admin frontend after shared 443 changes.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">An issued MTProto fake-TLS SNI under *.krotpn.xyz routes to the MTProto runtime bridge without changing the user's VPN state.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Unknown SNI, expired wildcard cert, missing cert files, or DNS mismatch fail closed and do not leak proxy secrets.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">443 bind conflict or bad shared-edge classification triggers rollback to the previous nginx-only public surface.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="success">RU SNI router forwards browser HTTPS to RU nginx fallback and Telegram fake-TLS to DE runtime without exposing policy API publicly.</scenario-7>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-046][edge_contract][DOMAIN_SETTINGS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-046][nginx_contract][HTTP_TO_HTTPS_REDIRECT]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-046][edge_router][SNI_CLASSIFY]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-046][edge_router][HTTPS_FALLBACK]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-046][edge_router][MTPROTO_ROUTE]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-046][edge_contract][ROLLBACK_READY]</marker-6>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Verification logs must never print certificate private keys, .env values, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, derived secrets, tg://proxy links, JWTs, or email verification tokens.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Live smoke output may include hostnames, status codes, certificate issuer/expiry, route names, and redacted SNI suffixes only.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Admin and diagnostic summaries must not include full per-user MTProto links or raw fake-TLS secrets.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <live-smoke-gates>
    <gate-1>DNS A or AAAA for krotpn.xyz and wildcard SNI test names points to the intended edge host before live smoke.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Let's Encrypt or another trusted certificate validates krotpn.xyz and *.krotpn.xyz without browser or curl trust bypass.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>HTTP redirect returns a permanent redirect to the canonical HTTPS host.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>HTTPS frontend, backend API health, and admin route return healthy responses through the public edge.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>One issued MTProto SNI reaches the runtime bridge while unknown SNI remains safely rejected or falls back to HTTPS as designed.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Rollback procedure is documented and rehearsed enough to restore previous public behavior quickly.</gate-6>
    <gate-7>Phase-37 live smoke confirms public TCP 443 owner, nginx 8443 fallback owner, local policy health, public HTTPS response, and Telegram Desktop proxy availability.</gate-7>
    <gate-8>Phase-38 live smoke confirms RU SNI router public 443 owner, DE runtime target, private policy health, public HTTPS response, and Telegram Desktop proxy availability.</gate-8>
  </live-smoke-gates>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>edge_http_redirect_count tagged by host and status code.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>edge_sni_classification_count tagged by route_type without secret-bearing labels.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>edge_https_fallback_count tagged by route frontend, api, or admin.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>edge_mtproto_route_count tagged by issued/unissued classification only.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>edge_rollback_trigger_count tagged by safe failure code.</metric-5>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>partial-local-only</level>
    <safe-local>Static tests, docker compose config, XML parsing, MyGRACE lint, and secret-redaction checks are safe to run locally.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Live DNS, wildcard certificate issuance, public 443 ownership changes, production smoke, and Telegram Desktop proof require explicit operator readiness and rollback window.</requires-operator>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py passed locally with 7 tests.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-14: docker compose config passed using a temporary .env symlink to .env.example and DB_PASSWORD=phase32-compose-check.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-14: scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs passed and protected deploy/install scripts were not changed.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-14: M-044/M-043/M-040 regression pytest passed locally with 29 tests for runtime bridge, scheduler, MTProto provisioning, email delivery, and email verification guards.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-14: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and git diff whitespace checks passed.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-14: Phase-34 handoff records V-M-046 live smoke as operator-required and the local static smoke keeps deploy/install/edge surfaces unchanged.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-17: Phase-35 updated the edge static guard to allow only approved M-048 installer wildcard TLS deploy surface changes; M-046 public shared-443 live smoke remains operator-required.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-18: Phase-37 corrected the live design so mtproto-edge owns public 443 and normal HTTPS fallback moves to nginx 8443.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-18: Phase-38 verification redefines the public 443 live gate around RU SNI router plus DE runtime after RU-only mtproto_proxy stayed blocked-live.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution passed SNI router static coverage, compose public-443 ownership checks, nginx HTTPS fallback checks, and docker compose config with .env.example.</evidence-10>
  </evidence>
</V-M-046>
