<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-037 MODULE="M-037" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase54-pass-local-phase74-pass-local-phase75-pass-local-phase76" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-74="pass-local" PHASE-75="pass-local" PHASE-76="pass-local">
  <module>mobile-admin-console</module>
  <checks>Admin frontend must become compact and usable from a phone for operational status, user search, devices, payments/analytics, and system health.</checks>
  <test-files>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx frontend-admin/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs</test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-05: Phase-75 frontend-admin build and admin Users/Devices smoke passed for single Users nav, bounded expanded device lists, reachable actions, readable confirmations, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend guard.</commands>
  <levels>
    <module-local>TypeScript/Vite build and static source review after every Phase-24 frontend-admin change.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Mobile smoke across overview, users, devices, and analytics/payment routes after each completed UI wave.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Final Phase-24 gate requires build, mobile smoke, confirmation-path evidence, and deploy/install no-diff evidence before V-M-037 can move to pass-local.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Admin frontend build passes.</check-1>
    <check-2>Mobile overview surfaces service health, users, subscriptions, revenue, VPN/system status, and urgent counts without desktop-only layout.</check-2>
    <check-3>User search and device registry are readable on phone viewports without table-only primary workflows.</check-3>
    <check-4>Device block, unblock, rotate, and revoke are reachable and require confirmation.</check-4>
    <check-5>Audit-sensitive admin actions preserve current backend audit expectations and show refreshed success/error feedback.</check-5>
    <check-6>No deploy/install scripts are modified during Phase-24 execution.</check-6>
    <check-7>Admin API base path and device endpoint names remain compatible with M-006 and M-024 unless separately approved.</check-7>
    <check-8>Mobile smoke auth fixture uses a test admin state and does not require storing real production tokens in evidence.</check-8>
    <check-9>Phase-54 Matrix mobile admin shell keeps navigation, search, pagination, filters, and action controls compact at 360px without long unstructured lists.</check-9>
    <check-10>Phase-54 tables, graphs, and investigation panels use bounded internal scroll or pagination instead of document-level horizontal scroll.</check-10>
    <check-11>Phase-54 confirms confirmation dialogs/sheets remain readable, focused, and visually above Matrix overlays.</check-11>
    <check-12>Phase-74 admin navigation removes Tariffs from visible mobile/tablet/desktop nav while keeping Dashboard, Users, MTProto, Servers/Nodes, Analytics, and Logout reachable.</check-12>
    <check-13>Phase-74 logout position is directly below Nodes in the admin rail so it stays visible without requiring a long scroll.</check-13>
    <check-14>Phase-74 scroll repair proves mouse-wheel and touch scrolling operate over admin content panes, with the rail bounded instead of owning the only useful scroll path.</check-14>
    <check-15>Phase-75 phone/tablet admin navigation exposes one Users section and does not show a separate Devices tab after the merge.</check-15>
    <check-16>Phase-75 expanded user device lists must stay bounded and scrollable so many devices do not create an unmanageable long page.</check-16>
    <check-17>Phase-75 device actions remain reachable from mobile within the expanded user row or compact detail surface.</check-17>
    <check-18>Phase-75 confirmation surfaces remain readable above Matrix overlays and name the exact device target.</check-18>
    <check-19>Phase-75 preserves search for users and a practical path to inspect devices for the selected user on phone viewports.</check-19>
  </module-checks>
  <deterministic-assertions>
    <assert-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build exits 0.</assert-1>
    <assert-2>Every checked viewport records document.documentElement.scrollWidth &lt;= window.innerWidth.</assert-2>
    <assert-3>Device action controls do not call blockMutation.mutate, unblockMutation.mutate, rotateMutation.mutate, or revokeMutation.mutate directly from row buttons.</assert-3>
    <assert-4>Routes /, /users, /devices compatibility redirect, and /analytics remain registered in frontend-admin/src/main.tsx; visible compact navigation exposes /users without a separate /devices tab after Phase-75.</assert-4>
    <assert-5>deploy, install.sh, nginx, docker-compose.yml, frontend-admin/Dockerfile, and frontend-admin/nginx.conf have no Phase-24 diff.</assert-5>
    <assert-6>Phase-54 checked routes /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, and /analytics report document.documentElement.scrollWidth &lt;= window.innerWidth on mobile viewports.</assert-6>
    <assert-7>Phase-54 checked routes expose their primary search, pagination, or action controls within compact mobile surfaces.</assert-7>
    <assert-8>Phase-74 smoke confirms no visible "Тарифы" navigation item or stale Tariffs card remains in admin shell output.</assert-8>
    <assert-9>Phase-74 smoke confirms admin content containers expose normal vertical overflow/scroll markers and do not depend on rail-only wheel scrolling.</assert-9>
    <assert-10>Phase-74 smoke confirms admin-rail has explicit height/overflow bounds compatible with phone, tablet, and desktop layouts.</assert-10>
    <assert-11>Phase-75 smoke confirms no visible "Устройства" navigation item remains after the merge.</assert-11>
    <assert-12>Phase-75 smoke confirms the Users page carries unified-inventory and expandable-device-row markers.</assert-12>
    <assert-13>Phase-75 smoke confirms expanded device lists have bounded-scroll or pagination markers for many-device users.</assert-13>
    <assert-14>Phase-75 smoke confirms one-device confirmation guards remain in the unified Users route.</assert-14>
    <assert-15>Phase-75 smoke confirms direct /devices handling is a safe redirect/compat path, not a duplicate primary nav surface.</assert-15>
  </deterministic-assertions>
  <phase-74-admin-shell-responsive-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Desktop admin shell keeps Logout under Nodes, not below long secondary content.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Visible admin navigation does not include Tariffs/Plans after Phase-74, while operational routes remain reachable and compact.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Content-area wheel scrolling and rail clipping are asserted statically by Phase-74 smoke markers.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-74 changes are frontend-admin only; no backend API, billing provider, deploy, install, nginx, docker, or runtime behavior changed.</gate-4>
  </phase-74-admin-shell-responsive-gates>
  <phase-75-unified-inventory-responsive-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Phone and tablet admin navigation must keep Users, MTProto, Nodes, Analytics, and Logout reachable while removing the separate Devices nav item.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Expanded device lists inside Users must be compact, bounded, and usable at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, and 1440x900.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Device action buttons and confirmation sheet/dialog must remain visible and touch-safe without document-level horizontal scroll.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-75 must not weaken Phase-74 content scroll or rail bounds.</gate-4>
  </phase-75-unified-inventory-responsive-gates>
  <static-probes>
    <probe-1>Review frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx for confirmation state, dialog/sheet/modal, or equivalent explicit confirmation before mutation.</probe-1>
    <probe-2>Review frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx for mobile navigation that does not preserve the 320px sidebar as the primary phone path.</probe-2>
    <probe-3>Review frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx and frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx for compact rows/cards that are usable without table-only horizontal scrolling.</probe-3>
    <probe-4>Review frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx for phone-first KPI summaries before chart-heavy detail.</probe-4>
  </static-probes>
  <viewport-matrix>
    <viewport-1 route="/" size="360x740">Overview loads without horizontal document scroll and exposes system health plus urgent user/device navigation.</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2 route="/users" size="390x844">Search, counters, role/status, identity, and pagination fit without a desktop-only table dependency.</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3 route="/devices" size="430x932">Device rows, signals, and block/unblock/rotate/revoke confirmation paths fit within the viewport.</viewport-3>
    <viewport-4 route="/analytics" size="390x844">Payment and analytics status remains readable without charts dominating the first phone viewport.</viewport-4>
  </viewport-matrix>
  <phase-54-viewport-matrix status="pass-local">
    <viewport-1 route="/" size="360x740">Matrix dashboard health/KPI rows remain readable and primary operational links are visible.</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2 route="/users" size="390x844">Search, filters, user rows, role/status, and pagination fit compactly without document horizontal scroll.</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3 route="/devices" size="430x932">Device rows and block/unblock/rotate/revoke confirmation paths remain reachable and non-overlapping.</viewport-3>
    <viewport-4 route="/mtproto" size="390x844">Assignment inventory, embedded analytics, alerts, IP history, promotion tag, and reissue/revoke controls stay usable.</viewport-4>
    <viewport-5 route="/servers" size="390x844">Nodes, routes, forms, and delete/edit actions stay bounded and confirmation-safe.</viewport-5>
    <viewport-6 route="/plans" size="360x740">Canonical tariff matrix remains readable without accidental edit/delete controls.</viewport-6>
    <viewport-7 route="/analytics" size="430x932">Business charts and summaries stay compact and do not dominate the first phone viewport.</viewport-7>
  </phase-54-viewport-matrix>
  <smoke-fixture>
    <auth-fixture>Use a non-production persisted admin-auth/localStorage fixture or a test backend session; never record real admin_token or refresh token values.</auth-fixture>
    <api-fixture>Use local backend, mocked network responses, or existing dev fixtures sufficient to render stats, users, devices, billing, and health states.</api-fixture>
    <state-fixture>Exercise loading, empty, populated, success feedback, error feedback, and confirmation states where practical.</state-fixture>
  </smoke-fixture>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Admin can inspect system state and manage a device from a phone without switching to desktop layout.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Admin can search a user and read role/status/account context from compact rows at 360px width.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Admin can open a device action confirmation that names the target peer before mutation.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Critical device actions are hidden in a wide table or unavailable on mobile.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">An admin action lacks confirmation or loses audit visibility.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">A compact UI change modifies deploy/install scripts, backend business rules, or billing provider behavior.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[FrontendAdmin][Phase24][BUILD_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[FrontendAdmin][Phase24][NO_HORIZONTAL_SCROLL]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[FrontendAdmin][Phase24][DEVICE_ACTION_CONFIRM]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[FrontendAdmin][Phase24][NO_DEPLOY_INSTALL_DIFF]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[FrontendAdmin][Phase24][ADMIN_API_CONTRACT_UNCHANGED]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MobileAdminConsole][Phase54][ROUTE_VIEWPORT_SAFE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MobileAdminConsole][Phase54][PRIMARY_ACTIONS_REACHABLE]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[MobileAdminConsole][Phase54][TABLES_SCROLL_CONTAINED]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[MobileAdminConsole][Phase54][CONFIRMATIONS_READABLE]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[MobileAdminConsole][phase74][ADMIN_LOGOUT_UNDER_NODES]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[MobileAdminConsole][phase74][CONTENT_SCROLL_WHEEL_SAFE]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[MobileAdminConsole][phase74][RAIL_BOUNDS_SAFE]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[MobileAdminConsole][phase75][SINGLE_USERS_NAV]</marker-13>
    <marker-14>[MobileAdminConsole][phase75][EXPANDED_DEVICE_LIST_BOUNDED]</marker-14>
    <marker-15>[MobileAdminConsole][phase75][DEVICE_ACTIONS_REACHABLE]</marker-15>
    <marker-16>[MobileAdminConsole][phase75][CONFIRMATIONS_READABLE]</marker-16>
  </required-log-markers>
  <telemetry>
    <telemetry-1>Record route, viewport width/height, scrollWidth, innerWidth, and primary visible controls for each smoke step.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>Record the device action name, target display label, confirmation surface presence, and post-action feedback behavior without storing peer keys or tokens.</telemetry-2>
    <telemetry-3>Record build command, exit code, and git diff no-deploy result.</telemetry-3>
  </telemetry>
  <redaction>
    <redact-1>Do not record admin_token, admin_refresh_token, Authorization headers, cookies, private keys, full VPN configs, raw .env values, payment secrets, or database URLs.</redact-1>
    <redact-2>Use anonymized emails and device names in screenshots or textual evidence when possible.</redact-2>
  </redaction>
  <autonomous-execution-safety status="ready-with-guards">
    Autonomous execution is allowed only for frontend-admin UI files and matching MyGRACE docs. Backend business rules, billing provider behavior, Phase-25 auth/session changes, deploy scripts, install scripts, docker, and nginx files are excluded.
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <planned-evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-10: npm run build passed in frontend-admin.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-10: Chrome/CDP mobile smoke passed for /, /users, /devices, and /analytics at 360x740, 390x844, and 430x932; every route reported scrollWidth equal to innerWidth and mobile nav present.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-10: Device action smoke clicked Block, opened confirmation text containing the target device/user/scope, and observed 0 mutation requests before confirm.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-10: Static review found no direct Mutation.mutate calls from device row buttons.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-10: deploy/install/docker/nginx/frontend-admin deployment surfaces had no diff.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-03: Phase-54 verification design added mobile Matrix route, viewport, pagination, bounded scroll, confirmation, and protected-surface gates.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-06-03: Phase-54 local execution passed frontend-admin build and smoke markers [MobileAdminConsole][Phase54][ROUTE_VIEWPORT_SAFE], [PRIMARY_ACTIONS_REACHABLE], [TABLES_SCROLL_CONTAINED], and [CONFIRMATIONS_READABLE].</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-06-05: Phase-74 smoke passed [MobileAdminConsole][phase74][ADMIN_LOGOUT_UNDER_NODES], [CONTENT_SCROLL_WHEEL_SAFE], and [RAIL_BOUNDS_SAFE] with no visible Tariffs nav.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-06-05: Phase-75 smoke passed [MobileAdminConsole][phase75][SINGLE_USERS_NAV], [EXPANDED_DEVICE_LIST_BOUNDED], [DEVICE_ACTIONS_REACHABLE], and [CONFIRMATIONS_READABLE] with /devices redirected to /users.</evidence-9>
  </planned-evidence>
  <phase-76-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Mobile admin console regression verification across Phase-74 and Phase-75.</scope>
    <gate-1>Phone, tablet, and desktop admin shell must keep Dashboard, Users, MTProto, Nodes, Analytics, and Logout reachable without visible Tariffs or separate Devices navigation.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Expanded user device rows must remain bounded, scrollable, action-reachable, and confirmation-safe on mobile.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Phase-54, Phase-58, Phase-59, Phase-61, and Phase-62 admin regressions must remain green in the Phase-76 bundle.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs.</commands>
  </phase-76-verification-design>
  <phase-76-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Consolidated Phase-76 gate passed for mobile admin console: Phase-74/75 smokes plus Phase-54/58/59/62 regressions kept the unified Users inventory, bounded device rows, logout placement, content scroll, and confirmation surfaces intact.</phase-76-evidence>
</V-M-037>
