<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-052 MODULE="M-052" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="superseded-pass-local">
  <purpose>Verify the Phase-40 official MTProxy data-plane reference and, for Phase-41, verify that it is not the active production path unless rollback is explicit.</purpose>
  <phase-41-supersession>
    <item-1>Phase-41 production behavior removes official MTProxy from active DE MTProto routing.</item-1>
    <item-2>Official runtime files may remain in the repository as reference/rollback artifacts, but active issuance must use KPprotoN fake-TLS policy.</item-2>
  </phase-41-supersession>
  <test-files>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_official_mtproxy_supervisor.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">scripts/phase40-official-mtproxy-live-smoke.sh</file>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/entrypoint.sh</file>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/secret-control.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/Dockerfile</file>
    <file implemented="true">deploy/haproxy-phase40.cfg</file>
    <file implemented="true">deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file implemented="true">docker-compose.yml</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 LEVEL="module-local">bash -n official-mtproxy/entrypoint.sh scripts/phase40-official-mtproxy-live-smoke.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh install.sh</check-1>
    <check-2 LEVEL="module-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_official_mtproxy_supervisor.py tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py -v</check-2>
    <check-3 LEVEL="wave">docker compose config with Phase-40 MTProxy services enabled, using redacted env fixtures only.</check-3>
    <check-4 LEVEL="phase-live">scripts/phase40-official-mtproxy-live-smoke.sh --redacted --require-req-pq</check-4>
    <check-5 LEVEL="phase-41">Verify official MTProxy is not the active production data-plane after KPprotoN fake-TLS rollback.</check-5>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Launcher builds official mtproto-proxy arguments from active 32-hex secrets and passes them as -S values without echoing secrets.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Runtime stats and health are bound privately or to loopback and expose no user secrets, tg links, or runtime tokens.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">RU public 443 routes HTTPS ClientHello for krotpn.xyz to web and routes non-HTTPS MTProto traffic to DE official MTProxy.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Live req_pq through the public KrotPN endpoint receives resPQ for the issued secure secret.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Repeated apply of an unchanged active manifest returns health and emits UNCHANGED without restarting mtproto-proxy.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Official config fetch failure uses documented cached files or marks runtime degraded without returning active user payloads.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Invalid or empty secret manifest prevents official runtime promotion and emits redacted degraded status.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">Any web HTTPS, backend API, or admin 8443 regression blocks release readiness.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="success">Phase-41 deploy keeps official runtime inactive while KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime serves issued SNI traffic.</scenario-9>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[OfficialMTProxy][manifest][REDACTED_COUNT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[OfficialMTProxy][process][STARTED]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[OfficialMTProxy][http][STARTED]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[OfficialMTProxy][manifest][UNCHANGED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[Phase40Smoke][route][HTTPS_OK]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[Phase40Smoke][req_pq][PASS_REDACTED]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[Phase40Smoke][redaction][PASS]</marker-7>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never print raw 32-hex secrets, dd-prefixed secrets, full tg links, proxy-secret file contents, runtime tokens, wildcard private keys, JWTs, API keys, or raw .env content.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Allowed evidence is assignment id, masked hostname, secret fingerprint, active secret count, route state, req_pq pass/fail, and high-level container health.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <evidence-levels>
    <level-1>Deterministic static assertions first: shell syntax, config rendering, routing rules, private stats binding, and secret-output grep guards.</level-1>
    <level-2>Integration checks second: compose config, container command inspection, HAProxy route classification, and rollback path.</level-2>
    <level-3>Live proof last: public RU 443 req_pq and operator Telegram Desktop/mobile availability confirmation.</level-3>
  </evidence-levels>
  <failure-policy>
    <policy-1>Any req_pq timeout keeps Phase-40 blocked-live.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Any raw secret or full proxy link in logs, docker output, admin output, or smoke output fails verification.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Any regression in web HTTPS, backend API, or admin 8443 fails release readiness.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Any unchanged manifest apply that restarts mtproto-proxy fails live stability verification.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>After Phase-41 execution, any active production route to M-052 fails verification unless explicitly running rollback.</policy-5>
  </failure-policy>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-19: backend/tests/test_official_mtproxy_supervisor.py proves unchanged manifest apply skips restart while dead-process fallback still restarts.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-19: Live DE hotfix showed repeated scheduler/apply cycles emitted UNCHANGED without SIGTERM and health returned healthy with private stats available.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design marks official MTProxy as superseded for production and adds a gate that it is inactive in the KPprotoN rollback path.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local smoke verified official MTProxy is not selected as the active production data-plane while rollback/reference files remain available.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
</V-M-052>
