<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-038 MODULE="M-038" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local">
  <module>compact-ui-system</module>
  <checks>Shared UI rules must make user and admin surfaces compact, consistent, and readable on mobile screens.</checks>
  <test-files>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx frontend/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx frontend-admin/src/index.css</test-files>
  <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; Phase-23 compact UI static review and mobile viewport smoke; cd ../frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build; Phase-24 admin compact UI static review and Chrome/CDP mobile viewport smoke before full M-038 closure</commands>
  <levels>
    <module-local>User frontend build and static compact UI review run after each compact shell, dashboard, config, or subscription change.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Phase-23 wave smoke checks layout density, no nested cards, no decorative hero/orb basis, stable controls, and safe text on user routes.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Full M-038 compact UI closure passed locally after Phase-24 admin build and mobile admin smoke.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>User frontend build passes for Phase-23.</check-1>
    <check-2>Admin frontend build passes during Phase-24 or full M-038 closure.</check-2>
    <check-3>Compact UI rules avoid nested cards, oversized dashboard sections, decorative clutter, and horizontal scroll.</check-3>
    <check-4>Buttons, lists, tabs, dialogs, and confirmations have stable mobile dimensions.</check-4>
    <check-5>Operational screens do not start with marketing hero sections or repeated status panels.</check-5>
    <check-6>Text wraps or truncates intentionally for long emails, device keys, plan names, and status labels.</check-6>
    <check-7>Admin device actions use confirmation-safe mobile patterns and do not mutate directly from table-row buttons.</check-7>
    <check-8>Compact UI execution records route/viewport/no-scroll evidence for both user and admin surfaces before M-038 can move from partial-local.</check-8>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-matrix>
    <rule-layout>Mobile shell uses concise navigation instead of a desktop-width sidebar and repeated identity/status panels.</rule-layout>
    <rule-density>Dashboard, config, and subscription pages use compact rows or flat sections instead of large decorative grids.</rule-density>
    <rule-controls>Action buttons keep icon plus short label, stable touch target size, disabled state, and no layout shift while loading.</rule-controls>
    <rule-text>Long emails, device names, device keys, plan names, prices, and status labels wrap or truncate intentionally without overlap.</rule-text>
    <rule-background>Operational surfaces do not rely on decorative radial-gradient/orb backgrounds or marketing hero composition.</rule-background>
    <rule-admin-actions>Admin destructive/disruptive actions stay visible but require confirmation that identifies the target device/peer.</rule-admin-actions>
    <rule-evidence>Every compact UI closure records deterministic build first, visual/mobile smoke second, and static design review third.</rule-evidence>
  </verification-matrix>
  <evidence-types>
    <type-1 priority="deterministic">Build result, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and git no-diff checks for excluded surfaces.</type-1>
    <type-2 priority="trace">Route/viewport smoke logs with scrollWidth, innerWidth, visible controls, and confirmation state.</type-2>
    <type-3 priority="integration">Optional local backend or mocked API route render checks for admin stats, users, devices, billing, and health states.</type-3>
  </evidence-types>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">User cabinet uses compact layout rules while preserving VPN, billing, and device workflows.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Admin console adopts the same rules in Phase-24 without changing the Phase-23 user scope.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">A redesigned screen remains card-heavy, desktop-first, decorative, or text-overlapping on phones.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">The compact system hides destructive actions without clear secondary placement or confirmation-safe affordance.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">CSS simplification makes loading, empty, error, modal, or disabled states resize the surrounding layout.</scenario-5>
  </scenarios>
  <ui-rules>
    <rule-1>No nested cards inside cards.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>No decorative radial-gradient/orb backgrounds as the basis of operational screens.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>No wide tables or raw pre blocks causing page-level horizontal scroll.</rule-3>
    <rule-4>Use lucide icons in action buttons where an icon exists.</rule-4>
    <rule-5>Use stable touch targets and row heights across loading, empty, success, and error states.</rule-5>
    <rule-6>Use confirmation-safe mobile action surfaces for admin block, unblock, rotate, and revoke flows.</rule-6>
  </ui-rules>
  <static-review>
    <review-1>Layout does not preserve the 320px desktop sidebar as the primary phone navigation.</review-1>
    <review-2>Dashboard does not keep decorative hero copy as the dominant first-screen element.</review-2>
    <review-3>Config page does not expose raw preformatted config text in a way that creates page-level horizontal scroll.</review-3>
    <review-4>Subscription page does not depend on oversized plan cards for basic purchase and renewal actions.</review-4>
    <review-5>Admin layout does not preserve the 320px desktop sidebar as the primary phone navigation.</review-5>
    <review-6>Admin users and devices do not depend on wide tables as the only usable mobile workflow.</review-6>
    <review-7>Admin analytics keeps charts secondary to concise payment/subscription KPI summaries on phones.</review-7>
    <review-8>Admin device action controls open a confirmation surface before calling block/unblock/rotate/revoke mutations.</review-8>
  </static-review>
  <observability>
    <telemetry-1>Compact UI evidence records route, viewport, scrollWidth, innerWidth, and checked layout rule.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>UI evidence must not contain tokens, private keys, full VPN config text, payment secrets, or raw .env values.</telemetry-2>
    <telemetry-3>Phase-23 evidence covers user frontend only; Phase-24 must add admin evidence before full M-038 closure.</telemetry-3>
    <telemetry-4>Admin compact UI evidence must include confirmation-state checks for block, unblock, rotate, and revoke controls.</telemetry-4>
  </observability>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[CompactUI][Phase23][BUILD_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[CompactUI][Phase23][COMPACT_RULES_PASS]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[CompactUI][Phase23][NO_HORIZONTAL_SCROLL]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[CompactUI][Phase23][TEXT_SAFE]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[CompactUI][Phase24][ADMIN_BUILD_PASS]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[CompactUI][Phase24][ADMIN_NO_HORIZONTAL_SCROLL]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[CompactUI][Phase24][ADMIN_CONFIRMATION_SAFE]</marker-7>
  </required-log-markers>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>Record Phase-23 user frontend build and mobile viewport smoke result.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>Record Phase-24 admin frontend build and mobile viewport smoke result before marking M-038 complete.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>Record static review result for nested cards, decorative background basis, wide raw config blocks, and stable control sizing.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-10: Phase-23 user frontend passed build and Chrome CDP smoke.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-10: Phase-24 admin frontend passed build and Chrome/CDP smoke for /, /users, /devices, and /analytics at 360x740, 390x844, and 430x932.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-10: Admin device confirmation guard passed and deploy/install surfaces stayed unchanged.</evidence-6>
  </evidence>
  <autonomous-execution-safety status="phase-23-user-only">
    Autonomous Phase-23 execution is complete for user frontend compact UI files. Admin frontend remains Phase-24 scope and deploy/install surfaces remain out of scope.
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-24-safety status="planned">
    Phase-24 execution is safe only for frontend-admin compact UI files and related MyGRACE docs. Backend business rules, deploy/install scripts, docker, nginx, and Phase-25 session security remain out of scope.
  </phase-24-safety>
  <closure-gate status="pass-local">
    M-038 moved to done after Phase-24 admin build, mobile smoke, no horizontal scroll, confirmation-safe device actions, and no excluded-surface diff were recorded.
  </closure-gate>
</V-M-038>
