<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-051 MODULE="M-051" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="verification-designed" VERSION="1.1.0">
  <module>mtproto-availability-diagnostics</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-39 status="planned">Close the remaining issued Telegram proxy unavailable state with redacted local/static and operator-live evidence.</phase-39>
    <supersedes>M-050 remains the edge-routing module; M-051 adds the missing availability proof layer above routing and policy health.</supersedes>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file planned="true">scripts/phase39-mtproto-availability-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file planned="true">scripts/phase39-mtproto-live-smoke.sh</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_availability_diagnostics.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_api.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1>bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase39-mtproto-availability-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>bash scripts/phase39-mtproto-live-smoke.sh --redacted</command-3>
    <command-4>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_api.py tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py tests/test_mtproto_availability_diagnostics.py -v</command-4>
    <command-5>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-5>
    <command-6>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/modules/M-051.xml docs/plans/Phase-39.xml docs/verification/V-M-051.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-6>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Static checks prove link format, redaction, fallback-port contracts, and diagnostic schema without live secrets.</module-local>
    <wave-level>M-043, M-044, M-045, M-050, and M-012 run together because issued-link payload, runtime policy, UI connection action, DE edge, and deploy guard form one availability behavior.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Operator-live smoke proves one active assignment through public RU 443, DE fake-TLS accept, Telegram downstream reachability, and Telegram Desktop available status.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">Backend and runtime secret derivation parity remains stable for issued SNI without printing the derived secret.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Generated owner link supports the primary Telegram connection action and full-link copy flow.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">DE runtime fallback guard rejects stale 127.0.0.1:8443 for Phase-39 and expects private 9443 fallback.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="security">Phase-39 diagnostics redact tg links, derived secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, private keys, JWTs, and raw .env content.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="operator-live">One active assignment is present, active, policy-applied, and counted in DE policy health.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="operator-live">Fake-TLS probe receives a response through public RU 443 to DE runtime using the issued assignment derivation.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="operator-live">DE runtime can reach at least one Telegram downstream target or emits a separate downstream failure code.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="operator-live">Telegram Desktop marks the issued proxy available using the refreshed primary connection action.</check-8>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-matrix>
    <gate-1 MODULES="M-051,M-043" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Issued assignment payload, SNI, port, and link assembly remain stable and do not rotate existing user credentials.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 MODULES="M-051,M-044" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Runtime policy diagnostics distinguish policy-applied, policy-missing, bridge-unreachable, and adapter-rejected states without leaking credentials.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 MODULES="M-051,M-045" EVIDENCE="deterministic">User cabinet exposes a primary Telegram connection action and full-link copy while keeping manual fields secondary and mobile-safe.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 MODULES="M-051,M-050,M-012" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Deploy/static smoke rejects stale DE fallback 8443 and preserves the Phase-38 private 9443 web fallback versus public admin 8443 split.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 MODULES="M-051,M-050" EVIDENCE="operator-live">Public RU 443 routes an issued MTProto SNI to DE and the fake-TLS probe receives a runtime response.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 MODULES="M-051" EVIDENCE="operator-live">Telegram Desktop marks the issued proxy available after using the refreshed primary connection action.</gate-6>
  </verification-matrix>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Verified user opens cabinet, clicks the primary Telegram action, and Telegram Desktop marks the issued proxy available.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Operator runs redacted live smoke and receives assignment, policy, route, fake-TLS, and downstream success without secrets.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Policy health is OK but fake-TLS accept fails; diagnostics classify secret/link mismatch instead of route failure.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Fake-TLS accept succeeds but downstream Telegram connection fails; diagnostics classify Telegram DC/provider reachability separately.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Stale DE fallback 8443 is detected and blocked from being treated as Phase-39-ready.</scenario-5>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-051][availability_smoke][LOAD_ACTIVE_ASSIGNMENT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-051][availability_smoke][POLICY_HEALTH]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-051][availability_smoke][ROUTE_PUBLIC_443]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-051][availability_smoke][FAKE_TLS_ACCEPT]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-051][availability_smoke][TELEGRAM_DOWNSTREAM]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-051][availability_smoke][TELEGRAM_DESKTOP_PROOF]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-045][dashboard_mtproto_card][OPEN_TELEGRAM]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-050][de_mtproto_runtime][FALLBACK_PORT_GUARD]</marker-8>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never print full tg://proxy links, https://t.me/proxy links, derived secret, base secret, salt, runtime token, wildcard private key, JWTs, refresh tokens, Resend key, or raw .env values.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Live evidence may include assignment id, user id, masked SNI, status codes, policy count, safe hash fingerprints, route role names, and safe failure codes only.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>phase39_assignment_probe_status tagged found, missing, inactive, duplicate, or query_failed.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>phase39_policy_status tagged healthy, degraded, unauthorized, unreachable, or policy_missing.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>phase39_route_status tagged web_route, mtproto_route, unknown_route, connect_failed, or timeout.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>phase39_fake_tls_status tagged accepted, invalid_digest, no_sni, no_response, or runtime_unreachable.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>phase39_downstream_status tagged reachable, unreachable, bootstrap_empty, or provider_blocked.</metric-5>
    <metric-6>phase39_desktop_proof_status tagged operator_available, operator_unavailable, not_run, or stale_client_state.</metric-6>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <live-smoke-gates>
    <gate-1>RU backend can identify exactly one active assignment for the selected test user.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>DE policy health succeeds privately and policy_count is non-zero.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>RU HAProxy routes issued SNI traffic to the DE backend.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Fake-TLS probe receives a server response through public RU 443.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>DE reaches at least one Telegram downstream target.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Operator Telegram Desktop proof reports available.</gate-6>
  </live-smoke-gates>
  <failure-handoff>
    <item-1>If route fails, inspect RU HAProxy SNI match and wildcard DNS before changing secrets.</item-1>
    <item-2>If fake-TLS accept fails, compare redacted derivation fingerprints and user link source before rotating anything.</item-2>
    <item-3>If downstream fails, keep user link stable and investigate DE provider/Telegram DC reachability separately.</item-3>
    <item-4>If Telegram Desktop alone fails after fake-TLS probe passes, clear old proxy entries and retry with the refreshed primary Telegram link before code changes.</item-4>
  </failure-handoff>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, static smoke, backend fake/private adapter tests, frontend build, redaction checks, and deterministic link-format checks.</safe-local>
    <safe-server-readonly>Read-only server diagnostics that do not print .env values, tokens, full links, private keys, or secrets.</safe-server-readonly>
    <requires-operator>Applying live deploy changes, restarting RU/DE services, and accepting Telegram Desktop proof as final availability evidence.</requires-operator>
    <blocked-action>Secret rotation, SNI reissue, policy token replacement, wildcard certificate replacement, and public firewall changes are out of scope unless a new explicit fix phase approves them.</blocked-action>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-051>
