<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-064 MODULE="M-064" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase53">
  <purpose>Verify Phase-46 registration password example and MTProto user-cabinet link/status UX polish.</purpose>
  <checks>Password example matches policy, MTProto Telegram app and browser links are separated, visible labels are Russian, status badge refresh is dynamic, and protected deploy surfaces remain unchanged.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/passwordPolicy.ts</file>
    <file>scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-46.xml docs/modules/M-064.xml docs/verification/V-M-064.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml</command>
    <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
  </commands>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Registration form renders a password example and keeps passwordStrengthIssues as the validation gate.</check-1>
    <check-2>Dashboard builds tg://proxy for Telegram app opening and https://t.me/proxy for Ссылка browser/copy action.</check-2>
    <check-3>Visible MTProto field/action labels are Ссылка, Сервер, Порт, and Секрет.</check-3>
    <check-4>MTProto status badge class is derived from live payload state and the query has bounded refresh or equivalent invalidation.</check-4>
    <check-5>Phase-46 verification fails if the protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose diff guard shows changes.</check-5>
    <check-6>Phase-53 Matrix auth screens keep password example, duplicate-email recovery CTA, and reset/verify guidance readable without API changes.</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-53 Matrix dashboard keeps tg:// app link, https://t.me browser link, Russian labels, and bounded status refresh readable and compact.</check-7>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-53-ux-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Registration Matrix form keeps strong-password hints and the safe example visible without encouraging literal reuse.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Login, forgot-password, reset-password, verify-email, and check-email states remain compact, readable, and free of stale trial/VPN copy.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>MTProto status badge remains data-derived and must not become a static success badge after visual refactor.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-53 smoke rejects unbounded polling, secret-bearing debug output, and any protected deploy/install diff.</gate-4>
  </phase-53-ux-gates>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Deterministic static smoke validates exact UX contract: safe password example, passwordStrengthIssues gate, dual MTProto link schemes, Russian labels, bounded status refresh, and no secret-bearing output.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Frontend build validates touched React/TypeScript surfaces and shared password policy imports.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and deploy/install diff guard validate artifact consistency and operational isolation.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">A registering user sees a clear password example and still cannot submit a weak password.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">An owner with an activated MTProto proxy can open Telegram through tg:// and copy browser link through https://t.me.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Pending or degraded MTProto state becomes visible after bounded refetch without a page reload or stale success badge.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">The UI reuses https://t.me for the Telegram app button or tg:// for the browser/full-link action.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Status badge remains statically green after backend state changes or no bounded refresh exists.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Smoke, console traces, or fixtures expose a real MTProto secret-bearing link, access token, reset token, or private environment value.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Runtime telemetry is not required for Phase-46 because the scope is frontend UX; static smoke must still assert that no secret-bearing console/debug output is introduced.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Status refresh evidence must be visible in code through bounded polling, invalidation, or equivalent refetch control; unbounded intervals are rejected.</requirement-2>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <required-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-064][phase46_user_cabinet_ux][PASSWORD_EXAMPLE]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-064][phase46_user_cabinet_ux][DUAL_MTPROTO_LINKS]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-064][phase46_user_cabinet_ux][RUSSIAN_LABELS]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-064][phase46_user_cabinet_ux][DYNAMIC_STATUS]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-064][phase53_auth_matrix][PASSWORD_EXAMPLE_READABLE]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-064][phase53_mtproto_matrix][DYNAMIC_STATUS_PRESERVED]</marker-6>
  </required-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Smoke output must not print real MTProto secrets, full proxy links from live accounts, access tokens, refresh tokens, reset tokens, or private env values.</rule-1>
  </redaction-rules>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-06-01: cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build passed.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-06-01: node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs passed and emitted the required M-064 markers.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and deploy/install diff guard passed.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-06-03: Phase-53 frontend build and static smoke passed for readable Matrix auth screens, password example, duplicate-email recovery CTA, dual MTProto links, Russian labels, bounded refresh, and redaction.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Allowed after plan approval because scope is frontend-only and deploy/install/backend runtime surfaces are out of scope.</autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-064>
