<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-044 MODULE="M-044" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase41" VERSION="1.8.1">
  <module>kpproton-runtime-bridge</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-30 status="pass-local">Runtime bridge implemented with fake/local adapter verification.</phase-30>
    <phase-34 status="planned">Stabilization gate keeps runtime apply, replay, health, and revoke in the end-to-end MTProto release suite.</phase-34>
    <phase-37 status="partial-live">Live edge runtime adapter added after clean-VPS Telegram Desktop proxy availability failed because no real MTProto service owned public 443.</phase-37>
    <phase-38 status="pass-local">Runtime bridge must apply, revoke, health-check, and replay policy against a private DE runtime API with degraded-safe failure behavior.</phase-38>
    <phase-41 status="pass-local">Runtime bridge is the production policy path again and does not depend on official MTProxy manifest sync.</phase-41>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_scheduler.py</file>
    <file phase="38-fix">mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl</file>
    <file phase="37">mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_policy_handler.erl</file>
    <file phase="37">scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_scheduler.py -v</commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Runtime bridge tests use fake KPprotoN adapters and local DB sessions; they must not call live Telegram, DNS, host tools, deploy scripts, or install scripts.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Runs with M-042/M-043 tests so bridge policy state cannot drift from assignment persistence or owner-safe payload generation.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-30 cannot pass unless bridge outage produces explicit degraded MTProto state while normal login, verified onboarding, and VPN config access remain non-blocked.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">apply-domain-policy succeeds for one issued SNI and records runtime policy state without persisting secrets.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Startup replay loads active assignments idempotently and skips disabled or superseded assignments.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="failure-path">Bridge unavailable, timeout, malformed response, or adapter exception returns degraded status without breaking KrotPN auth/VPN APIs.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Scheduler reconciliation job is registered once and does not disturb existing subscription, cleanup, or anti-abuse jobs.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="security">Runtime logs and health payloads expose no tg://proxy links, derived secrets, base secret, salt, tokens, or provider credentials.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="operational">Deploy/install surfaces remain unchanged; runtime bridge activation is configured inside backend/runtime service boundaries only.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="deterministic">revoke-domain-policy removes one SNI from runtime policy state idempotently even after the assignment is marked disabled.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="phase-34-integration">Phase-34 full gate proves assignment issuance, owner access, admin revoke, runtime policy removal, and replay remain mutually consistent.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="phase-37-deterministic">HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter applies, revokes, and health-checks the local edge policy API with a token header and without exposing token or proxy secrets.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="phase-37-live-required">Provisioning returns an active proxy payload only after live policy apply succeeds or explicitly reports degraded/incomplete state.</check-10>
    <check-11 evidence="phase-38-deterministic">HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter accepts a private DE policy API URL and rejects unsafe public/no-token configurations in static smoke.</check-11>
    <check-12 evidence="phase-38-failure-path">DE policy API timeout, auth failure, public exposure guard failure, or unreachable route returns degraded state without blocking normal KrotPN login/VPN access.</check-12>
    <check-13 evidence="phase-38-deterministic">The Erlang mtproto_proxy bootstrap URL uses POLICY_LISTEN_IP, not hardcoded 127.0.0.1, when the policy API is privately bound on DE.</check-13>
    <check-14 evidence="phase-41-deterministic">Policy apply/revoke/replay targets KPprotoN SNI policy and no official secret manifest apply is needed for active user issuance.</check-14>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-34-stabilization-gates>
    <gate-1>Startup replay after restore loads only active assignments and skips disabled, superseded, or revoked rows.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Runtime bridge degraded state is visible to owner/admin surfaces without blocking KrotPN login, trial, billing, or VPN APIs.</gate-2>
  </phase-34-stabilization-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">New active assignment is applied to MTProto policy runtime and returns activated status.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Backend or bridge restart replays active SNI assignments exactly once per reconciliation cycle.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Scheduled reconciliation repairs missing runtime policy state after local adapter reports drift.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Explicit admin revoke removes the runtime SNI policy while preserving the disabled assignment record.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Runtime bridge failure marks MTProto proxy pending/degraded and emits safe operator evidence.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Invalid SNI, disabled assignment, superseded assignment, or missing assignment is rejected before adapter apply calls.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Policy apply or revoke failure does not prevent normal KrotPN login, verified-email activation, billing, or VPN config retrieval.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="success">Configured backend bridge applies an issued SNI to the live mtproto-edge policy API before the user sees an active Telegram proxy link.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="success">Configured backend bridge applies an issued SNI to the private DE runtime policy API while preserving the owner proxy payload.</scenario-9>
    <scenario-10 kind="success">Adding a new Phase-41 user applies one SNI policy without restarting the DE data-plane.</scenario-10>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][LOAD_POLICY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][POLICY_APPLIED]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-044][apply_domain_policy][BRIDGE_UNAVAILABLE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-044][replay_active_assignments][REPLAY_START]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-044][replay_active_assignments][REPLAY_POLICY]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-044][replay_active_assignments][REPLAY_SUMMARY]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-044][runtime_health][BRIDGE_HEALTHY]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-044][runtime_health][BRIDGE_DEGRADED]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[M-044][sync_mtproto_policy][SCHEDULER_SYNC]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[M-044][revoke_domain_policy][REVOKE_POLICY]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[M-044][revoke_domain_policy][POLICY_REVOKED]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][POST_APPLY]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][GET_HEALTH]</marker-13>
    <marker-14>[M-050][de_policy_api][HEALTH]</marker-14>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Policy logs may include assignment id, user id, SNI, status, adapter name, retry count, and correlation id.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Never log or return full tg://proxy links, derived secret, base secret, salt, JWT/session tokens, email verification tokens, or raw adapter credentials.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Health endpoints and admin summaries must report aggregate bridge state, not per-user proxy credentials.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>policy_apply_success_count and policy_apply_failure_count, tagged by safe failure code.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>policy_replay_processed_count, policy_replay_skipped_count, and policy_replay_failed_count.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>bridge_health_status with last_success_at and last_failure_code without secret-bearing fields.</metric-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>safe-local-adapter-only</level>
    <reason>Phase-30/38 may be executed autonomously only with fake/private adapters and static smoke. Phase-37/38 live runtime rollout and public routing changes require server-side health, rollback checks, and operator Telegram proof.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: V-M-044 target tests passed locally inside the combined Phase-30 pytest run.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-14: Phase-33 runtime revoke fix added deterministic test coverage for removing an applied SNI policy.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Phase-37 added HTTP adapter coverage and live-apply provisioning regression coverage after clean-VPS Telegram Desktop reported the issued proxy as unavailable.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Phase-38 verification adds private DE policy API target gates and degraded-safe failure requirements.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution passed private DE policy URL Settings tests, existing runtime bridge tests, and trace-marker smoke for HTTP apply/health operations.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: Follow-up verification covers POLICY_LISTEN_IP-aware bootstrap URL generation after DE mtproto_proxy failed to start against hardcoded 127.0.0.1:18080.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-18: DE runtime live check passed after rebuild: policy health OK and mtproto_proxy listener open on TCP 443 while policy API remains on the private relay address.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design restores M-044 as the production policy bridge and removes official manifest sync from the active issuance path.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local tests passed for KPprotoN bridge apply/revoke/replay, scheduler replay result shape, admin runtime actions, and absence of official manifest sync in active issuance.</evidence-9>
  </evidence>
</V-M-044>
