<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-048 MODULE="M-048" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="partial-local" VERSION="1.7.0">
  <module>installer-wildcard-tls</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-35 status="partial-local">Installer flow for operator-provided wildcard TLS certificate paths, validation, env wiring, and reusable deploy installation passed local/static checks; clean VPS wildcard TLS deploy remains operator-live.</phase-35>
    <phase-36 status="partial-local">Installer/deploy flow collects Resend API key and sender settings so clean VPS registration can send verification emails; real Resend delivery remains operator-live.</phase-36>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>install.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>.env.example</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="36-designed">scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="36-designed">docs/plans/Phase-36.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-35.xml</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-048.xml</file>
    <file>docs/verification/V-M-048.xml</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1>bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py -v</command-3>
    <command-4>sh -c 'if [ -e .env ]; then DB_PASSWORD=phase35-compose-check docker compose config; else ln -s .env.example .env &amp;&amp; trap "rm -f .env" EXIT &amp;&amp; DB_PASSWORD=phase35-compose-check docker compose config; fi'</command-4>
    <command-5>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-35.xml docs/plans/Phase-36.xml docs/modules/M-048.xml docs/verification/V-M-048.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-5>
    <command-6>operator-live: prepared wildcard cert deploy on clean RU VPS, then HTTPS and MTProto-domain smoke with redacted evidence.</command-6>
    <command-7 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</command-7>
    <command-8 status="operator-live">operator-live: after Resend verifies krotpn.xyz, run one controlled-mailbox registration smoke with redacted evidence.</command-8>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>M-048 source smoke proves prompts, dynamic input validators, default paths, RU openssl bootstrap, remote certificate validation, production self-signed guard, safe cert install, deploy-generated MTProto secrets, Resend email env, and edge env wiring.</module-local>
    <wave-level>M-012 bash syntax, docker compose config, and M-046 domain TLS static tests prove installer changes do not break deploy composition or existing edge settings.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Operator-live smoke proves a clean VPS can consume prepared wildcard TLS material and serve public HTTPS without reissuing certificates.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">install.sh prompts for PUBLIC_DOMAIN, TLS_FULLCHAIN_PATH, and TLS_PRIVKEY_PATH after RU SSH connectivity is available.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Default values are krotpn.xyz, /root/krotpn-ssl/fullchain1.pem, and /root/krotpn-ssl/privkey1.pem.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Domain and path inputs reject empty values, newlines, command substitution, shell metacharacters, and relative cert paths.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Operator source certificate paths under /opt/KrotPN are rejected before clone can delete them.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Installer remote preflight bootstraps openssl/ca-certificates on clean RU hosts when supported package managers are available.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="deterministic">Remote validation rejects missing files, unreadable files, empty files, expired certs, mismatched cert/key pairs, and missing base-domain or wildcard SAN coverage.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="deterministic">Cert/key match uses public-key fingerprints or equivalent non-secret output and never prints private-key material.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="deterministic">deploy/deploy-on-server.sh installs validated cert material to /opt/KrotPN/ssl/server.crt and /opt/KrotPN/ssl/server.key with safe permissions.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="deterministic">The deploy script aborts before docker compose changes when TLS validation fails.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="deterministic">Production deploy does not silently generate self-signed certificates when operator wildcard TLS is expected.</check-10>
    <check-11 evidence="deterministic">Generated .env uses the operator domain for DOMAIN, FRONTEND_URL, CORS origins, MTPROTO_BASE_DOMAIN, EDGE_PUBLIC_DOMAIN, EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_PATH, EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_KEY_PATH, and EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_MODE.</check-11>
    <check-12 evidence="deterministic">Generated .env includes deploy-created non-empty 32-hex MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX and MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT values without printing them.</check-12>
    <check-13 evidence="phase-36-designed">Generated .env includes EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL=https://api.resend.com/emails, EMAIL_FROM=noreply@krotpn.xyz, and EMAIL_VERIFICATION_URL_BASE for the selected domain.</check-13>
    <check-14 evidence="deterministic">nginx canonical host, wildcard host, and mounted cert paths match the operator-selected domain and /etc/nginx/ssl/server.* contract.</check-14>
    <check-15 evidence="static-redaction">No verification output, installer logs, deploy logs, XML files, or smoke scripts print private key contents or Resend API key.</check-15>
    <check-16 evidence="live-required">Clean VPS smoke proves HTTP redirect, HTTPS frontend/API/admin, trusted cert chain, MTProto SNI readiness, and Resend-backed registration email delivery with prepared wildcard TLS.</check-16>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-matrix>
    <gate-1 MODULES="M-048,M-012" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Installer UX collects domain and certificate paths only after RU SSH connectivity can support remote validation.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 MODULES="M-048" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Invalid certificate material fails closed before /opt/KrotPN/ssl replacement and before compose/service mutation.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 MODULES="M-048,M-046" EVIDENCE="deterministic+static">Validated wildcard TLS is wired to backend/frontend/admin edge env and nginx cert mount paths.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 MODULES="M-048,M-012" EVIDENCE="static-redaction">Secret-bearing material is never printed or embedded in verification artifacts.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 MODULES="M-048,M-046,M-044" EVIDENCE="live-required">Prepared wildcard TLS supports public HTTPS and leaves MTProto shared-443 proof under the existing live gate.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 MODULES="M-048,M-012,M-001" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Installer/deploy Resend env wiring is sufficient for backend Settings to enable email provider delivery.</gate-6>
    <gate-7 MODULES="M-048,M-040,M-041" EVIDENCE="operator-live">Clean VPS registration sends a verification email through Resend after the domain is verified.</gate-7>
  </verification-matrix>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Operator places /root/krotpn-ssl/fullchain1.pem and /root/krotpn-ssl/privkey1.pem on RU, accepts default krotpn.xyz prompts, and deploy completes with trusted TLS paths.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Operator reruns install with the same valid cert paths and the deploy preserves or atomically refreshes TLS material without reissuing certificates.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Operator enters a non-default production domain and the installer validates base-domain plus wildcard SAN coverage for that domain.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Wrong file path or permission issue aborts before docker compose changes.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Mismatched key, expired cert, or SAN mismatch aborts before replacing /opt/KrotPN/ssl files.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Invalid domain/path input containing shell metacharacters is rejected before remote command construction.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Self-signed fallback is unavailable in production mode unless explicitly selected for dev/test.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">A certificate source path under /opt/KrotPN is rejected because installer clone refreshes that directory.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="failure">Blank MTProto secret env values must not make backend restart-loop; deploy should generate them and backend should treat blanks as missing config.</scenario-9>
    <scenario-10 kind="failure">Blank or missing Resend API key is rejected before clean deploy claims verified-registration email readiness.</scenario-10>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-048][installer_tls][PROMPT_DOMAIN]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-048][installer_tls][VALIDATE_INPUTS]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-048][installer_tls][VALIDATE_CERT_PATHS]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-048][installer_tls][VALIDATE_CERT_KEY_MATCH]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-048][installer_tls][VALIDATE_SAN]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-048][deploy_tls][INSTALL_CERT]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-048][deploy_tls][ABORT_BEFORE_DEPLOY]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-048][deploy_tls][ENV_WIRING]</marker-8>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never print private key contents, certificate PEM bodies, .env secrets, RESEND_API_KEY, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, JWTs, refresh tokens, or email verification tokens.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Logs may include the domain, redacted paths, certificate issuer, notAfter date, and validation status.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Operator-live evidence must redact server passwords and should not include full shell traces around secret-handling commands.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>installer_tls_validation_result tagged by reason without secret-bearing labels.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>installer_tls_certificate_expiry_days logged as a bounded numeric value without PEM output.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>deploy_tls_install_result tagged success, preserved, replaced, or aborted.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>edge_domain_config_result tagged by canonical host only.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>self_signed_fallback_attempt_count tagged dev-mode or blocked-production.</metric-5>
    <metric-6>deploy_resend_config_result tagged configured, missing-key, invalid-sender, or redacted without API key value.</metric-6>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <live-smoke-gates>
    <gate-1>DNS for krotpn.xyz points to the target RU edge host.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Wildcard certificate files are present on RU before install starts.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Installer validation passes without printing private key contents.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>openssl s_client or equivalent confirms the public certificate chain, issuer, SAN coverage, and expiry for the canonical host.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>curl -I http://krotpn.xyz returns a redirect to https://krotpn.xyz.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>HTTPS frontend, /api health, and /admin route respond with the trusted wildcard certificate.</gate-6>
    <gate-7>One issued MTProto SNI under the wildcard domain is ready for the existing M-046/M-044 live smoke.</gate-7>
    <gate-8>krotpn.xyz domain is verified in Resend and noreply@krotpn.xyz is accepted as the production sender.</gate-8>
    <gate-9>A controlled mailbox receives one registration verification email and logs contain no Resend API key, verification token, or full verification URL.</gate-9>
  </live-smoke-gates>
  <failure-handoff>
    <item-1>If local static smoke fails, fix installer/deploy contract drift before running any live VPS install.</item-1>
    <item-2>If remote cert validation fails live, preserve the existing /opt/KrotPN/ssl files and report the redacted failure reason.</item-2>
    <item-3>If public HTTPS smoke fails after deploy, roll back to the previous /opt/KrotPN/ssl files and nginx config before testing MTProto shared 443.</item-3>
    <item-4>If Resend rejects the key or sender, leave active user access unissued, preserve deployment state, and return an operator-safe provider configuration failure.</item-4>
  </failure-handoff>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>planned-static-plus-operator-live</level>
    <safe-local>bash syntax checks, source static smoke, Phase-36 Resend deploy smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint are safe locally.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Real cert files, live DNS, clean VPS install, public HTTPS smoke, verified Resend domain, live mailbox receipt, and MTProto client proof require operator control.</requires-operator>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh passed locally.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: node scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs passed locally.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-17: backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py passed locally with 7 tests.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-17: docker compose config passed using local env handling; Docker reported only the existing obsolete version warning.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>Operator-live clean VPS deploy with prepared wildcard cert files remains required before full production closure.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-17: Reviewer follow-up added RU openssl bootstrap, /opt/KrotPN source-path rejection, and dynamic validator checks in scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-17: Live clean VPS backend unhealthy failure fixed by generating MTProto secrets in deploy/deploy-on-server.sh and adding smoke guards against blank deploy values.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-17: Phase-36 planning scoped Resend API key installer/deploy wiring after clean VPS registration hit Email provider is disabled.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-17: Phase-36 verification design added Resend installer/deploy smoke, backend settings gate, and controlled-mailbox live gate.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-05-17: Phase-36 local execution passed bash syntax and scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs; live clean VPS Resend mailbox smoke remains blocked on operator API key and domain verification.</evidence-10>
  </evidence>
</V-M-048>
