<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-060 MODULE="M-060" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase43-pass-local-phase79" PHASE-79="pass-local" VERSION="1.4.0">
  <purpose>Verify MTProto admin abuse alerts, operator review states, and confirmation-safe enforcement actions.</purpose>
  <module-ref>M-060</module-ref>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_analytics_api.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local-phase79">scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Alert model/service tests prove dedupe, state transitions, severity mapping, and safe payloads.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run with V-M-056 to prove high/critical abuse signals create alerts and with V-M-047/V-M-026 to prove actions are audited.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Admin UI cannot close until open alert badges, alert list, review drawer, and confirmation actions are visible on mobile.</phase-level>
    <phase-79-level>No alert creation path may enforce access changes; only explicit admin-confirmed action routes may disable a proxy or apply a TTL IP block.</phase-79-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Only high and critical abuse signals create operator alerts by default; low/medium remain stored as observe-only signals and are hidden from the operator UI by M-058.</check-1>
    <check-2>Dedupe key prevents repeated scheduler runs from flooding the admin inbox.</check-2>
    <check-3>Acknowledge and resolve state transitions record admin id and timestamps without changing runtime access.</check-3>
    <check-4>Disable proxy delegates to M-047 revoke and marks the alert action outcome after confirmation.</check-4>
    <check-5>TTL IP block refuses untrusted or stale IP evidence and requires double confirmation.</check-5>
    <check-6>Reviewed disable/resolve/IP-block actions move alerts out of the open inbox and preserve them for archive review.</check-6>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-79-checks status="pass-local">
    <check-1>Creating or deduping an alert does not change assignment status, revoke proxy credentials, update runtime block state, or resolve the alert automatically.</check-1>
    <check-2>Proxy disable remains available only through an admin-confirmed route and affects only the selected assignment.</check-2>
    <check-3>TTL IP block remains available only through an admin-confirmed route with trusted M-061 client-IP evidence and explicit TTL.</check-3>
    <check-4>Acknowledge and resolve remain review/archival actions and do not perform hidden disable or hidden IP-block side effects.</check-4>
    <check-5>Audit payloads remain safe: no proxy secrets, full tg links, promotion tag values, raw private keys, or copied raw IP payloads.</check-5>
  </phase-79-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>High or critical abuse signals create exactly one open admin alert per dedupe key.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Repeated scanner runs update the existing alert instead of flooding the inbox.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Admin can acknowledge and resolve alerts without changing runtime access.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Disable proxy action requires confirmation, revokes only the selected assignment, and writes an audit-safe event.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>TTL IP block action requires double confirmation and refuses to run without trusted M-061 client IP evidence.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Alert payloads do not contain tg links, proxy secrets, runtime tokens, private keys, or copied raw IP strings.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7>After a confirmed IP block, the alert status is resolved and action metadata is available to the archive.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 phase="79-pass-local">Hard MTProto abuse creates an open admin alert while the user proxy remains usable until the administrator chooses a confirmed action.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 phase="79-pass-local">Normal promo-sharing activity produces no open hard-abuse alert and no automatic disable or IP-block state.</scenario-9>
  </scenarios>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_analytics_api.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/verification/V-M-060.xml docs/modules/M-060.xml docs/plans/Phase-43.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml</command>
  </commands>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Alert list payloads may include assignment id, user id, user email under admin policy, signal type, metric, threshold, severity, and timestamps.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Alert payloads must not copy raw IP strings, tg links, proxy secrets, runtime tokens, or private keys.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Audit details must reference IP observation ids or hash prefixes, not decrypted raw IP strings.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <log-markers>
    <marker>[M-060][create_abuse_alert][ALERT_CREATED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-060][create_abuse_alert][ALERT_DEDUPED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-060][acknowledge_alert][ALERT_ACKNOWLEDGED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-060][resolve_alert][ALERT_RESOLVED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-047][admin_mtproto_alert_action][CONFIRM_ACTION]</marker>
    <marker>[M-060][block_ip][CONFIRM_TTL_BLOCK]</marker>
  </log-markers>
  <acceptance>
    <item-1>Admin alert inbox shows open high/critical abuse signals dynamically.</item-1>
    <item-2>Alert actions never auto-punish without explicit admin confirmation.</item-2>
    <item-3>Audit records contain safe identifiers and action reasons, not raw secrets or copied raw IP payloads.</item-3>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>pass-local 2026-06-06: alert lifecycle, dedupe, acknowledge/resolve, hard-abuse handoff, mobile-IP false-positive guard, stale-IP block rejection, recorded TTL block with resolved archive state, admin API action routes, frontend-admin build, Phase-43 static smoke, and Phase-79 no-auto-enforcement checks passed.</evidence>
  <phase-79-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py -v; node scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</commands>
    <acceptance>Alert creation, acknowledgement, dedupe, and archive movement remain advisory until explicit admin-confirmed disable-proxy or TTL IP-block actions run.</acceptance>
    <evidence>PASS local 2026-06-06: backend MTProto admin-alert and analytics tests prove alert creation/review does not auto-disable assignments or create blocked IP rows.</evidence>
  </phase-79-verification-design>
</V-M-060>
