<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-050 MODULE="M-050" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-live-phase41-pass-local-phase47-short-suffix" VERSION="1.9.0">
  <module>mtproto-de-backed-edge</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-38 status="partial-live">DE-hosted MTProto runtime plus RU public TCP 443 SNI router passed live RU/DE edge checks; Phase-41 supersedes the remaining Phase-38 Telegram acceptance gap.</phase-38>
    <phase-41 status="pass-live">DE-backed edge returns to KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI routing, removes official MTProxy from the active production target, fixes blank ad-tag req_pq timeout, and passes operator Telegram Desktop/mobile proof.</phase-41>
    <phase-47 status="pass-local-short-suffix">CTA-issued hostnames are routed by the same RU SNI router MTProto ACL as legacy u-* hostnames; the fix preserves existing 7-hex CTA labels and accepts new 4-hex CTA labels.</phase-47>
    <supersedes>M-049 RU-only runtime path is superseded; Phase-38/41 verifies the replacement DE-backed traffic path.</supersedes>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py</file>
    <file phase="38-pass-local">backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
    <file phase="47-hotfix-pass-local">scripts/phase47-mtproto-cta-links-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/haproxy-phase38.cfg</file>
    <file>deploy/sni-router-telemetry.py</file>
    <file>deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl</file>
    <file>install.sh</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-38.xml</file>
    <file phase="41-pass-local">docs/plans/Phase-41.xml</file>
    <file phase="41-pass-local">scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1>bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</command-1>
    <command-2 status="pass-local">sh -c 'if [ -e .env ]; then DB_PASSWORD=phase38-compose-check docker compose config; else ln -s .env.example .env &amp;&amp; trap "rm -f .env" EXIT &amp;&amp; DB_PASSWORD=phase38-compose-check docker compose config; fi'</command-2>
    <command-3>node scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</command-3>
    <command-4>node scripts/phase47-mtproto-cta-links-smoke.mjs</command-4>
    <command-5>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py -v</command-5>
    <command-6>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/modules/M-012.xml docs/modules/M-043.xml docs/modules/M-044.xml docs/modules/M-046.xml docs/modules/M-048.xml docs/modules/M-049.xml docs/modules/M-050.xml docs/modules/M-065.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml docs/plans/Phase-47.xml docs/verification/V-M-012.xml docs/verification/V-M-043.xml docs/verification/V-M-044.xml docs/verification/V-M-046.xml docs/verification/V-M-048.xml docs/verification/V-M-049.xml docs/verification/V-M-050.xml docs/verification/V-M-065.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint</command-6>
    <command-7 status="pass-live">operator-live: RU SNI router owns public TCP 443, RU nginx fallback works, DE MTProto runtime listens, private policy API rejects public access, active SNI replay succeeds, mtp_ping marks the issued proxy available, and Telegram Desktop/mobile user retest passed.</command-7>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Static contract tests and smoke scripts prove the intended config shape: one RU public 443 owner, web SNI to RU nginx fallback, MTProto SNI to DE runtime, private policy API, no blank runtime secrets, and no secret leakage.</module-local>
    <wave-level>M-012, M-043, M-044, M-046, M-048, M-049, and M-050 gates run together because deploy, assignment stability, policy apply, TLS, routing, and runtime ownership are one production behavior.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Operator-live evidence on RU and DE proves HTTPS, private policy health, assignment replay, DE Telegram upstream reachability, and Telegram Desktop availability.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">RU public TCP 443 has exactly one configured owner, the SNI router, and the compose service grants explicit low-port bind permission.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Web SNI names krotpn.xyz and www.krotpn.xyz route to private RU nginx HTTPS fallback on 9443.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Issued MTProto wildcard SNI names route to the DE MTProto runtime target and unknown SNI has an explicit safe fallback or reject behavior.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">DE runtime env contains non-empty base secret, salt, runtime token, TLS paths, policy bind address, and proxy port values.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Backend bridge uses a private DE policy API URL with bearer token auth and redacts token, base secret, salt, derived secret, and full tg link material.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="deterministic">Existing assignments are replayed to the DE runtime without reissue, SNI mutation, base secret rotation, or salt rotation.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="deterministic">Deploy/static smoke rejects public DE policy API exposure on 0.0.0.0 unless paired with an explicit deny-public firewall/private-bind gate.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="deterministic">Wildcard cert/key delivery to DE is validated or copied through a redaction-safe path and never printed in logs, XML evidence, or smoke output.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="trace">Required route and policy log markers exist for web route, MTProto route, DE runtime start, DE policy health, policy apply, and degraded apply failure.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="operator-live">RU public HTTPS remains healthy through the SNI router after public 443 ownership changes.</check-10>
    <check-11 evidence="operator-live" status="passed">DE runtime reaches Telegram upstream and Telegram Desktop/mobile mark the issued proxy available and usable.</check-11>
    <check-12 evidence="deterministic">Direct https://krotpn.xyz:8443/login serves the admin frontend, not the user frontend.</check-12>
    <check-13 evidence="deterministic">DE mtproto_proxy bootstrap endpoints use the configured private POLICY_LISTEN_IP so the proxy listener can start while the policy API remains private.</check-13>
    <check-14 evidence="phase-41-deterministic">Issued u-*.krotpn.xyz SNI routes to DE KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime while official MTProxy is not the active target.</check-14>
    <check-15 evidence="operator-live" status="passed">MTPROTO_AD_TAG/PROXY_AD_TAG is non-empty and defaults to zero 32-hex tag; issued-link mtp_ping returns OK across DC +1 through +5 after policy replay.</check-15>
    <check-16 evidence="deterministic">RU SNI router emits local syslog observations to 127.0.0.1:1514 with issued SNI capture so M-055 can store real client IPs before DE proxying.</check-16>
    <check-17 evidence="live-hotfix">DE awg-quick@awg0 is enabled for boot and the runtime waits for POLICY_LISTEN_IP before binding the private policy API.</check-17>
    <check-18 evidence="deterministic" status="pass-local-phase47-short-suffix">RU SNI router MTProto ACL matches legacy u-12hex hostnames, new CTA-prefix-4hex hostnames such as hochu-bystree-xxxx.krotpn.xyz, and existing CTA-prefix-7hex hostnames such as hochu-bystree-xxxxxxx.krotpn.xyz.</check-18>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-matrix>
    <gate-1 MODULES="M-050,M-046" EVIDENCE="deterministic">SNI router target map separates web, issued MTProto SNI, and unknown SNI behavior.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 MODULES="M-050,M-048,M-012" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Deploy/install contract creates or preserves Phase-38 env values without printing tokens, private key material, or raw .env contents.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 MODULES="M-050,M-044" EVIDENCE="deterministic">HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter can apply, revoke, and health-check a private DE policy API target and return degraded state when unavailable.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 MODULES="M-050,M-043,M-049" EVIDENCE="deterministic">Existing assignment SNI, base secret, salt, and tg links remain stable while runtime target changes from RU-only to DE-backed.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 MODULES="M-050,M-046" EVIDENCE="operator-live" STATUS="passed">Public HTTPS, API, admin, and registration surfaces remain healthy after RU public 443 is moved to the SNI router.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 MODULES="M-050" EVIDENCE="operator-live" STATUS="passed">Telegram Desktop/mobile mark an existing issued user proxy available and usable through the DE runtime route.</gate-6>
    <gate-7 MODULES="M-050,M-052" EVIDENCE="phase-41-deterministic">Official MTProxy route is disabled from production traffic after KPprotoN fake-TLS rollback.</gate-7>
    <gate-8 MODULES="M-050,M-055,M-061" EVIDENCE="deterministic">RU SNI-router real client IP observation is wired without sending PROXY protocol into the DE MTProto listener.</gate-8>
    <gate-9 MODULES="M-050,M-065" EVIDENCE="deterministic" STATUS="passed-local">Phase-47 4-hex and existing 7-hex CTA-issued SNI labels route to mtproto_de_runtime and unknown SNI remains on HTTPS fallback.</gate-9>
  </verification-matrix>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Browser request for krotpn.xyz routes from RU public 443 to private RU nginx 9443 and returns a healthy HTTPS page.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Telegram request for an issued user SNI routes from RU public 443 to DE MTProto runtime and becomes available in Telegram Desktop.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Backend startup replay loads all active assignment policies into the DE runtime after backend, runtime, or server restart.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Admin health shows a redacted DE-backed runtime state with aggregate counts only.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">DE policy API unavailable returns degraded MTProto state and does not claim an active usable proxy.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Public access to DE policy API is rejected by private bind, firewall, token auth, or all three.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">SNI router bind conflict or bad route classification rolls back to nginx-only public 443 before user traffic is advertised.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">Missing TLS material, expired wildcard certificate, or key mismatch aborts before replacing live edge roles.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="success">Phase-41 routes a newly issued fake-TLS SNI to DE KPprotoN runtime and keeps krotpn.xyz HTTPS on web fallback.</scenario-9>
    <scenario-10 kind="success">RU SNI router observes the user device IP and issued SNI locally while the DE runtime may only see the RU router hop.</scenario-10>
    <scenario-11 kind="success">After RU/DE reboot, DE awg0 returns automatically, policy health becomes reachable, and scheduler replay reapplies all active SNI policies without reissue.</scenario-11>
    <scenario-12 kind="success">Telegram request for a new CTA-issued hostname such as hochu-bystree-b405.krotpn.xyz or an existing 7-hex CTA hostname routes from RU public 443 to DE KPprotoN instead of HTTPS fallback.</scenario-12>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-050][ru_sni_router][ROUTE_WEB]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-050][ru_sni_router][ROUTE_MTPROTO]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-050][ru_sni_router][ROUTE_UNKNOWN_SNI]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-050][de_mtproto_runtime][START_RUNTIME]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-050][de_policy_api][HEALTH]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-050][de_policy_api][DENY_PUBLIC]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][POST_APPLY]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-044][HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter][GET_HEALTH]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[M-043][get_or_create_assignment_payload][APPLY_RUNTIME_POLICY]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[M-046][edge_contract][ROLLBACK_READY]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[M-055][ru_sni_router][CLIENT_IP_OBSERVATION]</marker-11>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never print MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, derived fake-TLS secrets, full tg links, private keys, JWTs, refresh tokens, Resend API keys, email verification tokens, or raw .env contents.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Live evidence may include role names, port ownership, status codes, aggregate policy counts, certificate issuer/expiry, and redacted SNI suffixes only.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Operator evidence must redact server passwords and should not include full shell traces around certificate, token, or .env materialization.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>phase38_sni_route_count tagged by route_type web, mtproto, or unknown without full SNI labels.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>phase38_policy_apply_count tagged success, degraded, auth_failed, timeout, or unreachable.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>phase38_policy_replay_count tagged applied, skipped, failed, or unchanged.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>phase38_edge_health_status tagged ru_router, ru_nginx_fallback, de_runtime, or de_policy_api.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>phase38_rollback_trigger_count tagged by safe failure code.</metric-5>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <live-smoke-gates>
    <gate-1>RU ss output shows public TCP 443 owned by the SNI router, nginx private HTTPS fallback on 9443, and public admin TLS on 8443.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>DE ss output shows MTProto runtime listening on its configured target port.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>RU backend policy health succeeds to DE over the private path with the runtime token.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Public internet cannot access the DE policy API.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 status="passed">curl https://krotpn.xyz returns a healthy frontend response without TLS bypass.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 status="passed">Backend/API/admin and registration email surfaces remain healthy after the router change.</gate-6>
    <gate-7 status="passed">Existing active assignment SNI replay returns success and policy count is non-zero.</gate-7>
    <gate-8 status="passed">Operator Telegram Desktop/mobile retest marks the proxy available and usable.</gate-8>
    <gate-9 status="passed">Phase-41 clean deploy proves official MTProxy is not the active DE data-plane and KPprotoN runtime owns the issued SNI path.</gate-9>
  </live-smoke-gates>
  <failure-handoff>
    <item-1>If static SNI router smoke fails, do not touch live public 443; fix config shape locally first.</item-1>
    <item-2>If DE runtime starts but policy API is public, stop rollout and close the policy API before Telegram testing.</item-2>
    <item-3>If HTTPS fails after router activation, restore nginx-only public 443 before continuing MTProto checks.</item-3>
    <item-4>If Telegram Desktop remains unavailable while DE runtime and policy apply are healthy, collect redacted DE runtime logs and Telegram upstream reachability evidence before changing assignment secrets.</item-4>
  </failure-handoff>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>local-plus-operator-live-verified</level>
    <safe-local>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, static smoke, syntax checks, compose config, and backend tests with fake/private policy targets.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Future public 443 routing changes, DE runtime rollout changes, wildcard certificate/private key replacement, firewall changes, private policy API live proof, and Telegram Desktop/mobile proof.</requires-operator>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-18: Local Phase-38 execution added HAProxy RU SNI router, default compose public-443 owner, DE runtime compose template, private POLICY_LISTEN_IP runtime bind, private DE policy URL validation, deploy-time DE runtime rollout, and secret-preserving .env generation.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-18: Local verification passed: bash -n install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh; docker compose config with .env.example; node scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs; backend pytest wave for runtime bridge, provisioning, domain TLS edge, Phase-38 settings, and Phase-38 deploy static tests; rebar3 compile.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>Earlier operator-live gates for clean VPS deploy, RU public HTTPS through SNI router, DE runtime listener, private policy API denial from public internet, assignment replay, and Telegram Desktop available status are closed by Phase-41 pass-live evidence.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Clean VPS follow-up fixed live regressions by adding HAProxy low-port bind permissions and separating admin 8443 from the SNI-router web fallback on private 9443.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: DE runtime follow-up fixed mtproto_proxy startup against private policy bind by replacing the hardcoded 127.0.0.1 bootstrap URL with POLICY_LISTEN_IP-derived bootstrap URLs.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: Live verification passed: RU public 443 serves KrotPN through HAProxy, RU public 8443/login serves KrotPN Admin, nginx private fallback listens on 127.0.0.1:9443, DE runtime listens on 0.0.0.0:443, private policy health returns OK, RU can reach DE 443, and HAProxy reports mtproto_de_runtime UP.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design restores M-050 to KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI routing and marks official MTProxy routing as superseded for production.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local execution passed deploy static tests and smoke for active haproxy-phase38 SNI routing, KPprotoN DE runtime compose, admin 8443 preservation, and official MTProxy production inactivity.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Live fix on DE showed vanilla mtproto_proxy passes req_pq only with a valid tag; KrotPN DE runtime with zero 32-hex tag, active assignment replay, RU SNI route, and issued u-*.krotpn.xyz link passed mtp_ping on DC +1 through +5.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy validation confirmed RU public web, admin, VPN, and Telegram Desktop/mobile MTProto proxy behavior work from the Phase-41 edge.</evidence-10>
    <evidence-11>2026-05-21: Local fix added HAProxy local syslog SNI/client-IP observation, host collector service, static smoke coverage, and backend IP observability tests for real client IP history.</evidence-11>
    <evidence-12>2026-05-23: Live RU/DE reboot diagnosis found DE awg0 was not enabled for boot; enabling awg-quick@awg0 restored policy health and active assignment replay applied both existing user SNIs.</evidence-12>
    <evidence-13>2026-06-01: Phase-47 CTA routing hotfix passed locally: Phase-38, Phase-41, and Phase-47 smoke scripts plus backend deploy static/provisioning/edge tests prove approved CTA labels reach mtproto_de_runtime while web/unknown SNI remains safe.</evidence-13>
    <evidence-14>2026-06-01: Short-suffix follow-up passed locally: router smoke and backend static guards now cover new 4-hex CTA labels, existing 7-hex CTA labels, legacy u-12hex labels, and 5-hex rejection.</evidence-14>
  </evidence>
</V-M-050>
