<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-056 MODULE="M-056" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase43-pass-local-phase79" PHASE-43="pass-local" PHASE-79="pass-local" VERSION="1.5.0">
  <module>mtproto-analytics-service</module>
  <checks>Analytics service produces accurate summaries, top users, usage windows, runtime health, availability proof state, and observe-only abuse signals from M-054 data.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_scheduler.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local-phase79">scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-06: cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py tests/test_mtproto_promotion_tag.py -v; node scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</commands>
  <evidence>Analytics service tests cover summary/top users/timeseries/storage budget, IP_OBSERVATION no-inflation, hard-abuse alert handoff, mobile-IP false-positive guard, promo-sharing many-IP observe-only behavior, and hard concurrent multi-IP alert-only handoff; alert regression passed.</evidence>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Use deterministic M-054 fixtures to verify summaries, windowed rollups, top-user ordering, active sessions, stale telemetry, and observe-only abuse classifiers.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run after V-M-054/V-M-055 so analytics consumes the real planned persistence and runtime ingestion shapes.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Admin API and UI gates cannot close unless M-056 returns all metrics requested by the operator without raw secrets or payload-level Telegram data.</phase-level>
    <phase-43-level>Phase-43 requires graph-ready timeseries, storage-budget summaries, high/critical abuse alert handoff to M-060, and no automatic enforcement.</phase-43-level>
    <phase-79-level>Phase-79 requires promo-sharing and many-IP churn to remain observe-only while high/critical alert handoff requires hard combined evidence.</phase-79-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <phase-43-checks>
    <check-1>Timeseries buckets are stable for hour/day ranges and include traffic, active connections, connections, duration, and errors.</check-1>
    <check-2>Top users supports longer limits up to 100 and keeps deterministic ordering under ties.</check-2>
    <check-3>High/critical abuse signals call M-060 alert creation once per dedupe key.</check-3>
    <check-4>Storage-budget summary reports raw event, session, rollup, alert, and IP-observation retention windows.</check-4>
    <check-5>Current/last IP summaries come from M-061 and are absent rather than guessed when source data is unavailable.</check-5>
    <check-6>Many-IP churn without strong concurrent multi-IP activity remains a medium signal and does not create an admin alert.</check-6>
  </phase-43-checks>
  <phase-79-checks status="pass-local">
    <check-1>Individual MTProto proxy sharing for promotion is an allowed use case and does not create high/critical abuse by IP count alone.</check-1>
    <check-2>Many distinct client IPs over time produce observe-only low/medium signals with observe_only=true and no M-060 alert handoff.</check-2>
    <check-3>High/critical alert handoff requires strong evidence such as concurrent multi-IP activity combined with extreme traffic or repeated protocol errors.</check-3>
    <check-4>Alert handoff never mutates assignment status, runtime policy, IP block lists, SNI, promotion tag, base secret, salt, or issued proxy links.</check-4>
    <check-5>Tests must include a normal promo-sharing fixture, a mobile-network churn fixture, and a hard-abuse fixture with deterministic thresholds.</check-5>
  </phase-79-checks>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Global summary returns issued proxy total, active/disabled/reissue_required counts, active connections, runtime health, and availability proof state.</check-1>
    <check-2>Per-assignment summary returns last_seen, traffic, duration, connection count, errors, active sessions, and current abuse signals.</check-2>
    <check-3>Day, week, month, and custom time windows calculate stable totals from rollups and raw recent events.</check-3>
    <check-4>Top users rank deterministically by traffic, duration, connection count, and error count with stable tie-breaking.</check-4>
    <check-5>Abuse signals detect too many IP hashes, too many concurrent sessions, traffic spikes, and repeated failures without disabling access.</check-5>
    <check-6>Missing or stale runtime telemetry is explicit and never rendered as false zero usage.</check-6>
    <check-7>Queries avoid N+1 scans for summary, top users, and per-assignment drill-down.</check-7>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Global summary returns issued proxy totals, active status counts, active connections, runtime health, and availability proof state.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Per-assignment summary returns last seen, traffic, duration, connection count, errors, and active sessions.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Top users ranking is stable for traffic, duration, connection count, and errors across selected time windows.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Abuse signals detect many IP hashes, high concurrency, traffic spikes, and repeated failures without disabling access.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Unknown/rejected SNI activity is visible globally but cannot be misattributed to a user.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Phase-43 graph requests return bucketed data without scanning unbounded raw events.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7>High/critical abuse creates an admin alert but does not disable proxy access automatically.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 phase="79-pass-local">A user shares the proxy link for promo visibility; many clients connect over time; analytics records usage and IP metadata but does not mark the proxy for automatic punishment.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 phase="79-pass-local">One assignment shows many simultaneous IPs plus extreme traffic or repeated errors; analytics emits a high/critical alert handoff only, leaving enforcement to M-060/admin confirmation.</scenario-9>
  </scenarios>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Analytics outputs include only internal ids, masked SNI, counters, states, and safe timestamps.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>No Telegram chats, channels, message contents, contacts, Telegram user ids, full proxy links, or secrets are inferred or returned.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker>[M-056][build_global_summary][SUMMARY]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][build_assignment_usage][USAGE_DETAIL]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][build_top_users][TOP_USERS]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][detect_abuse_signals][OBSERVE_ONLY]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][build_global_summary][STALE_TELEMETRY]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][build_timeseries][TIMESERIES]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][detect_abuse_signals][ALERT_HANDOFF]</marker>
    <marker>[M-056][build_storage_budget][RETENTION_BUDGET]</marker>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>Pure service tests may use fixture-backed repositories and disposable databases.</safe-local>
    <blocked-live>Threshold tuning that would affect automatic enforcement remains out of scope; Phase-43 still requires admin-reviewed action.</blocked-live>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-79-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py -v; node scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</commands>
    <acceptance>Promo-sharing and many-IP churn remain observe-only; hard abuse creates alert handoff only; no automatic proxy disable, IP block, runtime mutation, or promotion tag/link rotation occurs.</acceptance>
    <evidence>PASS local 2026-06-06: tests/test_mtproto_analytics_service.py, tests/test_mtproto_admin_alerts.py, tests/test_mtproto_promotion_tag.py, and Phase-79 smoke passed.</evidence>
  </phase-79-verification-design>
</V-M-056>
