<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-068 MODULE="M-068" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase53-phase54-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase72-regression-pass-local-phase73-phase74-planned" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-68="pass-local" PHASE-72-REGRESSION="pass-local" PHASE-73="pass-local" PHASE-74="planned">
  <purpose>Verify Phase-50 canonical paid tariffs across billing catalog convergence, YooKassa payment creation, subscription activation, device-limit policy, and compact user/admin UI.</purpose>
  <checks>Exactly three canonical active tariffs, server-authoritative prices, idempotent clean-deploy upsert, downgrade guard, correct payment metadata, paid subscription activation, device-limit enforcement, user/admin UI rendering, and unchanged deploy/install surfaces.</checks>
  <evidence-priority>
    <level-1>Deterministic assertions first: exact canonical tariff matrix, no duplicate upsert, server-derived payment amount, webhook subscription state, and device-limit boundaries.</level-1>
    <level-2>Trace assertions second: secret-free markers for catalog upsert, checkout validation, downgrade rejection, payment creation, and paid subscription update.</level-2>
    <level-3>Integration checks third: frontend build, frontend-admin build, static smoke, XML/MyGRACE, and protected deploy/install guard.</level-3>
  </evidence-priority>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_tariff_catalog.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_plan_api.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_service.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_device_access_policy.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/i18n/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="54-pass-local">scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="68-pass-local">scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="73-pass-local">scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="74-planned">scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_billing_tariff_catalog.py tests/test_billing_plan_api.py tests/test_billing_service.py tests/test_device_access_policy.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="pass-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-50.xml docs/modules/M-068.xml docs/verification/V-M-068.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
    <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
    <command status="pass-local">git diff --check</command>
    <command status="pass-local">git diff --name-only HEAD -- install.sh docker-compose.yml nginx deploy deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml .env.example produced no output</command>
    <command status="planned-phase74">node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs; protected guard must prove backend billing/user tariff/deploy/runtime surfaces unchanged while admin Tariffs UI is removed.</command>
  </commands>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Canonical catalog defines only krotpn-1, krotpn-6, and krotpn-9 as active paid storefront plans.</check-1>
    <check-2>Prices are 369, 693, and 936 RUB; duration is 30 days; device limits are 1, 6, and 9.</check-2>
    <check-3>Startup or migration convergence is idempotent and does not duplicate plan rows across backend restarts.</check-3>
    <check-4>Payment creation accepts only plan_id from the user and derives all money-sensitive fields server-side.</check-4>
    <check-5>YooKassa payload amount values are 369.00, 693.00, and 936.00 and metadata contains only non-secret plan/payment identifiers.</check-5>
    <check-6>Checkout blocks lower device-limit plans when consumed active or blocked device slots exceed the target plan limit.</check-6>
    <check-7>Paid webhook activation cancels pending trials, preserves paid-subscription non-regression, and exposes the correct effective device limit.</check-7>
    <check-8>User /subscription renders exactly three compact tariff cards with Russian labels, price, duration, device limit, current usage, and popular marker.</check-8>
    <check-9>Admin Plans renders a compact canonical tariff matrix and does not expose accidental canonical delete/edit actions.</check-9>
    <check-10>Phase-50 does not change install.sh, deploy scripts, docker-compose, nginx, TLS material, VPN runtime, or MTProto runtime.</check-10>
    <check-11>Phase-53 subscription Matrix UI renders exactly three user-facing tariff cards with canonical 369/693/936 RUB prices and 1/6/9 device limits.</check-11>
    <check-12>Phase-53 visual refactor does not allow frontend-provided price, duration, currency, or device limit to affect checkout.</check-12>
    <check-13>Phase-54 admin Plans Matrix UI preserves the three canonical tariffs, prices, durations, device limits, active/popular state, and protected non-CRUD controls.</check-13>
    <check-14>Phase-54 admin Plans layout remains readable at mobile widths without nested card bloat or horizontal document overflow.</check-14>
    <check-15>Phase-54 does not introduce frontend-admin controls that can override canonical price, duration, currency, device_limit, or payment amount.</check-15>
    <check-16>Phase-74 removes the admin Tariffs/Plans visible UI only; canonical backend tariffs and user-facing tariff purchase cards remain unchanged.</check-16>
    <check-17>Phase-74 smoke must fail if backend/app/billing, billing tests, user SubscriptionPanel/Subscription page, checkout shape, canonical slugs, prices, duration, or device limits drift.</check-17>
    <check-18>Phase-74 direct admin /plans handling must not expose accidental canonical CRUD controls or stale plan cards after the nav removal.</check-18>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-54-admin-plans-ui-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>/plans renders exactly KrotPN 1, KrotPN 6, and KrotPN 9 with 369, 693, and 936 RUB prices and device limits 1, 6, and 9.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Canonical tariff rows/cards use compact Matrix styling, readable badges, and stable dimensions at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, and 1440x900.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Admin can inspect canonical tariff state but cannot delete/edit canonical plans unless a later backend/admin phase explicitly approves CRUD.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Smoke fails if stale placeholder CRUD copy, wrong prices, wrong device limits, duplicate canonical plans, or frontend-controlled money fields appear.</gate-4>
  </phase-54-admin-plans-ui-gates>
  <phase-74-admin-tariff-removal-gates status="planned">
    <gate-1>Admin panel must not show a visible "Тарифы" navigation item or a stale Plans card/route entry point.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Admin /plans direct access must be handled safely without breaking build or exposing edit/delete controls.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Public billing plans API, canonical catalog, YooKassa checkout, device-limit policy, and user-facing tariff cards must remain identical to Phase-68/73 state.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-50 and Phase-68 tariff smokes remain required regression gates whenever Phase-74 touches admin plan UI references.</gate-4>
  </phase-74-admin-tariff-removal-gates>
  <phase-53-subscription-ui-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Matrix tariff cards remain compact and readable at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, and 1440x900.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Current usage, selected plan, popular marker, duration, price, and device limit text do not overlap buttons or adjacent cards.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Checkout CTA sends only plan_id through the existing frontend API binding.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-53 smoke fails on stale placeholder plan copy, missing canonical tariffs, non-Russian visible tariff labels, or protected deploy/install drift.</gate-4>
  </phase-53-subscription-ui-gates>
  <phase-50-gates>
    <gate-1>Public GET /api/v1/billing/plans returns exactly krotpn-1, krotpn-6, and krotpn-9 in sort order with price, currency, duration_days, device_limit, slug, active status, and popular marker.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Admin plan response exposes slug, is_active, is_popular, sort_order, price, currency, duration_days, and device_limit; frontend-admin build fails if the type contract drifts.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Canonical upsert can run repeatedly on clean or existing databases and leaves exactly one active row per canonical slug with current approved values.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Checkout accepts plan_id only from the user-facing request and rejects inactive, noncanonical, stale, or lower-limit incompatible plans before YooKassa payment creation.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>YooKassa create-payment request uses server-derived amount strings and metadata; frontend tampering with price, duration, currency, or device_limit cannot affect provider payload.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Succeeded webhook cancels pending trial, activates or extends paid subscription, preserves paid-subscription non-regression, and exposes the selected device limit to M-021.</gate-6>
    <gate-7>Device policy enforces 1, 6, and 9 active slots and blocks the next over-limit provisioning attempt with a deterministic error.</gate-7>
    <gate-8>Phase-50 static smoke fails if the user/admin UI shows fewer or more than three tariffs, stale plan CRUD placeholder copy, non-Russian labels, or missing protected-surface guard.</gate-8>
    <gate-9>Any diff under install.sh, deploy, docker-compose.yml, nginx, TLS material, VPN runtime topology, or MTProto runtime topology blocks Phase-50 completion.</gate-9>
  </phase-50-gates>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Backend tests cover catalog convergence, API payloads, checkout validation, YooKassa amount/metadata, webhook activation, and device-limit enforcement.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Frontend and frontend-admin builds plus Phase-50 smoke cover compact tariff presentation and API type compatibility.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/install diff guard cover metadata integrity and operational isolation.</phase-level>
    <live-optional>Operator clean-deploy validation may confirm the three tariffs render in both panels and a test payment reaches YooKassa with the expected amount.</live-optional>
  </verification-levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success" trace="TARIFF_CATALOG_UPSERT">Clean DB startup creates exactly three canonical paid tariffs.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success" trace="TARIFF_CATALOG_UPSERT">Repeated startup updates canonical fields without creating duplicates.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success" trace="BILLING_PAYMENT_CREATED">KrotPN 6 checkout creates a 693.00 RUB YooKassa payment from backend-derived plan data.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success" trace="BILLING_SUBSCRIPTION_UPDATED">Succeeded webhook activates paid subscription and effective device limit 6.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success" trace="VPN_DEVICE_LIMIT_REJECTED">A one-device paid plan rejects the second active device.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure" trace="TARIFF_DOWNGRADE_BLOCKED">User with six consumed slots cannot start checkout for the one-device tariff.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Frontend price tampering cannot alter backend payment amount, duration, currency, or device limit.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">Any deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/TLS/runtime diff appears during Phase-50.</scenario-8>
  </scenarios>
  <required-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-068][tariff_catalog][TARIFF_CATALOG_UPSERT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-068][checkout][TARIFF_CHECKOUT_VALIDATED]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-068][checkout][TARIFF_DOWNGRADE_BLOCKED]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[BillingService][create_payment][BILLING_PAYMENT_CREATED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[BillingService][process_payment_webhook][BILLING_SUBSCRIPTION_UPDATED]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-068][phase53_tariff_ui][CANONICAL_TARIFFS_VISIBLE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-068][phase53_tariff_ui][CHECKOUT_SHAPE_PRESERVED]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-068][phase54_admin_tariff_ui][CANONICAL_TARIFFS_READABLE]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[M-068][phase54_admin_tariff_ui][NO_CANONICAL_CRUD_DRIFT]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[TariffCatalog][phase74][ADMIN_TARIFF_UI_REMOVED_ONLY]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[TariffCatalog][phase74][CANONICAL_TARIFFS_PRESERVED]</marker-11>
  </required-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Do not log YooKassa secret keys, raw Authorization headers, JWTs, payment provider credentials, email tokens, TLS private keys, VPN config bodies, MTProto secrets, or full user identifiers during Phase-50 verification.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Payment metadata may include plan slug, plan_id, payment_id, user_id, duration_days, and device_limit; no secrets or raw provider credentials may be stored in payment_metadata.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <evidence>
    <phase-53-local-2026-06-03>Frontend build and node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs passed for Matrix tariff UI, canonical slug/price/device-limit preservation, plan_id-only checkout shape, and protected deploy/install isolation.</phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>Phase-54 verification design added admin Plans Matrix UI gates for canonical tariff readability, no canonical CRUD drift, mobile compactness, and no frontend money-field control.</phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>Phase-54 smoke passed for admin Plans Matrix readability, canonical 369/693/936 RUB prices, 1/6/9 device limits, no canonical CRUD controls, no frontend money-field control, and protected deploy/install guard.</phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-68-local-2026-06-04>Phase-68 frontend smoke and Phase-50 tariff smoke passed after user-visible tariff aliases changed to KrotPN Self, KrotPN Family, and KrotPN Team while canonical slugs, prices, device limits, and plan_id-only checkout remained unchanged.</phase-68-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-72-regression-2026-06-05>Phase-68 dashboard/subscription smoke was aligned to i18n-backed pending-copy rendering after Phase-72 Russian-only Settings cleanup and passed without tariff catalog, checkout, price, device-limit, or admin plan-surface drift.</phase-72-regression-2026-06-05>
  </evidence>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Allowed after Phase-50 verification approval because the scope is limited to billing catalog, payment validation, device-limit policy, UI presentation, tests, docs, and protected-surface guards.</autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-68-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>User-visible tariff presentation verification for dashboard subscription merge.</scope>
    <gate-1>Frontend tariff cards must display KrotPN Self, KrotPN Family, and KrotPN Team.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Displayed descriptions must be "Персональный тариф", "Тариф для семьи", and "Тариф для команды".</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Canonical plan IDs, prices 369/693/936 RUB, 1/6/9 device limits, and backend checkout payload must remain unchanged.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Admin canonical tariff surfaces from Phase-54 must not regress.</gate-4>
    <commands>backend billing tariff tests; cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-68-verification-design>
  <phase-73-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Tariff-aware device-limit copy verification for the user config page.</scope>
    <gate-1>Device-limit exhausted message may display the active/current tariff name but must not change canonical tariff slugs, prices, duration, device limits, checkout payload, or YooKassa metadata.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Frontend must not trust user-editable price, duration, currency, or device_limit values for enforcement; the Phase-73 tariff name is presentation-only unless backend contract is explicitly extended.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Canonical Phase-50 tariff smoke and Phase-68 tariff alias smoke remain green.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs; backend tariff/device-limit tests if API shape changes.</commands>
  </phase-73-verification-design>
  <phase-73-required-markers status="observed-local">
    <marker-1>[TariffCatalog][phase73][DISPLAY_NAME_ONLY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[TariffCatalog][phase73][DEVICE_LIMIT_MESSAGE_SAFE]</marker-2>
  </phase-73-required-markers>
  <phase-73-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">
    <command-1>node scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</command-1>
    <summary>Config page uses existing subscription plan_name only for display and maps KrotPN 1/6/9 to Self/Family/Team aliases; canonical prices, slugs, limits, checkout, YooKassa metadata, and admin tariffs were not changed.</summary>
  </phase-73-evidence>
  <phase-74-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Protect canonical paid tariffs while removing the visible admin tariff management section.</scope>
    <gate-1>Admin UI may remove Plans/Tariffs navigation and visible route entry points.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Backend catalog, user tariff UI, checkout payload, YooKassa metadata, migration behavior, and device-limit enforcement are protected no-diff surfaces.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verification must include Phase-74 admin shell smoke plus Phase-50 and Phase-68 tariff regressions.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-74-verification-design>
</V-M-068>
