<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-009 MODULE="M-009" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase46-phase51-phase52-phase53-phase56-phase59-pass-local-phase67-pass-local-session60-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase69-pass-local-phase70-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72" VERSION="1.19.0" PHASE-59="pass-local" PHASE-67="pass-local" PHASE-68="pass-local" PHASE-69="pass-local" PHASE-70="pass-local" PHASE-71="pass-local" PHASE-72="pass-local">
  <module>frontend-user</module>
  <checks>User frontend still builds, matches the Phase-28 auth API response shape, makes registration mobile-safe without implying active KrotPN trial before email verification, and resumes valid stored sessions across tabs within the 60-day idle TTL.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/VerifyEmail.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/App.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Loading.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/session.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/passwordPolicy.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/stores/auth.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/index.html</file>
    <file>frontend/vite.config.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/public/favicon.ico</file>
    <file>frontend/public/brand/email-logo.png</file>
    <file>scripts/phase28-register-flow-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="67-pass-local">scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="70-pass-local">scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="71-pass-local">scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="72-pass-local">scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/session-security-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-05: frontend build, Phase-72 smoke, and session-security smoke passed for Russian invalid-login localization, Russian-only Settings, logout-under-Settings navigation, mobile dock reachability, compact calendar, and protected-surface guard.</commands>
  <anchors>TYPESCRIPT_NO_ERRORS REGISTER_PENDING_STATE REGISTER_VERIFIED_SUCCESS REGISTER_EXPIRED_LINK REGISTER_RESEND_AVAILABLE PHASE45_SUBSCRIPTION_COUNTDOWN PHASE46_PASSWORD_EXAMPLE PHASE46_MTPROTO_LINKS PHASE51_BRAND_ASSETS PHASE52_MATRIX_VISUAL_SHELL PHASE53_USER_MATRIX_ROUTES PHASE56_PUBLIC_AUTH_ROUTES PHASE59_MATRIX_MOTION</anchors>
  <phase-28-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>Register submit handles pending/check-email response without storing access tokens or marking the user authenticated.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Verify-email route handles success, expired token, replayed token, and resend-needed states with compact mobile layouts.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Frontend copy clearly states that free trial and VPN config become available after email verification.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Existing login, refresh, logout, dashboard, config, and subscription flows continue to build against the shared API client.</gate-4>
  </phase-28-frontend-gates>
  <phase-44-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>Register pending state includes spam-folder guidance and removes stale 3-day trial/immediate VPN copy.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Forgot/reset password routes exist and bind to the Phase-44 auth API methods.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Client-side password strength hints match the backend minimum policy shape.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Duplicate-email errors show a recovery CTA.</gate-4>
  </phase-44-frontend-gates>
  <phase-45-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>Dashboard shows pending trial as config-access state without claiming the countdown has started.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Subscription page renders server-derived days/hours/minutes and active date range.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Subscription calendar highlights active dates and does not show stale 3-day trial copy.</gate-3>
  </phase-45-frontend-gates>
  <phase-46-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>Register form renders a format-only password example imported from the shared password policy helper.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Dashboard separates Telegram app tg://proxy link from browser https://t.me proxy link.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>MTProto visible labels are localized as Ссылка, Сервер, Порт, and Секрет.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>MTProto status badge refresh is bounded at 30 seconds and avoids background polling.</gate-4>
  </phase-46-frontend-gates>
  <phase-51-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>User frontend index.html references real favicon.ico and 16x16/32x32 PNG favicon fallbacks.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Vite PWA includes existing favicon and apple-touch-icon assets without referencing missing mask-icon.svg.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>User frontend public build contains pwa-192x192.png, pwa-512x512.png, and brand/email-logo.png.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Visible page logos are deferred until the planned frontend redesign; Phase-56 is the approved public/auth logo integration point.</gate-4>
  </phase-51-frontend-gates>
  <phase-52-frontend-gates>
    <gate-1>App mounts VisualShell around the existing user route tree without changing route structure, auth state, or API clients.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>MatrixBackground renders a fixed pointer-events-none canvas with resize, cleanup, fallback, and reduced-motion guards.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>User index.css exposes Matrix tokens, scanline/vignette/content layers, focus-visible rules, and reduced-motion policy.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Chrome mobile/desktop screenshots show the login shell remains readable above the Matrix layer.</gate-4>
  </phase-52-frontend-gates>
  <phase-53-frontend-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Auth screens keep existing API calls, spam hint, duplicate-email recovery CTA, password example, reset-token handling, and verification states while adopting Matrix forms.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, and settings routes build and render under VisualShell without route changes or API shape changes.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Phase-53 smoke must check 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, and 1440x900 viewports for no document-level horizontal scroll and no obvious text/control overlap.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Chrome screenshots must cover auth and reduced-motion states; protected dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings route surfaces are covered by static smoke when local preview has no authenticated backend session.</gate-4>
  </phase-53-frontend-gates>
  <phase-53-commands>
    <command-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>Chrome screenshot audit for /login, /register, /reset-password, desktop /login, and reduced-motion /login with virtual-time-budget.</command-3>
    <command-4>git diff --name-only -- install.sh deploy nginx docker-compose.yml</command-4>
  </phase-53-commands>
  <phase-53-required-markers>
    <marker-1>[FrontendUser][Phase53][BUILD_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[FrontendUser][Phase53][ROUTE_MATRIX_READY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[FrontendUser][Phase53][VIEWPORT_NO_OVERFLOW]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[FrontendUser][Phase53][AUTH_FLOW_UNCHANGED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[FrontendUser][Phase53][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-5>
  </phase-53-required-markers>
  <phase-56-frontend-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Public / route exists and protected user cabinet routes live under /dashboard with legacy redirects for /config, /subscription, /referrals, and /settings.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Landing, login, register, forgot-password, reset-password, and verify-email routes keep Matrix styling readable and show the public logo asset.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verified-email guard copy remains explicit and no access token is stored before successful verify-email.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Public tariff preview remains aligned with M-068 and does not create payment or own checkout amount/metadata.</gate-4>
  </phase-56-frontend-gates>
  <phase-56-commands>
    <command-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3>node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs</command-3>
    <command-4>node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</command-4>
    <command-5>node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</command-5>
    <command-6>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-6>
    <command-7>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-7>
    <command-8>node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</command-8>
  </phase-56-commands>
  <phase-59-frontend-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User VisualShell and MatrixBackground expose route, reduced-motion, pointer-scroll, focus, and inactive-tab lifecycle markers.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Dashboard, Config, and Referrals expose compact copy/download/proxy feedback and status transition classes without API changes.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Phase-59 smoke confirms no scroll hijack, pointer interception, long motion budget, secret logging, or protected backend/deploy/runtime diff.</gate-3>
  </phase-59-frontend-gates>
  <phase-67-frontend-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Frontend build must pass after splash/auth route changes.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>/ must render only a splash-logo flow and redirect to /login without marketing/tariff/product sections.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>/login, /register, /forgot-password, and /reset-password must preserve existing auth API calls, token storage boundaries, pending verification state, duplicate-email recovery CTA, password example, and reset-token handling.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-67 smoke must fail if visible matrix-auth-card framing, removed helper copy, visible above-field labels, or blue/cyan auth focus treatment returns.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Protected backend, deploy/install, nginx, docker-compose, VPN, MTProto, billing, and admin surfaces must remain untouched.</gate-5>
  </phase-67-frontend-gates>
  <session60-frontend-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>/login must call fetchUser for an existing valid stored session and redirect to /dashboard with replace=true.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Login and verify-email must persist tokens through persistUserSessionTokens instead of duplicating direct token writes.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>API and auth store must enforce the 60-day idle TTL and refresh last-seen timestamps on authenticated activity.</gate-3>
  </session60-frontend-gates>
  <phase-67-verification-levels>
    <module-local>Phase-67 smoke validates route wiring, removed-copy contracts, auth API/store preservation, MatrixBackground browser guards, BrandMark usage, CSS markers, and protected-surface diffs.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Phase-56 public/auth, Phase-60 QA, Phase-61 responsive, Phase-63 logo, Phase-52 visual, and Phase-59 motion smokes remain green.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Frontend build, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard pass before execution can be accepted.</phase-level>
  </phase-67-verification-levels>
  <phase-67-telemetry-requirements>
    <allowed>Route path, viewport label, selector marker, removed-copy check name, auth-flow invariant name, canvas branch, build size, and protected-surface diff summary.</allowed>
    <forbidden>Passwords, emails, access/refresh tokens, reset/verify token query values, API keys, VPN configs, MTProto secrets, proxy links, payment IDs, and server credentials.</forbidden>
  </phase-67-telemetry-requirements>
  <mobile-viewports>
    <viewport-1>360x740</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2>390x844</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3>430x932</viewport-3>
  </mobile-viewports>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success" trace="REGISTER_PENDING_STATE">Registration shows check-email state and no authenticated dashboard redirect.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success" trace="REGISTER_VERIFIED_SUCCESS">Verification success routes the user into the normal authenticated onboarding path.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure" trace="REGISTER_EXPIRED_LINK">Expired or replayed token state remains understandable and offers resend.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success" trace="TYPESCRIPT_NO_ERRORS">Frontend builds with zero TypeScript errors.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Password recovery screens build and static smoke passes.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="success">Phase-53 user route matrix renders Matrix style on auth, dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, and settings without changing API contracts.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Matrix visual redesign hides primary VPN, MTProto, subscription, password recovery, or config actions on phone viewports.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="success">Phase-67 splash/auth polish preserves frontend auth behavior while removing the landing content and visible auth card frames.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="failure">Phase-67 route polish changes backend/auth API contracts, deploy surfaces, or protected user cabinet routes.</scenario-9>
  </scenarios>
  <phase-67-autonomous-execution-safety>
    <allowed>Frontend user public/auth routes, user frontend CSS, user BrandMark/MatrixBackground/VisualShell compatibility edits, Phase-67 smoke, and MyGRACE docs.</allowed>
    <blocked>Backend auth semantics, auth API shape, protected user cabinet behavior, admin panel behavior, billing, VPN, MTProto, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, TLS/DNS, and release operations.</blocked>
    <handoff-trigger>Stop if the requested UX requires backend/API changes, a new asset not already available, or unverifiable browser behavior.</handoff-trigger>
  </phase-67-autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>2026-06-01: cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build and node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs passed for Phase-44 password recovery UX. 2026-06-01: Phase-45 frontend build and subscription UX smoke passed for pending-trial copy, countdown fields, calendar marker, and stale 3-day copy guard. 2026-06-01: Phase-46 frontend build and user-cabinet UX smoke passed for password example, dual MTProto links, Russian labels, and bounded status refresh. 2026-06-02: Phase-51 frontend build passed and brand asset smoke --expect-dist confirmed favicon/PWA/email-logo assets in dist. 2026-06-03: Phase-52 frontend build, Matrix visual smoke, and Chrome screenshots for /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion 390x844 passed. 2026-06-03: Phase-53 frontend build and node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs passed; production-preview screenshots passed for login/register/reset mobile, login desktop, and reduced-motion login with virtual-time-budget. 2026-06-03: Phase-56 frontend build, public/auth smoke, Phase-44/46/50/52/53/55 regressions, public/auth Chrome screenshot matrix, XML/MyGRACE/diff checks, and protected deploy/install guard passed. 2026-06-04: Phase-59 frontend build, motion smoke, Phase-52/55/56/57 regressions, post-commit Phase-58 smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed. 2026-06-04: Phase-67 frontend build, auth/splash smoke, Phase-44/46/52/55/56/59/60/61/62/63 regressions, browser screenshots for splash/login/register/forgot/reset desktop/mobile/reduced-motion, admin build, XML/MyGRACE checks, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed. 2026-06-04: session60 follow-up passed frontend build plus Phase-28/53/56/67/session smokes for verify-email frameless style, login stored-session redirect, and session-helper token persistence.</evidence>
  <phase-68-execution-evidence>2026-06-04: Phase-68 frontend build, dashboard/subscription smoke, Phase-45/50/53/57/62 regressions, Phase-60 QA, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed for compact dashboard ownership.</phase-68-execution-evidence>
  <phase-68-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Frontend route and API contract verification for dashboard/subscription merge.</scope>
    <gate-1>User dashboard route must request the existing auth/profile/subscription/MTProto/referral APIs without changing API paths.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>/dashboard/subscription route must remain compatible or redirect intentionally without breaking existing deep links.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Frontend API types must keep existing backend field names for plans, subscription countdown, MTProto proxy, and referral data.</gate-3>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-68-verification-design>
  <phase-69-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Frontend API and UX verification for referral bonus and masked invite identity.</scope>
    <gate-1>Referral pages must consume masked referred identity from backend or mask locally from an allowed partial field without exposing full email.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Referral bonus status must not claim active days until backend subscription state confirms activation/extension.</gate-2>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-69-verification-design>
  <phase-69-evidence status="pass-local">2026-06-04: frontend build passed; scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs passed for masked referral identity, no "Реферал #N" primary label, access_label typed API, and referral-bonus pending copy.</phase-69-evidence>
  <phase-70-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Frontend API and config route verification for QR parity.</scope>
    <gate-1>Config download, text fetch, QR modal, copy actions, and MIME-safe .conf flow must remain API-compatible.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>QR smoke and backend tests must compare rendered/frontend/backend/CLI payload sources without printing config bodies or key material.</gate-2>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-70-verification-design>
  <phase-70-evidence status="pass-local">2026-06-04: frontend build and scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs passed for level-M QR settings, preserved download/copy/config API flows, compact config page markers, and protected deploy/runtime guard.</phase-70-evidence>
  <phase-71-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Frontend API, i18n, and user-cabinet route verification for per-device config retrieval.</scope>
    <gate-1>deviceApi must expose selected-device config, download, QR, and optional Amnezia QR methods with typed responses and without breaking existing create/rotate/revoke/list APIs.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>English language mode must not leak the known hardcoded Russian strings in Settings, Config, SubscriptionPanel, and Layout controlled labels.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Frontend smokes must not print full config payloads, private keys, selected-device config text, auth tokens, or real emails.</gate-3>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-71-verification-design>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Frontend build passed; Phase-71 smoke passed for deviceApi selected-device methods, config master-detail markers, i18n cleanup, QR close icon, sticky actions, and protected deploy/runtime diff guard; Phase-70 QR parity smoke remained green.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Frontend auth and user-cabinet route verification for invalid-login localization, navigation reachability, Settings language removal, and compact calendar presentation.</scope>
    <gate-1>/login must render "Неверный логин или пароль" for invalid credentials and must not render "Invalid email or password".</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Login error mapping must remain frontend-only unless backend auth contract changes are explicitly approved.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Layout, Settings, SubscriptionPanel, Dashboard, and route registration must continue to build after removing visible language settings and adding mobile bottom navigation.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Smoke output must not print passwords, access tokens, refresh tokens, real emails, or backend auth responses containing credentials.</gate-4>
    <commands>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/session-security-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-72-verification-design>
  <phase-72-required-markers status="observed-local">
    <marker-1>[FrontendUser][phase72][LOGIN_ERROR_LOCALIZED]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[FrontendUser][phase72][LANGUAGE_SETTINGS_REMOVED]</marker-2>
  </phase-72-required-markers>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Frontend build passed; scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs passed for localized invalid-login handling, Russian-only Settings cleanup, desktop/mobile navigation markers, compact calendar markers, and protected admin/backend/deploy/runtime guard; scripts/session-security-smoke.mjs remained green.</phase-72-evidence>
</V-M-009>
