<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-071 MODULE="M-071" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase52">
  <scope>
    <phase>Phase-52</phase>
    <purpose>Verify the Matrix style system foundation for compact, readable, mobile-safe user and admin shells.</purpose>
    <module-ref>docs/modules/M-071.xml</module-ref>
  </scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-2>
    <check-3>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4>Viewport smoke: 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1440x900.</check-4>
    <check-5>Reduced-motion smoke: all transform-heavy, flicker-heavy, and scanline-heavy effects are disabled or simplified.</check-5>
    <check-6>git diff --name-only -- install.sh deploy nginx docker-compose.yml</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-53 viewport smoke: auth, dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, settings, reduced-motion dashboard, and desktop user route screenshots.</check-7>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-53-style-gates status="verification-designed">
    <gate-1>User cabinet routes use Matrix palette/tokens while preserving compact operational layout and avoiding nested cards.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>VPN config actions, QR/download/copy, MTProto secrets, countdown/calendar, tariff prices, referral links, and settings forms remain readable.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Focus states remain visible on buttons, links, inputs, segmented controls, copy actions, tariff CTAs, and navigation tabs.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Reduced-motion disables flicker-heavy/transform-heavy effects and keeps the Matrix identity as a static readable surface.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Palette review confirms cyan, magenta, amber, red, and neutral accents remain available and the UI is not a one-note green surface.</gate-5>
  </phase-53-style-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Shared Matrix tokens apply to both frontends without breaking compact operational layout rules from M-038.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">CRT scanlines, neon flicker, and glitch accents are visible but do not obscure forms, tables, proxy cards, tariffs, alerts, or primary actions.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Focus states are visible over the Matrix background for links, buttons, inputs, tabs, menus, and confirmation controls.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Mobile shells have no document-level horizontal scroll, no nested card bloat, and stable compact control dimensions.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Long emails, CTA proxy hostnames, secrets, config labels, tariff prices, and admin row actions wrap or truncate intentionally inside stable containers.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Color scan confirms the final theme is not a one-note green surface: cyan, magenta, neutral, warning, and danger accents remain available.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <visual-checks>
    <viewport-1>360x740</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2>390x844</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3>430x932</viewport-3>
    <viewport-4>768x1024</viewport-4>
    <viewport-5>1440x900</viewport-5>
    <check-1>No horizontal scroll.</check-1>
    <check-2>No icon/placeholder overlap in forms.</check-2>
    <check-3>No status badge, button, table, chart, proxy secret, or tariff text overlap.</check-3>
    <check-4>Visible focus states remain clear over Matrix background and scanline overlays.</check-4>
    <check-5>Primary VPN, MTProto, tariff, registration, and admin actions are visible and readable.</check-5>
  </visual-checks>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][TOKENS_PRESENT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][REDUCED_MOTION_POLICY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][VIEWPORT_NO_OVERFLOW]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][FOCUS_VISIBLE]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MatrixStyleSystem][smoke][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][USER_ROUTES_READABLE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][NO_TEXT_OVERLAP]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[MatrixStyleSystem][phase53][BALANCED_PALETTE]</marker-8>
  </required-log-markers>
  <evidence-levels>
    <module-local>Static smoke validates CSS tokens, class primitives, reduced-motion selectors, focus selectors, and protected-surface guard.</module-local>
    <wave-level>User and admin builds validate shared style integration in both apps.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Viewport screenshots validate readability, no overlap, no horizontal scroll, and balanced Matrix palette.</phase-level>
  </evidence-levels>
  <redaction>
    <rule-1>Visual smoke must not print real tokens, proxy secrets, tg links, VPN config contents, admin tokens, raw user IP history, or screenshot binary data.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Allowed output: route name, viewport, layout metrics, CSS selector presence, screenshot path, and redacted console marker counts.</rule-2>
  </redaction>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>medium</level>
    <allowed>Implement frontend-only CSS token system, shell classes, focus states, and smoke checks inside M-071 boundaries.</allowed>
    <blocked>Changing data contracts, auth/session storage, billing/VPN/MTProto behavior, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or backend runtime behavior.</blocked>
    <handoff-trigger>Stop and report if the theme makes operational content unreadable, creates horizontal scroll, hides primary actions, or conflicts with reduced-motion policy.</handoff-trigger>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <acceptance>
    <target-1>Frontend and frontend-admin builds pass.</target-1>
    <target-2>Phase-52 smoke passes with token, reduced-motion, viewport, focus, and protected-surface checks.</target-2>
    <target-3>Mobile and desktop screenshots show Matrix style without text overlap, control overlap, or one-note color dominance.</target-3>
    <target-4>No deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime topology changes are present.</target-4>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-3>
      <command-4>Chrome headless screenshot audit for user/admin /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion 390x844.</command-4>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-reduced-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-reduced-390x844.png</screenshot-paths>
      <viewport-review>Login shells stayed readable, Matrix layer was visible, focus and reduced-motion selectors are present, and no obvious icon/text overlap was observed on captured login viewports.</viewport-review>
      <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology diff.</protected-surface>
    </local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-53-designed-2026-06-03>
      <result>VERIFICATION_DESIGNED</result>
      <required-command>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</required-command>
      <required-proof>User cabinet route screenshots must show Matrix style without text overlap, horizontal scroll, hidden primary actions, or one-note palette dominance.</required-proof>
    </phase-53-designed-2026-06-03>
  </evidence>
</V-M-071>
