<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-028 MODULE="M-028" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase45" PHASE-43="pass-local" PHASE-44="pass-local" PHASE-45="pass-local" PHASE-69="verification-designed">
  <module>alembic-migrations</module>
  <checks>Alembic migrations apply all migrations on clean database and produce schema consistent with models. Backward compatible with existing SQLModel.create_all behavior during transition period. Phase-29 MTProto assignment migration is registered after baseline with user/SNI uniqueness indexes. Phase-43 adds encrypted MTProto IP observations, admin alerts, and TTL IP block records. Phase-44 adds password reset token persistence after Phase-43. Phase-45 adds pending trial activation fields after Phase-44.</checks>
  <test-files>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</commands>
  <anchors>ALEMBIC_MIGRATION_APPLIED</anchors>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="ALEMBIC_MIGRATION_APPLIED">alembic upgrade head applies all migrations on clean database</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="MTPROTO_ASSIGNMENT_SCHEMA">MTProto assignment migration follows baseline and contains registry schema markers</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="PHASE43_MTPROTO_OBSERVABILITY_SCHEMA">Phase-43 migration creates IP observation, admin alert, and blocked-IP record tables</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="PASSWORD_RESET_TOKEN_SCHEMA">Phase-44 migration creates password_reset_tokens after Phase-43</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="PENDING_TRIAL_SCHEMA">Phase-45 migration creates pending trial activation columns after Phase-44</scenario>
  </scenarios>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: tests/test_db_migrations.py passed as part of Phase-29 target pytest gate.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-20: tests/test_db_migrations.py passed in the Phase-43 backend wave and validates phase43_add_mtproto_ip_observability migration metadata.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: tests/test_db_migrations.py passed in Phase-44 backend suite and validates phase44_add_password_reset_tokens migration metadata.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-06-01: tests/test_db_migrations.py passed in Phase-45 backend suite and validates phase45_pending_trial_activation migration metadata plus runtime compatibility columns.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
  <phase-69-verification-design status="planned">
    <scope>Database migration verification for referral bonus state.</scope>
    <gate-1>If new columns/tables are required, migration must be reversible, deterministic, and safe on existing production rows.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Migration tests must prove existing referrals, subscriptions, and pending trials still load correctly.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Schema must support idempotency markers for paid-referral bonus processing.</gate-3>
    <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; pytest tests/test_db_migrations.py tests/test_referrals.py tests/test_trial_activation.py</commands>
  </phase-69-verification-design>
</V-M-028>
