<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-058 MODULE="M-058" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase43-phase54-pass-local-phase79" PHASE-43="pass-local" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-79="pass-local" VERSION="2.0.0">
  <module>mtproto-admin-analytics-ui</module>
  <checks>Frontend-admin exposes compact MTProto analytics, alert review, and promotion tag controls without secret leakage, visible technical Signals noise, hidden existing controls, or mobile layout regressions.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file status="pass-local">frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local">scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="phase54-pass-local">scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="pass-local-phase79">scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-06: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</commands>
  <evidence>Frontend-admin build passed and Phase-42/Phase-43/Phase-54/Phase-79 static smokes confirm compact Overview/Users/Abuse/Settings UI, removed Recent events, hidden visible Signals panel/count, paginated proxy/user lists, compact area graphs, source-IP unavailable state, auto-refresh markers, Russian hover help for alert review actions, compact scrollable IP history without visible CIDR prefixes, open inbox/archive split, no-dot empty states, promo-sharing allowed copy, manual-only enforcement copy, and redaction guards.</evidence>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Build frontend-admin and run static UI smoke for route wiring, API names, redaction strings, confirmation flows, and mobile viewport overflow.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run after V-M-057 to prove UI contracts match backend schemas for analytics and promotion tag state.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-42 cannot close unless admin can scan global and per-proxy analytics from mobile without exposing secrets or losing existing MTProto ops controls.</phase-level>
    <phase-43-level>Phase-43 cannot execute unless UI gates cover removed Recent events, Overview/Users/Abuse/Settings layout, long Top users, graphs, auto-refresh, raw-IP investigation scope, and mobile compactness.</phase-43-level>
    <phase-54-level>Phase-54 cannot close unless the Matrix admin redesign keeps MTProto analytics dense, compact, auto-refreshing, and readable without restoring visible technical Signals noise.</phase-54-level>
    <phase-79-level>Phase-79 cannot close unless visible MTProto alert copy frames sharing as expected promo usage and enforcement as manual admin action only.</phase-79-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <phase-43-checks>
    <check-1>Recent events section is absent from the visible admin MTProto analytics page.</check-1>
    <check-2>Overview, Users, Abuse, and Settings surfaces fit mobile widths without nested cards or horizontal overflow.</check-2>
    <check-3>Top users supports 25, 50, and 100 item views with scrollable compact rows.</check-3>
    <check-4>User detail drawer shows issued_at, last_seen_at, current IP, last IP, all IPs for 90 days, sessions, traffic, duration, and errors.</check-4>
    <check-5>Graphs render traffic, connections, active connections, duration, and errors without layout shift during auto-refresh.</check-5>
    <check-6>CPU/RAM/runtime metric tiles auto-refresh and show stale/unavailable states clearly.</check-6>
    <check-7>Raw IP strings render only inside the admin investigation drawer and are excluded from static smoke fixtures, summaries, and logs.</check-7>
    <check-8>Assignment inventory and user investigation search expose bounded page sizes with next/previous controls for large proxy sets.</check-8>
    <check-9>Abuse open inbox queries only open alerts and archive surfaces acknowledged/resolved alert history.</check-9>
    <check-10>Abuse empty states are padded for readability and do not end with stray punctuation.</check-10>
    <check-11>Visible technical Signals panel/count is absent from the admin MTProto UI while alert APIs remain wired.</check-11>
    <check-12>Open alert action buttons expose short Russian hover descriptions for review, acknowledge, resolve, disable, and follow-up TTL IP block decisions.</check-12>
    <check-13>IP history uses a bounded internal scroll area and renders only address/hash rows, not address/prefix mask rows.</check-13>
  </phase-43-checks>
  <phase-79-checks status="pass-local">
    <check-1>Open Abuse/Alerts copy must make clear that normal proxy sharing for promotion is allowed and alerts are hard-abuse candidates for admin review.</check-1>
    <check-2>The visible UI must not render technical Signals panels, signal counters, auto-block wording, auto-disable wording, or any implication that sharing is punished automatically.</check-2>
    <check-3>Disable proxy and TTL IP block buttons remain explicit admin actions with confirmation and Russian hover help before the operator clicks.</check-3>
    <check-4>Archive behavior remains intact: resolved/acknowledged/actioned alerts leave the open inbox but remain reviewable.</check-4>
    <check-5>Redaction smoke must reject full proxy links, fake-TLS secrets, raw promotion tags, runtime tokens, and raw IP values outside the explicit investigation drawer.</check-5>
  </phase-79-checks>
  <phase-54-checks status="pass-local">
    <check-1>Matrix /mtproto analytics keeps Overview, Users, Abuse, and Settings tabs compact and reachable on mobile.</check-1>
    <check-2>Graphs for traffic, connections, active connections, duration, and errors render in stable bounded containers without layout shift during refresh.</check-2>
    <check-3>Top users remains long-list friendly through page-size controls or bounded scroll, not unstructured document scrolling.</check-3>
    <check-4>User investigation drawer keeps issued time, last seen, current IP, last IP, IP history, sessions, graph data, and errors readable with internal scrolling.</check-4>
    <check-5>Abuse shows only Alerts plus Archive; visible technical Signals panel/count remains absent.</check-5>
    <check-6>Promotion tag control shows masked current tag, validation state, pending_restart/applied/failed state, and confirmation copy without raw tag leakage.</check-6>
    <check-7>Resource CPU/RAM/runtime metrics auto-refresh and show stale/unavailable states without resizing Matrix panels.</check-7>
    <check-8>Raw IP values are limited to the explicit investigation drawer and remain excluded from smoke logs, general cards, and screenshots when fixtures can use masked data.</check-8>
  </phase-54-checks>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Admin can scan global summary, traffic windows, top users, active connections, errors, runtime health, and availability proof on mobile.</check-1>
    <check-2>Per-proxy detail exposes last seen, session count, duration, traffic, errors, and alert context without hiding reissue/revoke controls.</check-2>
    <check-3>Filters for day, week, month, event type, status, and assignment do not cause horizontal overflow at 360px width.</check-3>
    <check-4>Technical abuse signals are not rendered as a separate visible admin panel; only high/critical Alerts plus Archive are shown.</check-4>
    <check-5>Promotion tag editing requires explicit confirmation and renders only masked current tag after save.</check-5>
    <check-6>Static smoke confirms no full tg links, fake-TLS secrets, runtime tokens, raw promotion tags, or raw IP values render in the UI bundle.</check-6>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Admin can scan global summary, traffic windows, top users, active connections, and error counts on mobile.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Per-proxy detail is reachable without hiding reissue/revoke controls.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Admin opens Abuse and sees only Alerts plus Archive, without the technical Signals list or signal counter.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>Static smoke confirms no full tg links, secrets, tokens, raw promotion tags, or raw IP values render in the UI.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Promotion tag form handles valid, invalid, pending_restart, applied, and failed states.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Phase-43 admin opens a high-abuse alert, reviews user/IP/session detail, and disables the selected proxy through confirmation UI.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7>Auto-refresh updates summary, alerts, top users, graph data, and resource metrics without duplicating requests or resizing controls.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8>Admin acknowledges, resolves, disables, or blocks from an alert; the alert leaves the open list and remains reviewable in the archive.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9>Phase-54 admin scans MTProto analytics on a phone and can still drill into one user without losing the overview context.</scenario-9>
    <scenario-10>Phase-54 visual effects do not obscure CPU/RAM runtime metrics, availability proof, alert action buttons, or promotion tag status.</scenario-10>
    <scenario-11 phase="79-pass-local">Admin sees a high/critical alert and understands it is a manual-review candidate; no UI copy says the proxy or IP was automatically blocked.</scenario-11>
    <scenario-12 phase="79-pass-local">Admin investigates a heavily shared promo proxy and still sees usage/IP history without a visible technical Signals panel or automatic punishment state.</scenario-12>
  </scenarios>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>UI renders masked SNI and masked promotion tags only.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Full proxy links remain limited to user-owned cabinet flows, not admin analytics lists.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Raw IP values may appear only in explicit admin investigation drawer fixtures; runtime token, full tag, base secret, salt, private keys, and proxy secrets may never appear in generated bundles or page render fixtures.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][REDACTED_RENDER]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][FILTER_USAGE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][PROMOTION_TAG_CONFIRM]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][RECENT_EVENTS_REMOVED]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][USER_DETAIL_DRAWER]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][AUTO_REFRESH]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][ALERT_REVIEW]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][ALERT_ARCHIVE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][ALERT_ACTION_TOOLTIP]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][admin_mtproto_analytics_ui][COMPACT_IP_HISTORY]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][phase54_mtproto_analytics][CHARTS_TABLES_READABLE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][phase54_mtproto_analytics][AUTO_REFRESH_STABLE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][phase54_mtproto_analytics][SIGNALS_STILL_HIDDEN]</marker>
    <marker>[M-058][phase54_mtproto_analytics][PROMOTION_TAG_REDACTED]</marker>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <safe-local>Frontend build and static smoke are safe to run locally.</safe-local>
    <blocked-live>Visual/live admin validation against production data requires operator approval and redacted screenshots only.</blocked-live>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>Phase-54 verification design added Matrix analytics gates for compact tabs, stable graphs, top-users list, alert inbox/archive, IP history, resource metrics, promotion tag redaction, auto-refresh, and no visible Signals regression.</phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>Frontend-admin build and Phase-54 smoke passed for compact Matrix analytics: CHARTS_TABLES_READABLE, AUTO_REFRESH_STABLE, SIGNALS_STILL_HIDDEN, PROMOTION_TAG_REDACTED, bounded user/top-user/alert/IP-history lists, and protected-surface isolation.</phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-79-local-2026-06-06>Frontend-admin build and Phase-79 smoke passed for promo-safe alert copy, hidden visible Signals, manual-only enforcement wording, promotion tag redaction, and no full proxy-link exposure.</phase-79-local-2026-06-06>
  </evidence>
  <phase-79-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <commands>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</commands>
    <acceptance>MTProto admin Abuse UI stays compact and redacted, keeps Signals hidden, presents sharing as expected promotion behavior, and exposes only manual confirmed enforcement actions.</acceptance>
    <evidence>PASS local 2026-06-06: admin build and Phase-43/54/79 smokes passed.</evidence>
  </phase-79-verification-design>
</V-M-058>
