<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-010 MODULE="M-010" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase51-phase52-phase54-phase59-pass-local-minimal-login-pass-local-phase74-pass-local-phase75" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-59="pass-local" PHASE-74="pass-local" PHASE-75="pass-local" VERSION="1.11.0">
  <module>frontend-admin</module>
  <checks>Admin frontend builds and reflects current admin, Full Tunnel, system, analytics, and device-control surfaces without auth regression.</checks>
  <test-files>frontend-admin/index.html frontend-admin/public/favicon.ico frontend-admin/public/favicon-16x16.png frontend-admin/public/favicon-32x32.png frontend-admin/public/apple-touch-icon.png frontend-admin/src/main.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts frontend-admin/src/stores/auth.ts frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts frontend-admin/src/index.css scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs</test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-05: frontend-admin build and Phase-75 admin Users/Devices smoke passed for unified Users inventory, no visible Devices nav, safe /devices redirect, expanded device rows, confirmation guards, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend guard.</commands>
  <levels>
    <module-local>Run npm build after frontend-admin route, component, API binding, or type changes.</module-local>
    <wave-level>During Phase-24, pair the build with V-M-037 mobile smoke for /, /users, /devices, and /analytics.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Frontend-admin remains pass only if auth guard, route registration, and admin API bindings compile after compact UI changes.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Routes /login, /, /users, /devices, /servers, /plans, and /analytics remain registered.</check-1>
    <check-2>Layout, Dashboard, Users, Devices, Analytics, Servers, and Plans compile against current types.</check-2>
    <check-3>adminApi base path remains /api/v1 unless a separate backend/API migration is approved.</check-3>
    <check-4>Device API binding names remain getDevices, blockDevice, unblockDevice, rotateDevice, and revokeDevice.</check-4>
    <check-5>Phase-24 does not change auth/session storage behavior; M-039 owns that in Phase-25.</check-5>
    <check-6>Admin auth store clears admin_refresh_token whenever admin_token is cleared.</check-6>
    <check-7>Admin login email/password fields do not expose stale default credential placeholders.</check-7>
    <check-8>Admin inputs with left icons use shared icon padding so the icon and placeholder/value text cannot overlap.</check-8>
    <check-9>Admin index.html references real favicon.ico and PNG fallbacks from frontend-admin public assets.</check-9>
    <check-10>No visible admin layout logo is added before the planned frontend redesign phase.</check-10>
    <check-11>Admin main mounts VisualShell around the existing route tree without changing auth state, API clients, or route registration.</check-11>
    <check-12>Admin index.css exposes Matrix tokens, pointer-safe visual layers, focus-visible rules, and reduced-motion policy.</check-12>
    <check-13>Phase-74 intentionally supersedes the Phase-54 visible /plans route requirement: /plans is registered only as a safe redirect to / and must not show a visible admin Tariffs page.</check-13>
    <check-14>Phase-54 admin UI changes preserve adminApi base path, endpoint names, auth store behavior, and React Query mutation boundaries.</check-14>
    <check-15>Phase-54 smoke confirms compact Matrix surfaces do not create document-level horizontal overflow or icon/text/control overlap on mobile.</check-15>
    <check-16>Phase-54 protected-surface guard confirms install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, docker-compose.yml, and runtime topology stay unchanged.</check-16>
    <check-17>Phase-59 motion smoke confirms admin feedback/status transitions, reduced-motion fallback, pointer-scroll/focus safety, and protected backend/deploy/runtime isolation.</check-17>
    <check-18>Admin /login is minimal: large unframed logo, email/password inputs, error state, submit action, no route-card strip, no helper paragraphs, and no default credential hints.</check-18>
    <check-19>Phase-74 intentionally supersedes the old visible admin /plans navigation requirement: "Тарифы" must be removed from admin UI only.</check-19>
    <check-20>Phase-74 admin login inputs must keep icon-safe padding for placeholder and typed values in email/password fields.</check-20>
    <check-21>Phase-74 admin logout must render directly under "Ноды" while preserving existing token cleanup and auth role gates.</check-21>
    <check-22>Phase-74 admin main content must scroll normally under mouse wheel when the cursor is over content, not only over the rail.</check-22>
    <check-23>Phase-74 admin rail must be bounded/clipped to the same visible height budget as the main admin content surface.</check-23>
    <check-24>Phase-74 direct /plans handling must be safe without leaving a visible stale Tariffs card or broken route.</check-24>
    <check-25>Phase-75 must expose a single visible admin "Пользователи" inventory that includes expandable per-user devices.</check-25>
    <check-26>Phase-75 must remove the separate visible "Устройства" admin navigation entry after those actions are reachable inside /users.</check-26>
    <check-27>Phase-75 direct /devices handling must be safe redirect or compatibility route, never a stale duplicate primary inventory.</check-27>
    <check-28>Phase-75 Users page must load or group device rows by user_id, show loading/empty/error states, and keep the list bounded for many devices.</check-28>
    <check-29>Phase-75 device action controls must preserve adminApi blockDevice, unblockDevice, rotateDevice, and revokeDevice mutation boundaries.</check-29>
    <check-30>Phase-75 smoke must prove frontend-admin build, unified route/navigation markers, expandable device rows, action confirmations, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend guard.</check-30>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-54-admin-route-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Login uses Matrix shell, empty email/password fields, icon padding safety, visible focus states, and no stale default credential hints.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Protected layout exposes compact navigation to dashboard, users, devices, MTProto, servers, plans, and analytics without horizontal scroll.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Dashboard, users, devices, servers, plans, analytics, and MTProto pages compile against current types and remain operational rather than marketing-like.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Admin destructive actions remain confirmation-safe and keyboard reachable after visual redesign.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Evidence must include static route smoke for protected admin routes when no authenticated local backend session is available.</gate-5>
  </phase-54-admin-route-gates>
  <phase-74-admin-shell-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed after route/nav/layout/login changes.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs passed for icon-safe admin login fields, no visible "Тарифы" nav, safe /plans handling, logout directly under "Ноды", content scroll markers, and rail bounds.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Phase-54/58/59/61/62 regressions remain required final-run gates so admin route compaction, motion, responsiveness, and deletion-audit contracts stay valid after the controlled Tariffs removal.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Protected guard in Phase-74 smoke proved backend billing, user-facing tariff cards, deploy/install, nginx, docker-compose, VPN runtime, and MTProto runtime are unchanged.</gate-4>
  </phase-74-admin-shell-gates>
  <phase-75-admin-unified-inventory-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build is mandatory after Users/Layout/main/api/type changes.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>node scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs must assert one visible Users inventory, no visible Devices nav, safe /devices redirect/compat handling, expandable user rows, and bounded device lists.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>The smoke must assert that block/unblock/rotate/revoke are still reachable through expanded user device rows and that no mutation runs before confirmation.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-54, Phase-58, Phase-59, Phase-61, Phase-62, and Phase-74 regressions remain final-run gates after the merge.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Protected guard must prove deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/VPN runtime/MTProto runtime/user frontend surfaces are unchanged; backend admin changes are allowed only for an approved minimal read-only device endpoint.</gate-5>
  </phase-75-admin-unified-inventory-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Admin login route and protected layout still build after compact UI changes.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Dashboard, users, devices, servers, plans, and analytics routes compile against existing admin API bindings.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">A frontend-admin UI simplification changes auth, admin API base path, or backend endpoint shape without approval.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">A compact navigation change drops /devices, /users, or /analytics from the registered protected route surface.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Phase-54 visual changes hide MTProto, Plans, Users, Devices, or Servers workflows behind decorative Matrix effects.</scenario-5>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[FrontendAdmin][Phase54][BUILD_PASS]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[FrontendAdmin][Phase54][ROUTE_MATRIX_READY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[FrontendAdmin][Phase54][VIEWPORT_NO_OVERFLOW]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[FrontendAdmin][Phase54][ADMIN_FLOW_UNCHANGED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[FrontendAdmin][Phase54][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MatrixMotion][phase59][MICROINTERACTIONS_READY]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[FrontendAdmin][fix][MINIMAL_LOGIN_READY]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[FrontendAdmin][phase74][LOGIN_ICON_PADDING_SAFE]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[FrontendAdmin][phase74][NO_TARIFFS_NAV]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[FrontendAdmin][phase74][PLANS_ROUTE_SAFE]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[FrontendAdmin][phase74][PROTECTED_ADMIN_API_UNCHANGED]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[FrontendAdmin][phase75][USERS_DEVICES_UNIFIED]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[FrontendAdmin][phase75][NO_DEVICES_NAV]</marker-13>
    <marker-14>[FrontendAdmin][phase75][DEVICES_ROUTE_SAFE]</marker-14>
    <marker-15>[FrontendAdmin][phase75][EXPANDABLE_USER_DEVICE_ROWS]</marker-15>
    <marker-16>[FrontendAdmin][phase75][PROTECTED_ADMIN_API_GUARD]</marker-16>
  </required-log-markers>
  <observability>
    <telemetry-1>Build evidence records command, exit code, and failing TypeScript/Vite output if any.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>Do not record real admin tokens, refresh tokens, Authorization headers, or cookies in frontend-admin evidence.</telemetry-2>
  </observability>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-10: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed after Phase-24 compact admin UI changes.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-10: Route/API binding static guard confirmed /users, /devices, /analytics, /api/v1, and existing device endpoint names.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-10: Phase-25 admin refresh compatibility fix added; rebuild required by V-M-039/V-M-010.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-10: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed after admin refresh-token persistence cleanup.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-21: Local admin UI fix removed login placeholders, removed stale admin@krotpn.com fallback copy, and passed frontend-admin build.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-02: Phase-51 frontend-admin build passed and brand asset smoke --expect-dist confirmed admin favicon assets in dist.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-06-03: Phase-52 frontend-admin build, Matrix visual smoke, and Chrome screenshots for admin /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion 390x844 passed.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-06-03: Phase-54 verification design added admin route, build, viewport, redaction, confirmation, and protected-surface gates before execution.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-06-03: Phase-54 local execution passed frontend-admin build and scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs; route registration, compact Matrix primitives, bounded lists, MTProto redaction, canonical Plans readonly guard, reduced-motion markers, and protected deploy/install guard passed.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-06-04: Phase-59 frontend-admin build, scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs, and post-commit scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs passed; admin feedback/status motion markers are present and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</evidence-10>
    <evidence-11>2026-06-04: Admin login follow-up removes the Phase-54 hero strip and helper copy, keeps only visible logo, inputs, error state, and Войти action, and updates Phase-54 smoke to lock that minimal surface.</evidence-11>
    <evidence-12>2026-06-05: Phase-74 frontend-admin build and admin shell smoke passed; Login has Phase-74 icon-safe fields, Layout has no visible Tariffs nav, main redirects /plans to /, Logout is under Nodes, and admin content/rail scroll markers are present.</evidence-12>
    <evidence-13>2026-06-05: Phase-75 frontend-admin build and scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs passed; Users groups AdminDevice rows by user_id, Layout removes visible Devices nav, main redirects /devices to /users, and confirmation-safe device actions stay inside expanded user rows.</evidence-13>
  </evidence>
</V-M-010>
