<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-062 MODULE="M-062" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase46-phase51">
  <purpose>Verify Phase-44 email onboarding, password policy, password reset, and duplicate-email UX without changing deploy/install scripts.</purpose>
  <checks>Branded email templates render safely, registration copy is accurate, weak passwords are rejected, reset tokens are one-time and TTL-bound, duplicate registration offers recovery, and secrets/tokens remain redacted.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_verified_registration.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_password_recovery.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <phase-44-gates>
    <gate-1>Verification and reset emails include branded HTML and text fallback while never logging full links or tokens.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Pending-registration UI tells users to check spam and contains no stale "trial на 3 дня" or immediate VPN claim.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Strong-password validation is deterministic for registration and reset flows on backend and frontend.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Password reset request, success, expired, replay, and invalid token states are covered.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Duplicate-email registration returns a clear account-exists message with reset CTA and no extra side effects.</gate-5>
    <gate-6>Deploy/install scripts show no diff.</gate-6>
  </phase-44-gates>
  <phase-46-gates>
    <gate-1>Password policy helper exports a format-only example that satisfies the active frontend policy.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Registration UI displays the example while clearly telling users not to reuse it literally.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>passwordStrengthIssues remains the registration validation gate; backend policy is unchanged.</gate-3>
  </phase-46-gates>
  <phase-51-gates>
    <gate-1>Verification and reset HTML emails render the public KrotPN email-logo image from FRONTEND_URL.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Text fallbacks do not include the email-logo URL and stay focused on one-time action links.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Email body logo rendering remains separate from provider-side BIMI sender-avatar behavior.</gate-3>
  </phase-51-gates>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Email template rendering, password-strength policy, reset token lifecycle, and duplicate-email side-effect guards are tested with deterministic backend assertions.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Auth/email/frontend surfaces are verified together so API response shape, UI copy, and provider redaction do not drift.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Backend tests, frontend build, static UX smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and no deploy/install diff guard must all pass before Phase-44 is closed.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Strong-password registration sends branded verification email and shows spam-folder guidance.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="failure">Weak-password registration is rejected before pending registration or provider send side effects.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Password reset token changes password once and authenticates with the new password.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Expired or replayed reset token cannot change password again.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Existing-email registration suggests password recovery without creating duplicate pending access.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="success">Verification/reset HTML body contains the public KrotPN logo while token handling and text fallback stay unchanged.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[EmailTemplates][build_verification_template][RENDER_BRANDED_VERIFICATION]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[EmailTemplates][build_password_reset_template][RENDER_PASSWORD_RESET]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[UsersService][validate_password_strength][POLICY_CHECK]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[UsersRouter][request_password_reset][CREATE_RESET_TOKEN]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[UsersRouter][reset_password][CONSUME_RESET_TOKEN]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[VerifiedRegistration][register][DUPLICATE_EMAIL_RECOVERY]</marker-6>
  </required-log-markers>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_email_delivery.py tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_password_recovery.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase44-auth-email-ux-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-44.xml docs/modules/M-062.xml docs/modules/M-002.xml docs/modules/M-009.xml docs/modules/M-028.xml docs/modules/M-040.xml docs/verification/V-M-062.xml docs/verification/V-M-002.xml docs/verification/V-M-009.xml docs/verification/V-M-028.xml docs/verification/V-M-040.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/requirements.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
    <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
  </commands>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-06-01: backend Phase-44 auth/email/migration suite passed outside sandbox because sandbox aiosqlite in-memory DB hangs; result was 29 passed in 0.84s.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-06-01: frontend npm run build passed.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: Phase-44 auth/email UX smoke passed.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-06-01: XML parse and MyGRACE lint passed.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-06-01: deploy/install diff guard passed by review; no deploy/install files changed.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-01: Phase-46 frontend build and UX smoke passed for safe password format example without backend policy changes.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-06-02: backend email delivery tests and Phase-51 smoke passed for shared verification/reset action-email logo rendering without text fallback noise or token leaks.</evidence-7>
  </evidence>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <metric-1>Password reset request, success, invalid, expired, and replay outcomes are counted without raw email, token, provider body, or IP leakage.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Email provider failures are normalized with provider code/category only; bearer keys, message bodies, and links stay redacted.</metric-2>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <redaction>
    <item-1>No verification token, reset token, Resend API key, bearer header, or full verification/reset link may appear in logs, test output, or smoke output.</item-1>
    <item-2>Provider errors are normalized before reaching user-facing responses.</item-2>
  </redaction>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Safe for local autonomous execute after explicit user approval because the scope is app/frontend only and excludes deploy/install. Block execution if password reset storage lacks migration coverage, if any token is stored raw, or if duplicate-email handling creates active access side effects.</autonomous-execution-safety>
</V-M-062>
