<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-061 MODULE="M-061" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase43" VERSION="1.2.0">
  <purpose>Verify encrypted admin-only MTProto client IP observability and 90-day retention.</purpose>
  <module-ref>M-061</module-ref>
  <test-files>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_ip_observability.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py</file>
    <file status="pass-local">backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Repository/model tests prove encryption, upsert, active/current/last derivation, redaction, and 90-day retention.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Run with V-M-054/V-M-055 so runtime IP telemetry flows into encrypted IP observation storage without breaking usage events.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Run with V-M-057/V-M-058 so only explicit admin investigation APIs and UI drawer can show decrypted IP values.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Encrypted IP ciphertext differs from plaintext and cannot be queried through general analytics serializers.</check-1>
    <check-2>HMAC hash and coarse prefix remain available for abuse detection without decrypting raw IP.</check-2>
    <check-3>Handshake, active_connection, and close events update first_seen, last_seen, current_active, and connection counters deterministically.</check-3>
    <check-4>source_ip_unavailable events do not create fake IP observations.</check-4>
    <check-5>90-day prune deletes expired exact IP rows and logs only counts.</check-5>
    <check-6>Admin-only list decrypts only the requested user's/proxy's observations with pagination.</check-6>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1>Handshake telemetry with client IP creates or updates one encrypted IP observation for the assignment and user.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2>Current active IPs and last connected IP are derived from active/close events without guessing when source IP is unavailable.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3>Admin-only user detail can return decrypted IPs, but general analytics, logs, audit details, and user APIs never expose raw IP strings.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4>IP hash and coarse prefix remain available for abuse detection without decrypting raw IP.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5>Retention prunes exact IP observations older than 90 days and preserves rollups needed for three-month graphs.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6>Backup and XML/test smoke output do not include decrypted IP material.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_ip_observability.py tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/verification/V-M-061.xml docs/modules/M-061.xml docs/plans/Phase-43.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml</command>
  </commands>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Raw IP plaintext may appear only in the explicit admin investigation response and in controlled test assertions.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Logs, audit details, general analytics, top users, event lists, user APIs, XML fixtures, and smoke output must not contain decrypted raw IP strings.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Backup and restore artifacts preserve encrypted rows only and do not require decrypted IP material.</rule-3>
  </redaction-rules>
  <log-markers>
    <marker>[M-061][record_ip_observation][OBSERVATION_UPSERT]</marker>
    <marker>[M-061][list_user_ip_observations][ADMIN_SCOPE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-061][apply_ip_retention][RETENTION_PRUNE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-061][current_ip_summary][SOURCE_UNAVAILABLE]</marker>
    <marker>[M-061][decrypt_ip_observation][ADMIN_ONLY]</marker>
  </log-markers>
  <acceptance>
    <item-1>Exact IP history is available to admins for the requested 90-day window.</item-1>
    <item-2>Raw IP storage is encrypted and redaction tests fail closed on accidental non-admin exposure.</item-2>
    <item-3>Retention bounds storage growth while preserving operational history through rollups.</item-3>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>pass-local 2026-05-20: encrypted IP observation tests, runtime ip_observation client_ip handoff, current/last/all IP derivation, 90-day prune, source_ip_unavailable handling, admin-only detail route, usage telemetry no-inflation handoff, and migration metadata guard passed.</evidence>
</V-M-061>
