<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-065 MODULE="M-065" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase47-short-suffix">
  <purpose>Verify Phase-47 CTA MTProto subdomain generation, owner link consistency, and RU SNI router compatibility for issued CTA hostnames.</purpose>
  <checks>CTA prefix allow-list, public 4-hex suffix derivation for new assignments, explicit prefix validation, stable pseudo-random prefix selection, final-SNI fake-TLS secret derivation, old assignment preservation, redaction, 4/7-hex router ACL compatibility, and no install/deploy-script topology changes.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/service.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>deploy/haproxy-phase38.cfg</file>
    <file>scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase47-mtproto-cta-links-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py -v</command>
    <command status="pass-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">node scripts/phase47-mtproto-cta-links-smoke.mjs</command>
    <command status="pass-local">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-47.xml docs/modules/M-065.xml docs/verification/V-M-065.xml docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/current-status.xml</command>
    <command status="pass-local">mygrace lint</command>
  </commands>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Allowed prefixes are exactly kupi-vpn, vpn-tut, beri-vpn, bez-blokirovok, hochu-bystree, and krot-vpn.</check-1>
    <check-2>Generated CTA SNI follows cta-prefix-4hex.krotpn.xyz, stays DNS-label-safe, and supports collision nonce changes.</check-2>
    <check-3>Numeric user IDs are not copied raw into public hostnames; hex-like user keys use the first 7 hex characters.</check-3>
    <check-4>Owner payload server, secret, tg:// link, and https://t.me browser link share the same final CTA SNI.</check-4>
    <check-5>Existing u-* active assignments are reused without automatic rewrite or forced reissue.</check-5>
    <check-6>Smoke output and logs do not print base secret, salt, derived secret, full proxy links from real accounts, runtime token, JWTs, or email tokens.</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-47 smoke fails if install.sh, deploy scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or wildcard TLS surfaces carry CTA implementation drift; HAProxy ACL compatibility is explicitly guarded.</check-7>
    <check-8>Generated CTA SNI is exactly one wildcard label below the configured public domain and cannot include dots, path separators, uppercase drift, or arbitrary operator input.</check-8>
    <check-9>Fake-TLS secret derivation uses the final persisted CTA SNI; stale u-* host text is rejected for new CTA assignments.</check-9>
    <check-10>Legacy u-* assignments stay valid and are not mass-rewritten during normal dashboard/API access.</check-10>
    <check-11>RU SNI router accepts new approved CTA-prefix-4hex and existing CTA-prefix-7hex issued hostnames and still routes unknown SNI to HTTPS fallback, not MTProto.</check-11>
  </module-checks>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Deterministic backend tests cover allowed prefixes, invalid prefixes, short-id derivation, DNS/SNI safety, collision nonce behavior, final-SNI fake-TLS secret derivation, and legacy assignment reuse.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Frontend build plus Phase-47 smoke cover owner API payload/link consistency with Phase-46 tg:// and https://t.me split.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>XML parse, MyGRACE lint, protected install/deploy-script diff guard, and M-050 router smoke prove MyGRACE consistency and operational isolation.</phase-level>
    <live-required>Live Telegram proof is not required to execute the local hotfix, but the next production promotion should include operator clean-deploy Telegram client proof for a CTA-issued hostname.</live-required>
  </verification-levels>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">New assignment for a numeric user ID returns a CTA server such as kupi-vpn-4bb4.krotpn.xyz without exposing the numeric ID.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Explicit prefix krot-vpn produces krot-vpn-xxxx.krotpn.xyz and the fake-TLS secret contains that hostname in hex.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Existing u-*.krotpn.xyz active assignment remains active and owner payload still matches the stored SNI.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Hex-like UUID/user keys use the first 7 hex characters while numeric IDs use a stable non-raw hash suffix.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Owner dashboard tg:// app link and https://t.me browser link reference the same CTA server returned by the owner API.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="success">RU SNI router classifies new hochu-bystree-b405.krotpn.xyz and existing hochu-bystree-b405086.krotpn.xyz as MTProto traffic and sends both to mtproto_de_runtime.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Unknown prefix, uppercase/unsafe DNS label, overlong label, dotted label, path separator, or foreign base domain is rejected before persistence or policy apply.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">Any test, smoke output, backend log, frontend console trace, or fixture leaks a real full proxy link or secret-bearing value.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="failure">Phase-47 changes install.sh, deploy scripts, nginx, docker-compose, wildcard TLS material, or runtime topology.</scenario-9>
  </scenarios>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Runtime telemetry is not required for local Phase-47 because the data-plane is unchanged, but backend logs must expose secret-free decision markers for prefix selection, public short-id derivation, CTA assignment creation, and legacy preservation.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Allowed log fields are assignment id, user id, selected prefix, public short id, SNI, credential mode, and safe failure code; full links, ee secrets, base secret, salt, runtime tokens, and JWT/email/reset tokens are forbidden.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>Smoke fixtures must use synthetic domains and redacted secrets; no live account links or real Telegram proxy secrets may be printed.</requirement-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <required-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-065][generate_cta_sni][CTA_PREFIX]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-065][generate_cta_sni][PUBLIC_SHORT_ID]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-065][issue_user_proxy][CTA_ASSIGNMENT]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-065][phase47_mtproto_cta_links][LEGACY_PRESERVE]</marker-4>
  </required-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Do not log or print base secret, salt, derived secret, full tg:// or https://t.me links from live users, runtime tokens, access tokens, refresh tokens, email verification tokens, reset tokens, or private env values.</rule-1>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Allowed after plan and verification approval because Phase-47 is scoped to provisioning/link generation and static verification, with deploy/install/runtime topology explicitly out of scope.</autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-06-01: backend provisioning suite passed 14/14 outside sandbox after the first sandbox run hung on known aiosqlite async DB behavior.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-06-01: frontend build passed and Phase-47 smoke verified CTA helper markers, owner link consistency, redaction guards, and protected-surface static guard.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose diff guard had no output; XML parse and MyGRACE lint passed.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-06-01: Operator report showed CTA links such as hochu-bystree-b405086.krotpn.xyz were unavailable because HAProxy only matched legacy u-12hex labels. Local hotfix widened the MTProto ACL to legacy-or-approved-CTA labels and passed Phase-38/41/47 smoke plus 27 targeted backend tests.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-06-01: Short-suffix fix changed new CTA links from 7-hex to 4-hex public suffixes, preserved existing 7-hex CTA routing, and strengthened smoke checks for 4-hex success plus 5-hex rejection.</evidence-5>
  </evidence>
</V-M-065>
