<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-041 MODULE="M-041" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local" VERSION="1.9.0">
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-27 status="pass-local">Foundation evidence exists for pending-registration primitives, token hashing, TTL/replay protection, email risk checks, fake-provider email delivery, and unchanged active /register behavior.</phase-27>
    <phase-28 status="pass-local">Primary cutover and cross-module verification prove that /register is a pending-email flow and that active KrotPN access exists only after verified email activation; V-M-004 billing and V-M-022 device/VPN route gates pass locally.</phase-28>
    <phase-34 status="pass-local">Stabilization gate proves verified-email activation and the free MTProto owner path are linked without issuing MTProto, trial, VPN, referral, or JWT side effects before email proof.</phase-34>
    <phase-36 status="pass-live">Resend deploy wiring verifies pending registration can send email in production after operator supplies a Resend API key; live clean-deploy registration email proof is operator-confirmed.</phase-36>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file phase="27-regression">backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py</file>
    <file phase="28-primary">backend/tests/test_verified_registration.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_manual_access_policy.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_billing_security.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_billing_plan_api.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_device_api.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py</file>
    <file phase="28-cross-module">backend/tests/test_referrals.py</file>
    <file phase="34-integration">backend/tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py</file>
    <file phase="36-designed">scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>
    <command-1 status="pass-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_verified_registration.py tests/test_email_verification_guard.py tests/test_manual_access_policy.py tests/test_billing_security.py tests/test_billing_plan_api.py tests/test_device_api.py tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py tests/test_referrals.py tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py -v</command-1>
    <command-2 status="planned">node scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <command-3 status="pass-live">After Resend domain verification, submit one controlled /register request and confirm check-email state plus delivered mailbox message.</command-3>
  </commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Risk checks, pending-token lifecycle, activation idempotency, and redaction run without live email provider, DNS mutability, VPN host mutation, or MTProto runtime.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Phase-28 must run together with V-M-002 auth, V-M-004 billing trial, V-M-005 referral, V-M-022 device provisioning, and V-M-009 frontend onboarding gates.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Changing /api/v1/auth/register is allowed only when tests prove the new pending response shape and no pre-verification active access.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">Allowed email input normalizes consistently and stores exactly one pending registration record without issuing JWT, cookies, trial, VPN device, VPN client, referral, or MTProto side effects.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Verification tokens are stored hashed or otherwise non-recoverable; plaintext tokens never persist or appear in logs.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Temporary, disposable, configured blocked, malformed, duplicate, expired, and replayed token paths fail with stable API errors.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Blocked-domain registration is rejected before M-040 email sending is called.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Allowlist policy can override broad deny rules for operator-approved domains.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="deterministic">Successful verification consumes the token, creates the canonical user, marks email ownership verified, and returns the same authenticated session contract used by login.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="idempotency">Activation side effects are executed exactly once even if the verify endpoint is called repeatedly or a transaction is retried after partial failure.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="phase-34-integration">Verified activation plus first owner MTProto access creates exactly one MTProto assignment; pending/unverified registration creates none.</check-8>
    <check-9 evidence="phase-36-designed">With EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend and operator API key configured, /register does not fail with provider_disabled and still creates only pending registration state before token proof.</check-9>
    <check-10 evidence="phase-36-designed">Resend provider errors keep User, Subscription, UserDevice, Referral, MTProtoAssignment, JWT, and cookie side effects at zero until a verification token is successfully consumed.</check-10>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-36-registration-gates>
    <gate-1>/api/v1/auth/register with Resend configured returns pending/check-email and never returns access_token, refresh_token, user profile, or authenticated cookies.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Provider-disabled regression gate fails if production deploy defaults leave EMAIL_PROVIDER disabled after an API key was provided.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Resend auth, rate-limit, unavailable, and domain-not-verified errors return safe user/operator messages and no active access.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 status="passed">Live controlled-mailbox smoke is allowed only after krotpn.xyz verification is complete in Resend.</gate-4>
  </phase-36-registration-gates>
  <phase-34-stabilization-gates>
    <gate-1>Unverified registration returns pending/check-email and leaves User, Subscription, UserDevice, Referral, and MTProtoAssignment counts unchanged.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Verified-email activation creates normal KrotPN access once and allows the owner MTProto endpoint to create or reuse exactly one assignment.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Replay of the verification token cannot duplicate KrotPN onboarding side effects or MTProto assignments.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 status="passed">Phase-28 cross-module blockers in V-M-004 and V-M-022 were resolved locally on 2026-05-19 by aligning stale route tests with the canonical /api/v1 router prefixes.</gate-4>
  </phase-34-stabilization-gates>
  <phase-28-cutover-gates>
    <gate-1>/api/v1/auth/register returns a pending/check-email response and never returns access_token, refresh_token, user profile, or authenticated cookies.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>/api/v1/auth/verify-email or the chosen equivalent endpoint accepts a valid one-time token and creates active access only after email ownership is proven.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Verified activation creates exactly one eligible trial, one primary VPN device path, and one referral linkage where applicable.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Token replay, duplicate email, expired token, and blocked-domain paths cannot duplicate trial, referral, VPN, or future MTProto side effects.</gate-4>
  </phase-28-cutover-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">New user submits allowed email and password, receives safe check-email state, and remains unauthenticated until verification.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">New user verifies a valid token and receives a normal authenticated response compatible with existing login/session consumers.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Temporary email domain is blocked before verification email is sent.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Malformed, expired, replayed, duplicate, and already-consumed pending-registration tokens fail with safe reasons.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Pending registration cannot emit JWT tokens or provision KrotPN resources.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="success">Production registration request sends one verification email through configured Resend provider and returns check-email state.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Resend auth, rate-limit, or unavailable errors are safe user/operator failures without creating active access.</scenario-7>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-041][request_registration][EMAIL_RISK_CHECK]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-041][request_registration][STORE_PENDING]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-041][request_registration][PENDING_RESPONSE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-041][request_registration][SEND_VERIFICATION_EMAIL]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-041][email_risk_check][BLOCK_DOMAIN]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[M-041][verify_registration][CONSUME_TOKEN]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[M-041][verify_registration][ACTIVATE_USER]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[M-041][verify_registration][ACTIVATE_SIDE_EFFECTS]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[M-041][verify_registration][TOKEN_REPLAYED]</marker-9>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Mask email local parts in logs and never log verification tokens, token hashes, password values, JWT values, cookies, or raw risk-provider payloads.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Failure reasons may be operator-readable but must not expose whether an unrelated account exists.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>guarded-runtime-change</level>
    <reason>Automated Phase-36 registration checks must use fake email delivery, local DB isolation, no live email provider calls, and no host VPN mutation; future live Resend proof remains operator-only after domain verification.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-13: Phase-27 backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py passed locally, covering disposable-domain blocking before email send, allowlist override, env domain parsing, HMAC token storage, one-time consume, expiry, zero user side effects, and old active /register compatibility boundary.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-13: Phase-28 backend suite passed locally: tests/test_verified_registration.py, tests/test_email_verification_guard.py, tests/test_manual_access_policy.py, tests/test_device_api.py, tests/test_referrals.py, tests/test_telegram_auth.py, and tests/test_security.py; 44 passed.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-14: MyGRACE reviewer/refresh found full V-M-004 and V-M-022 per-module commands failing on stale /api route expectations, so V-M-041 stayed partial-local at wave level while module-local cutover tests remained green.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-14: Phase-34 backend/tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py passed locally with 2 tests for pending no-access, verified activation, MTProto owner assignment idempotency, and token replay safety.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-17: Phase-36 planning added production Resend deploy wiring after clean VPS registration reached M-040 provider_disabled.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-17: Phase-36 verification design added provider_disabled regression, Resend failure side-effect, and live controlled-mailbox gates.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-17: Phase-36 local implementation preserves fake-provider registration verification and defined live controlled-mailbox proof after Resend domain verification.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy registration via email succeeded with Resend configured, closing the provider_disabled production blocker while preserving pending-registration semantics.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Full Phase-28 cross-module gate passed locally with 39 tests after aligning billing and VPN compatibility tests to /api/v1 route prefixes; V-M-004, V-M-022, and V-M-041 are pass-local.</evidence-9>
  </evidence>
</V-M-041>
