<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-035 MODULE="M-035" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="partial-local">
  <module>portable-data-backup</module>
  <checks>Backup and restore contract must preserve PostgreSQL data, runtime secrets, AWG state, and VPN device/client linkage.</checks>
  <test-files>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-22.xml</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-035.xml</file>
    <file>docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml</file>
    <file>docs/recovery/DRY-RUN-PHASE-22.xml</file>
    <file>docs/verification/V-M-035.xml</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-22.xml docs/modules/M-035.xml docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml docs/recovery/DRY-RUN-PHASE-22.xml docs/verification/V-M-035.xml &amp;&amp; mygrace lint; planned non-production pg_dump/pg_restore dry-run plus checksum and secret-redaction evidence</commands>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 level="module-local">Backup manifest names every required artifact without exposing secret values.</check-1>
    <check-2 level="module-local">Restore validation compares table counts, migration state, and selected integrity invariants.</check-2>
    <check-3 level="wave">AWG profile, subnet settings, and existing client compatibility feed M-034 cutover gates.</check-3>
    <check-4 level="wave">Checksums are generated before transfer and verified before restore validation passes.</check-4>
    <check-5 level="phase">Non-production pg_dump/pg_restore dry-run evidence is captured before Phase-22 is trusted for incidents.</check-5>
  </module-checks>
  <evidence-matrix>
    <evidence-1 type="deterministic">XML parse and mygrace lint pass for Phase-22, M-035, and V-M-035.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2 type="deterministic">Manifest lists PostgreSQL dump, protected runtime env, AWG/VPN state, checksums, counts, migration state, and restore notes.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3 type="trace">Backup and restore logs show artifact names and validation decisions but no secret values.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4 type="integration">Non-production pg_dump/pg_restore proves table counts and invariants before live use.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5 type="live-required">Real incident recovery still requires live target validation and operator cutover approval.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6 type="deterministic">Restore integrity gates compare schema/migration state, checksums, table counts, selected row invariants, and no-secret-log review.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7 type="blocked-live">Non-production pg_dump/pg_restore rehearsal is blocked until a trusted bundle and isolated restore target are available.</evidence-7>
  </evidence-matrix>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Restored database contains matching users, subscriptions, payments, devices, VPN clients, and migration state.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="failure">Backup bundle lacks .env/runtime secret material needed to boot replacement servers.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Backup bundle lacks AWG profile or device-client state needed to preserve client connectivity.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Checksum or critical table-count mismatch is ignored and cutover proceeds.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Backup or restore logs expose secret values, tokens, passwords, private keys, or raw .env content.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Existing client configs are invalidated without explicit operator-approved rotation.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[PortableBackup][manifest][CHECKSUMS_READY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[PortableBackup][restore][COUNTS_MATCH]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[PortableBackup][restore][MIGRATION_STATE_MATCH]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[PortableBackup][restore][SECRETS_REDACTED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[PortableBackup][restore][CLIENT_COMPATIBILITY_OK]</marker-5>
  </required-log-markers>
  <autonomy-safety>
    <safe-local>Agents may design manifest schemas, redaction checks, and non-production dry-run validation artifacts.</safe-local>
    <requires-operator>Agents must not move live secrets, run incident cutover, or rotate VPN/client material without explicit operator control.</requires-operator>
  </autonomy-safety>
</V-M-035>
