<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-077 MODULE="M-077" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72-pass-local-phase74-pass-local-phase75-pass-local-phase76-pass-local-phase77" PHASE-59="pass-local" RAINFIX="pass-local" PHASE-68="pass-local" PHASE-71="pass-local" PHASE-72="pass-local" PHASE-74="pass-local" PHASE-75="pass-local" PHASE-76="pass-local" PHASE-77="pass-local">
  <scope>Phase-59 verification for premium Matrix motion and microinteractions across user and admin frontends: copy/download/proxy feedback, VPN/MTProto/subscription/alert/health state transitions, route entrance motion, reduced-motion fallback, inactive-tab lifecycle, keyboard/pointer/scroll safety, and protected-surface isolation.</scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="71-pass-local">scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="72-pass-local">scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="74-pass-local">scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="75-pass-local">scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-077.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-59.xml</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 status="passed-local">cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2 status="passed-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-2>
    <check-3 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-4>
    <check-5 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</check-5>
    <check-6 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</check-6>
    <check-7 status="passed-local">node scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs</check-7>
    <check-8 status="pass-local-post-commit">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-8>
    <check-9 status="static-route-proof">Chrome screenshot audit is represented by Phase-59 static-route proof marker; authenticated clean-deploy screenshot review remains follow-up.</check-9>
    <check-10 status="static-smoke">Interaction smoke is static: copy/download/proxy link classes, route/focus/pointer/reduced-motion markers, passive pointer listener, and no scroll hijack patterns are asserted by Phase-59 smoke.</check-10>
    <check-11 status="pending-final-run">python3 XML parse for docs/modules/M-077.xml docs/plans/Phase-59.xml docs/verification/V-M-077.xml docs/verification-index.xml</check-11>
    <check-12 status="passed-local">mygrace lint</check-12>
    <check-13 status="passed-local">git diff --check</check-13>
    <check-14 status="passed-local">git diff --name-only HEAD -- install.sh docker-compose.yml nginx deploy deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml .env.example backend/app backend/tests mtproto-runtime official-mtproxy telegram-bot is empty</check-14>
    <check-15 status="pass-local-rainfix">node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs asserts root transform safety, CSS rain fallback, mobile overscan, and visualViewport listeners.</check-15>
    <check-16 status="pass-local-phase74">Phase-74 smoke asserted admin nav/logout microinteractions, pointer-safe scroll containers, reduced-motion fallback, and no Matrix overlay scroll interception.</check-16>
    <check-17 status="pass-local-phase75">Phase-75 smoke asserted expand/collapse feedback, confirmation pointer safety, reduced-motion fallback, and no Matrix overlay scroll interception in the unified Users inventory.</check-17>
  </module-checks>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend build passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend-admin build passed with the existing large chunk warning only.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-59 motion smoke printed all required MatrixMotion markers.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-52, Phase-55, Phase-56, Phase-57, and post-commit Phase-58 regression smokes passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Rainfix Phase-59 smoke passed after moving motion-route-enter from the root shell to matrix-visual-content and adding CSS_RAIN_FALLBACK_READY/MOBILE_OVERSCAN_READY assertions.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-68 kept dashboard/config/subscription buttons on existing motion-interactive primitives; Phase-59 and Phase-68 smokes passed with reduced-motion and protected-surface guards.</item>
    <item>2026-06-05: Phase-74 smoke passed MatrixMotion markers ADMIN_NAV_MOTION_SAFE and SCROLL_POINTER_SAFE for admin shell navigation and content scrolling.</item>
    <item>2026-06-05: Phase-75 smoke passed MatrixMotion markers EXPAND_COLLAPSE_MOTION_SAFE, CONFIRMATION_POINTER_SAFE, and REDUCED_MOTION_EXPANSION_PASS for the unified Users/Devices inventory.</item>
  </evidence>
  <verification-matrix>
    <target-1 evidence="static-and-interaction">Copy, download, QR/config, Telegram proxy, and promo/status feedback use short visible success/error states without blocking forms, buttons, links, or route navigation.</target-1>
    <target-2 evidence="static-and-screenshot">VPN, MTProto, subscription, alert, device, server, health, and billing status transitions remain readable while animating and do not resize fixed-format tiles, charts, rows, toolbars, QR blocks, or buttons.</target-2>
    <target-3 evidence="static-and-interaction">Route entrance motion is bounded, fast, and never hides first-screen CTA/action controls or delays keyboard focus restoration.</target-3>
    <target-4 evidence="static-and-screenshot">prefers-reduced-motion replaces motion-heavy behavior with static or fade-only variants, disables decorative loop/scanline intensity where needed, and keeps Matrix canvas pointer-safe.</target-4>
    <target-5 evidence="static">Motion CSS and runtime code avoid scroll hijacking, parallax scroll locking, pointer interception, keyboard traps, long cinematic loaders, negative letter spacing, viewport-scaled font sizes, oversized radii, and prohibited decorative orb/radial backgrounds.</target-5>
    <target-6 evidence="static">No backend API, auth/session, deploy/install, nginx, docker-compose, MTProto/VPN runtime, telegram-bot, billing catalog, or data model changes are introduced by Phase-59.</target-6>
  </verification-matrix>
  <success-scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">A user copies VPN config data, downloads a config, opens/copies MTProto links, and sees immediate compact feedback that clears without disrupting the workflow.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">An admin reviews devices, MTProto analytics, alerts, plans, servers, and dashboard health while status transitions clarify state without hiding destructive confirmations or redaction boundaries.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Keyboard-only navigation and focus-visible rings remain stable through route transitions and microinteractions.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Reduced-motion mode keeps the product premium through static/fade feedback, not decorative loops or movement-heavy transitions.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Inactive-tab or unmounted-route lifecycle stops animation timers/frames and does not leak work or stale feedback state.</scenario-5>
  </success-scenarios>
  <failure-scenarios>
    <failure-1 kind="failure">Animation hides operational controls, status text, QR/config content, admin confirmations, MTProto redaction states, tariff prices, or payment/subscription labels.</failure-1>
    <failure-2 kind="failure">Canvas, overlay, route wrapper, tooltip, toast, or feedback layer intercepts clicks, focus, copy/download actions, form submission, or mobile scrolling.</failure-2>
    <failure-3 kind="failure">Route transitions use long cinematic loaders, block navigation, reset scroll unexpectedly, trap keyboard focus, or delay emergency/admin actions.</failure-3>
    <failure-4 kind="failure">Reduced-motion media emulation still runs motion-heavy loops, transform-heavy transitions, flicker, or nonessential animation.</failure-4>
    <failure-5 kind="failure">Smoke output, screenshots, or logs reveal MTProto secrets, full proxy links, raw promotion tags, bearer/refresh/reset/verify tokens, real emails, raw IP exports, payment IDs, provider keys, database URLs, or API keys.</failure-5>
    <failure-6 kind="failure">Phase-59 touches backend/deploy/runtime/billing/auth surfaces or changes product behavior outside frontend motion/microinteraction scope.</failure-6>
  </failure-scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[MatrixMotion][phase59][MOTION_BUDGET_READY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixMotion][phase59][MICROINTERACTIONS_READY]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[MatrixMotion][phase59][STATUS_TRANSITIONS_READY]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[MatrixMotion][phase59][ROUTE_TRANSITIONS_FAST]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MatrixMotion][phase59][REDUCED_MOTION_PASS]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MatrixMotion][phase59][POINTER_SCROLL_SAFE]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MatrixMotion][phase59][KEYBOARD_FOCUS_SAFE]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[MatrixMotion][phase59][INACTIVE_TAB_SAFE]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[MatrixMotion][phase59][SCREENSHOT_MATRIX_REVIEWED]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[MatrixMotion][phase59][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[MatrixVisualRuntime][fix][CSS_RAIN_FALLBACK_READY]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[MatrixVisualRuntime][fix][MOBILE_OVERSCAN_READY]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[MatrixMotion][phase74][ADMIN_NAV_MOTION_SAFE]</marker-13>
    <marker-14>[MatrixMotion][phase74][SCROLL_POINTER_SAFE]</marker-14>
    <marker-15>[MatrixMotion][phase75][EXPAND_COLLAPSE_MOTION_SAFE]</marker-15>
    <marker-16>[MatrixMotion][phase75][CONFIRMATION_POINTER_SAFE]</marker-16>
    <marker-17>[MatrixMotion][phase75][REDUCED_MOTION_EXPANSION_PASS]</marker-17>
  </required-log-markers>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Allowed smoke output: route names, viewport names, selector names, timing budgets, reduced-motion mode, pointer/scroll/focus pass markers, synthetic fixture IDs, and screenshot paths.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Forbidden smoke output: MTProto ee secrets, full tg:// or https://t.me proxy links, raw promotion tags, bearer/refresh/reset/verify tokens, real user emails, raw IP history exports, payment IDs, YooKassa/Resend keys, database URLs, and API keys.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>Any runtime console markers must use stable Phase-59 marker strings and must not include payload values, device identifiers, IP addresses, account emails, or provider metadata.</requirement-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1 level="module-local">M-077 smoke proves motion budget, microinteraction markers, status transitions, route transitions, reduced-motion fallback, pointer/scroll/focus safety, inactive-tab safety, and protected-surface guard.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 level="wave">M-009, M-010, M-070, M-071, M-072, M-075, and M-076 regression smokes remain satisfied after motion changes.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 level="phase">User/admin builds, Phase-59 smoke, Phase-52/55/56/57/58 regressions, screenshot or static-route proof, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard pass before Phase-59 can be marked done-local.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 level="rainfix" status="passed-local">Route transition animation must remain on the content layer so fixed Matrix canvas/fallback layers are never clipped by a transformed root ancestor.</gate-4>
  </phase-gates>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Safe for autonomous local execution if changes stay inside user/admin frontend Matrix components, CSS, route wrappers, microinteraction helpers, Phase-59 smoke verification, and MyGRACE docs. Stop if implementation appears to require backend API changes, auth/session changes, deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose changes, MTProto/VPN runtime changes, billing catalog changes, or secret-handling changes.</autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-68-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Cabinet button and status microinteraction verification.</scope>
    <gate-1>All user-cabinet buttons must have compact hover, active, focus, loading, and disabled states.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Motion must not hide subscription countdown, tariff price, MTProto secret, QR actions, or referral controls.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>prefers-reduced-motion must disable transform-heavy effects while preserving visible feedback.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-68-verification-design>
  <phase-71-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion verification for QR close icon, selected-device UX, sticky actions, and subscription boundary pulse.</scope>
    <gate-1>Icon-only close, device row selection, copy/download feedback, and calendar boundary pulse must use bounded motion and visible focus states.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Reduced-motion mode must avoid transform-heavy or flicker-heavy animation while preserving visual meaning.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Motion layers must not intercept pointer, keyboard, copy, download, QR, or mobile scroll actions.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-71-verification-design>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Phase-71 smoke passed for Matrix motion markers, selected-device row feedback, icon-only close, sticky actions, calendar pulse, and reduced-motion safety; post-commit Phase-59 protected regression guard passed cleanly.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion verification for touch/scroll-aware bottom navigation and compact calendar states.</scope>
    <gate-1>Bottom navigation reveal/compact behavior must use short bounded motion and must not hijack scroll, pointer, keyboard, copy, download, or QR interactions.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Reduced-motion mode must keep navigation reachable without transform-heavy or flicker-heavy transitions.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Calendar density and boundary pulse must remain readable and must not introduce layout shifts during hover, focus, or route transitions.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-72-verification-design>
  <phase-72-required-markers status="observed-local">
    <marker-1>[MatrixMotion][phase72][TOUCH_NAV_REVEAL_SAFE]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixMotion][phase72][REDUCED_MOTION_NAV_PASS]</marker-2>
  </phase-72-required-markers>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-72 and Phase-59 smokes passed for bounded bottom-dock transitions, reduced-motion nav safety, pointer/scroll safety, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</phase-72-evidence>
  <phase-74-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion and pointer/scroll verification for the admin shell navigation and scroll repair wave.</scope>
    <gate-1>Logout and admin nav controls may use motion-interactive states but must not shift layout, hide controls, or trap keyboard focus.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Matrix visual layers, route transitions, and feedback layers must not intercept mouse-wheel, touch scroll, pointer events, or focus in the admin content surface.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion mode must keep admin navigation and scroll behavior usable without transform-heavy transitions.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-74-verification-design>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-74 smoke proved admin nav motion and content scroll pointer safety without Matrix overlay scroll interception or protected backend/deploy/runtime drift.</phase-74-evidence>
  <phase-75-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion and pointer/scroll verification for expandable user rows and device confirmations in the unified admin Users inventory.</scope>
    <gate-1>Expand/collapse interactions must be short, bounded, keyboard reachable, and must not resize unrelated admin shell navigation or headers.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Device action confirmations must remain pointer-safe above Matrix visual layers and must not mutate before explicit confirmation.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion mode must keep expanded device state readable without transform-heavy transitions.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Scroll containers for expanded device lists must not hijack the admin content wheel/touch scroll behavior repaired in Phase-74.</gate-4>
    <commands>node scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-75-verification-design>
  <phase-75-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-75 smoke passed expand/collapse, confirmation pointer-safety, and reduced-motion expansion markers without protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend drift.</phase-75-evidence>
  <phase-76-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion and microinteraction regression guard across the consolidated user/admin polish gate.</scope>
    <gate-1>User bottom dock, config actions, subscription calendar, admin nav, content scroll, expanded user rows, and confirmation surfaces must keep bounded motion.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Reduced-motion, pointer/scroll safety, keyboard focus safety, and Matrix overlay non-interception must remain verified by Phase-59 plus Phase-72/74/75 smokes.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Motion execution must not change backend, auth/session, billing, VPN, MTProto, deploy/install, nginx, docker, provider, or telegram-bot surfaces.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs; protected-surface guard.</commands>
  </phase-76-verification-design>
  <phase-76-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Consolidated Phase-76 gate passed for Matrix motion: Phase-59 smoke plus Phase-72/74/75 smokes preserved bounded motion, reduced-motion fallback, pointer/scroll safety, keyboard focus safety, bottom dock feedback, admin scroll, and confirmation pointer safety.</phase-76-evidence>
  <phase-77-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Motion verification for calendar pulses, dock interactions, reduced-motion fallback, and mobile scroll non-interception.</scope>
    <gate-1>Green/cyan/red calendar pulses must stay bounded and must not create layout shifts.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Reduced-motion must disable or collapse pulse/dock animation while preserving visible state.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Dock, Matrix visual layers, and content wrappers must not hijack pointer, keyboard, copy/download, QR, or mobile scroll interactions.</gate-3>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase77-subscription-mobile-polish-smoke.mjs.</commands>
  </phase-77-verification-design>
  <phase-77-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-59 and Phase-77 smokes passed for bounded calendar pulse classes, fixed dock interaction markers, reduced-motion fallback, pointer-safe Matrix layers, and no mobile scroll hijack.</phase-77-evidence>
  <mobile-route-transform-fix-verification status="pass-local" date="2026-06-07">
    <scope>Mobile-only route transform regression for fixed bottom navigation.</scope>
    <gate-1>Route entrance transform stays available on larger screens but is disabled for mobile user content where it can scope fixed-position descendants.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Disabling mobile route transform must not remove reduced-motion policy, copy feedback, status motion, calendar pulses, or pointer-safety markers.</gate-2>
    <commands>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase77-subscription-mobile-polish-smoke.mjs.</commands>
  </mobile-route-transform-fix-verification>
</V-M-077>
