<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-076 MODULE="M-076" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase59-phase62-pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase74-pass-local-phase75" PHASE-58="pass-local" PHASE-59="pass-local" PHASE-62="pass-local" RAINFIX="pass-local" PHASE-74="pass-local" PHASE-75="pass-local">
  <scope>Phase-58/Phase-59 premium admin cockpit evidence remains valid. Phase-62 verification now defines the compactness and deletion-audit contract for admin cockpit, MTProto analytics, operational inventories, emergency controls, redaction, responsive regressions, and protected backend/deploy/runtime isolation.</scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="59-pass-local">scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="62-pass-local">scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="74-pass-local">scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="75-pass-local">scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/catalog.py</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-076.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-58.xml</file>
    <file phase="62-pass-local">docs/plans/Phase-62.xml</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 status="pass-local">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-2>
    <check-3 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</check-4>
    <check-5 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</check-5>
    <check-6 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</check-6>
    <check-7 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-7>
    <check-8 status="pass-local">node scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</check-8>
    <check-9 status="pass-local-static-proof">Chrome screenshot audit for frontend-admin /login, /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, and /analytics at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion / 390x844. Local pass used static route proof because no authenticated admin backend session was available; clean-deploy authenticated screenshot review remains follow-up.</check-9>
    <check-10 status="pass-local">python3 XML parse for docs/modules/M-076.xml docs/plans/Phase-58.xml docs/verification/V-M-076.xml docs/verification-index.xml</check-10>
    <check-11 status="pass-local">mygrace lint</check-11>
    <check-12 status="pass-local">git diff --check</check-12>
    <check-13 status="pass-local">git diff --name-only HEAD -- install.sh docker-compose.yml nginx deploy deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml .env.example backend/app backend/tests mtproto-runtime official-mtproxy frontend must be empty</check-13>
    <check-14 status="pass-local-post-commit">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-14>
    <check-15 status="pass-local-phase59">node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</check-15>
    <check-16 status="pass-local-phase62">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-16>
    <check-17 status="pass-local-phase62">node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</check-17>
    <check-18 status="pass-local-phase62">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-18>
    <check-19 status="pass-local-phase62">node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</check-19>
    <check-20 status="pass-local-phase62">node scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</check-20>
    <check-21 status="pass-local-phase62">node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs</check-21>
    <check-22 status="pass-local-phase62">python3 -m xml.etree.ElementTree docs/plans/Phase-62.xml docs/modules/M-076.xml docs/verification/V-M-076.xml docs/verification-index.xml</check-22>
    <check-23 status="pass-local-phase62">mygrace lint; git diff --check; protected diff guard for backend/deploy/runtime/install/frontend-user surfaces</check-23>
    <check-24 status="pass-local-rainfix">Phase-58 regression guard allows only frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx as shared Matrix reliability diff and remains green through node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs.</check-24>
    <check-25 status="pass-local-phase74">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-25>
    <check-26 status="pass-local-phase74">node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</check-26>
    <check-27 status="pending-final-run-phase74">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs</check-27>
    <check-28 status="pending-final-run-phase74">node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</check-28>
    <check-29 status="pass-local-phase74">protected backend/deploy/runtime/frontend-user/tariff guard proved Phase-74 is admin-shell-only.</check-29>
    <check-30 status="pass-local-phase75">cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-30>
    <check-31 status="pass-local-phase75">node scripts/phase75-admin-users-devices-smoke.mjs passed for unified Users inventory, removed Devices nav, direct /devices safety, expandable device rows, action confirmations, and protected guard.</check-31>
    <check-32 status="pending-final-run-phase75">node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs and node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs remain final-run regressions after the merge.</check-32>
  </module-checks>
  <phase62-deletion-audit-contract>
    <classification>
      <remove>Duplicated KPI cards, repeated explanatory copy, decorative-only wrappers, stale helper text, and status summaries that do not expose unique admin state or action.</remove>
      <collapse>Secondary analytics details, long history blocks, verbose operation notes, alert archive details, and low-frequency metadata behind bounded panels, tabs, drawers, or expandable rows.</collapse>
      <move-secondary>Verbose admin descriptions, secondary filters, low-priority archive views, and deep troubleshooting text when they compete with first-screen service health or incident/action surfaces.</move-secondary>
      <compact>Dashboard, users, devices, MTProto, MTProto analytics, servers, plans, and analytics pages using denser rows, bounded inventories, compact chart frames, and mobile-first action grouping.</compact>
      <keep>Emergency controls, destructive/disruptive confirmations, user/device actions, MTProto disable/reissue/revoke/block/IP alert workflows, alert archive access, promotion tag operations, redacted analytics, server health, canonical tariffs, logout, and admin redaction.</keep>
    </classification>
    <preservation-invariants>
      <invariant-1>Admin health, users, devices, MTProto, alerts, servers, plans, and analytics remain reachable within one or two taps on phone layouts.</invariant-1>
      <invariant-2>Emergency and destructive controls must remain visible with explicit confirmation text after any compaction or deletion.</invariant-2>
      <invariant-3>MTProto analytics keeps useful admin signals while removing technical noise from visible UI; no secrets, full proxy links, bearer tokens, provider keys, or raw payment identifiers may appear in smoke output.</invariant-3>
      <invariant-4>Phase-62 must not change backend admin APIs, auth/session behavior, billing catalog ownership, VPN/MTProto runtime, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, secrets, or production topology.</invariant-4>
    </preservation-invariants>
  </phase62-deletion-audit-contract>
  <verification-matrix>
    <target-1 evidence="static-and-runtime">Admin layout keeps compact navigation, authenticated admin context, logout, route active state, and emergency surfaces reachable on phone/tablet/desktop.</target-1>
    <target-2 evidence="static-and-screenshot">Dashboard first viewport exposes service health, users, devices, revenue/billing, VPN, MTProto, analytics, and incident signals without decorative bulk or horizontal scroll.</target-2>
    <target-3 evidence="static">Users and devices pages preserve search, filters, bounded scrolling, readable dense rows, details, block/unblock or device-control actions, and explicit confirmation for destructive/disruptive operations.</target-3>
    <target-4 evidence="static">MTProto and MTProto analytics preserve redacted assignment/secret/promotion-tag displays, confirmation-safe reissue/revoke/disable/block actions, alert inbox/archive, IP-history compactness, charts, top users, runtime health, and auto-refresh markers.</target-4>
    <target-5 evidence="static">Plans page preserves canonical M-068 tariff matrix and does not introduce accidental CRUD controls, frontend-owned checkout amounts, or catalog mutation paths.</target-5>
    <target-6 evidence="static">Servers and analytics pages stay operationally dense while preserving runtime-data read-only semantics, health visibility, and no backend API shape changes.</target-6>
    <target-7 evidence="runtime-screenshot">Phone/tablet/desktop/reduced-motion screenshots show no text/icon/button/status overlap, no hidden emergency CTA, no long unbounded inventory, and no Matrix layer click/scroll interception.</target-7>
    <target-8 evidence="static-and-smoke">Phase-75 Users route becomes the single account/device inventory, with expandable device rows and preserved emergency device actions after the separate Devices nav is retired.</target-8>
  </verification-matrix>
  <phase-74-admin-cockpit-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Admin Layout navigation order must place Logout directly under Nodes and remove visible Tariffs/Plans from the rail.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Dashboard, Users, MTProto, Servers/Nodes, and Analytics admin cockpit routes must remain reachable, compact, and operational.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Direct Plans access must be safely redirected, hidden, or otherwise handled without a broken blank screen.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Admin scroll repair must allow normal content-area wheel scrolling and bound admin-rail overflow.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Canonical tariffs remain protected by M-068 and are no longer an admin cockpit visible route after Phase-74.</gate-5>
  </phase-74-admin-cockpit-gates>
  <phase-75-admin-cockpit-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Admin cockpit must expose one "Пользователи" inventory that combines account rows and expandable device sublists.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Visible "Устройства" navigation is removed only after block/unblock/rotate/revoke device controls are reachable from expanded user rows.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Direct /devices must redirect or remain a compatibility path without creating a duplicate long-scroll device dashboard.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Users inventory must support search, pagination, loading/empty/error states, and bounded expanded device lists for large accounts.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Emergency device actions, confirmation text, feedback, and audit-safe behavior must be preserved.</gate-5>
  </phase-75-admin-cockpit-gates>
  <success-scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Admin can reach dashboard health, users, devices, MTProto, plans, servers, analytics, and incident review in one or two taps on phone.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Users/devices/MTProto inventories are searchable, bounded, compact, and remain readable without losing row actions.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Destructive and disruptive admin actions retain visible confirmation text, guarded buttons, and audit-safe feedback.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">MTProto secrets, full tg links, raw promotion tags when masked, access tokens, raw IP history exports, and payment/provider identifiers are not printed by smoke output, console markers, screenshots, or docs.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Phase-58 does not touch backend admin APIs, auth/session handling, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, MTProto/VPN runtime, or canonical tariff catalog behavior.</scenario-5>
  </success-scenarios>
  <failure-scenarios>
    <failure-1 kind="failure">Premium visual redesign hides emergency controls, destructive confirmations, MTProto reissue/revoke/disable/block actions, user/device actions, tariff state, server health, or incident review.</failure-1>
    <failure-2 kind="failure">Any admin route exposes MTProto secrets, full proxy links, raw promotion tags, bearer/refresh tokens, raw emails beyond synthetic fixtures, payment IDs, YooKassa/Resend keys, or backend secrets.</failure-2>
    <failure-3 kind="failure">Users, devices, MTProto, analytics, or plans become unbounded long-scroll surfaces without search/filter/scroll containment.</failure-3>
    <failure-4 kind="failure">Plans page introduces canonical tariff mutation, frontend-controlled payment amounts, or accidental CRUD controls.</failure-4>
    <failure-5 kind="failure">Phase-58 changes backend API shape, auth/session behavior, billing catalog values, MTProto/VPN runtime behavior, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or production topology.</failure-5>
    <failure-6 kind="failure">Phase-75 removes the separate Devices page before device actions are reachable and confirmation-safe inside the Users route.</failure-6>
    <failure-7 kind="failure">Phase-75 leaves both Users and Devices as duplicate primary inventories, making admin navigation longer instead of simpler.</failure-7>
  </failure-scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][ROUTES_READY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][OPS_COMMAND_CENTER]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][ADMIN_ACTIONS_REACHABLE]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][INVENTORIES_BOUNDED]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][MTPROTO_REDACTION]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][CONFIRMATION_GUARDS]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][TARIFF_ADMIN_GUARD]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][ANALYTICS_RUNTIME_READONLY]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][REDUCED_MOTION_SAFE]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][SCREENSHOT_MATRIX_REVIEWED]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase58][PROTECTED_SURFACE_GUARD]</marker-11>
    <marker-12 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][ADMIN_SURFACES_INVENTORIED]</marker-12>
    <marker-13 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][ADMIN_SURFACES_PRUNED]</marker-13>
    <marker-14 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][EMERGENCY_CONTROLS_PRESERVED]</marker-14>
    <marker-15 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][REDACTION_CONFIRMATION_PRESERVED]</marker-15>
    <marker-16 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][ADMIN_INVENTORIES_BOUNDED]</marker-16>
    <marker-17 phase="62-pass-local">[CompactDeletionAudit][phase62][NO_BACKEND_DEPLOY_DRIFT]</marker-17>
    <marker-18 phase="74-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase74][LOGOUT_UNDER_NODES]</marker-18>
    <marker-19 phase="74-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase74][TARIFFS_ROUTE_REMOVED]</marker-19>
    <marker-20 phase="74-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase74][CONTENT_SCROLL_REPAIRED]</marker-20>
    <marker-21 phase="75-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase75][USERS_INVENTORY_UNIFIED]</marker-21>
    <marker-22 phase="75-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase75][DEVICES_NAV_REMOVED]</marker-22>
    <marker-23 phase="75-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase75][EMERGENCY_DEVICE_ACTIONS_PRESERVED]</marker-23>
    <marker-24 phase="75-pass-local">[PremiumAdminCockpit][phase75][BOUNDED_EXPANDED_DEVICES]</marker-24>
  </required-log-markers>
  <telemetry-requirements>
    <requirement-1>Allowed smoke output: route names, viewport names, selector markers, action names, redacted state names, screenshot paths, and pass/fail markers.</requirement-1>
    <requirement-2>Forbidden smoke output: MTProto ee secrets, full tg:// or https://t.me proxy links, raw promotion tags when masked in UI, bearer/refresh tokens, reset/verify tokens, real user emails, raw IP export data, payment IDs, YooKassa/Resend keys, database URLs, and API keys.</requirement-2>
    <requirement-3>If screenshots require authenticated fixtures, fixtures must use synthetic admin/user/device/proxy/payment data only; live clean-deploy screenshots must be operator-approved and redacted.</requirement-3>
  </telemetry-requirements>
  <phase-gates>
    <gate-1 level="module-local">M-076 smoke proves admin dashboard, layout, users, devices, MTProto, MTProto analytics, plans, servers, analytics, compact primitives, confirmation guards, and redaction guards.</gate-1>
    <gate-2 level="wave">M-010, M-037, M-047, M-058, M-068, M-070, M-071, and M-072 regression smokes remain satisfied after admin cockpit edits.</gate-2>
    <gate-3 level="phase">Frontend-admin build, Phase-58 smoke, regression smokes, screenshot/static route proof, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/frontend-user guard pass before Phase-58 can be marked done-local.</gate-3>
    <gate-4 level="phase-62" status="passed-local">Phase-62 passed locally on 2026-06-04: inventory, classification, prune/collapse decisions, preserved workflow proof, static-route proof, frontend-admin build, Phase-62 smoke, Phase-58/54/61/60 regressions, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/frontend-user guard passed.</gate-4>
    <gate-5 level="phase-62">Authenticated screenshots may use static-route proof locally; live clean-deploy authenticated screenshot review remains required before production-signoff claims.</gate-5>
    <gate-6 level="rainfix" status="passed-local">Phase-58 guard update is limited to shared Matrix VisualShell reliability diff and does not permit backend/deploy/runtime drift.</gate-6>
    <gate-7 level="phase-74" status="pass-local">Phase-74 admin build and shell smoke passed; Phase-54/58/59/61/62 regressions, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and git diff --check remain required in the final verification run.</gate-7>
    <gate-8 level="phase-75" status="pass-local">Phase-75 passed unified Users inventory, removed Devices nav, safe direct /devices handling, preserved device actions, and bounded expanded rows through frontend-admin build and Phase-75 smoke.</gate-8>
  </phase-gates>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-06-04 pass-local: Phase-58 smoke printed all required PremiumAdminCockpit markers including routes, command center, actions, bounded inventories, MTProto redaction, confirmation guards, tariff guard, readonly analytics, reduced motion, static screenshot proof, and protected-surface guard.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>Regression evidence passed: Phase-42 MTProto admin analytics smoke, Phase-43 MTProto analytics UX/IP/alerts smoke, Phase-50 tariff catalog smoke, Phase-52 Matrix visual smoke, Phase-54 admin Matrix smoke, and Phase-55 premium art-direction smoke.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>Protected-surface evidence passed: no diff in install.sh, docker-compose.yml, nginx, deploy, deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml, .env.example, backend/app, backend/tests, mtproto-runtime, official-mtproxy, or frontend.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-06-04 pass-local: Phase-59 admin motion smoke passed for Devices, MTProto, MTProtoAnalytics, VisualShell, MatrixBackground, shared admin CSS, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard. Post-commit Phase-58 smoke passed after HEAD included Phase-59 user frontend changes.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-06-04 pass-local: Phase-62 compactness/deletion audit folded MTProto alert archive, MTProto storage details, and legacy VPN server compatibility diagnostics into compact secondary panels while preserving emergency controls, alert actions, confirmation/redaction guards, bounded inventories, and read-only analytics. Frontend-admin build, Phase-62 smoke, Phase-58/54/61/60 regressions, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/frontend-user guard passed. Implementation commit: 3d09fa8.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-04 pass-local-rainfix: Phase-58 protected surface guard was narrowed to permit only the shared user VisualShell Matrix rain reliability diff during Phase-60 regression. Phase-60 QA passed and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard remained clean.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-06-05 pass-local: Phase-74 frontend-admin build and admin shell smoke passed for Logout under Nodes, removed visible Tariffs route/nav, safe /plans redirect, repaired content scroll, and bounded rail geometry.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-06-05 pass-local: Phase-75 frontend-admin build and admin Users/Devices smoke passed for single Users inventory, removed visible Devices nav, safe /devices redirect, preserved emergency device actions, bounded expanded devices, and protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend guard.</evidence-8>
  </evidence>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>Safe for local autonomous execution if changes stay inside frontend-admin cockpit routes/components/CSS, Phase-62 smoke verification, and MyGRACE docs. Stop execution if backend admin API changes, auth/session changes, billing catalog mutation, VPN/MTProto runtime changes, deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose changes, user frontend changes, or secret-handling changes appear necessary.</autonomous-execution-safety>
  <phase-74-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>Premium admin cockpit verification for the approved navigation and scroll repair wave.</scope>
    <gate-1>Visible Tariffs UI is removed from admin only; admin shell remains compact and usable.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Logout under Nodes is asserted by source order, visible label order, and route shell smoke.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Scroll and rail CSS markers are required before claiming the mouse-wheel fix.</gate-3>
    <commands>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build; node scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase58-premium-admin-cockpit-smoke.mjs; node scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</commands>
  </phase-74-verification-design>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-74 smoke passed PremiumAdminCockpit markers LOGOUT_UNDER_NODES, TARIFFS_ROUTE_REMOVED, and CONTENT_SCROLL_REPAIRED while protecting backend/deploy/runtime/user tariff surfaces.</phase-74-evidence>
  <phase-75-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-75 smoke passed PremiumAdminCockpit markers USERS_INVENTORY_UNIFIED, DEVICES_NAV_REMOVED, EMERGENCY_DEVICE_ACTIONS_PRESERVED, and BOUNDED_EXPANDED_DEVICES while protecting backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend surfaces.</phase-75-evidence>
</V-M-076>
