<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-070 MODULE="M-070" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass-local-phase52-phase53-phase54-phase59-pass-local-phase67" PHASE-54="pass-local" PHASE-59="pass-local" PHASE-67="pass-local">
  <scope>
    <phase>Phase-52</phase>
    <purpose>Verify the shared React/Vite Matrix visual runtime before it is used by the full user/admin redesign phases.</purpose>
    <module-ref>docs/modules/M-070.xml</module-ref>
  </scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="54-pass-local">scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="59-pass-local">scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="67-pass-local">scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-1>
    <check-2>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</check-2>
    <check-3>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</check-3>
    <check-4>Chrome/Playwright screenshot audit: /login user shell desktop 1440x900, 390x844, and reduced-motion.</check-4>
    <check-5>Chrome/Playwright screenshot audit: admin /login shell desktop 1440x900, 390x844, and reduced-motion.</check-5>
    <check-6>git diff --name-only -- install.sh deploy nginx docker-compose.yml</check-6>
    <check-7>Phase-53 user route screenshot audit: auth, dashboard, config, subscription, referrals, settings, and reduced-motion dashboard.</check-7>
    <check-8>Phase-54 local static admin route smoke: /login, /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, /analytics, pointer-safe overlays, reduced-motion markers, and protected-surface guard; authenticated screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up.</check-8>
    <check-9>Phase-59 motion smoke: route motion, reduced-motion, pointer-scroll, keyboard focus, inactive-tab lifecycle, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</check-9>
    <check-10 status="pass-local-phase67">Phase-67 auth/splash smoke: MatrixBackground must tolerate canvas context failure, missing or legacy matchMedia listener APIs, reduced-motion, resize cleanup, and static fallback without console errors.</check-10>
  </module-checks>
  <phase-53-runtime-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>MatrixBackground remains mounted once through VisualShell while user route navigation changes content.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Canvas and CRT overlays remain pointer-events-none and do not intercept VPN config download, copy, QR, tariff checkout, MTProto copy/open, or auth form controls.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion mode renders a readable static Matrix surface across dashboard/config/subscription routes without running animation loops.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Runtime cleanup markers remain available after route navigation, hot reload, unmount, hidden-tab pause, and resize paths.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Phase-53 smoke must fail if Matrix runtime changes deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose or backend runtime topology.</gate-5>
  </phase-53-runtime-gates>
  <phase-54-runtime-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>Admin VisualShell keeps exactly one pointer-safe MatrixBackground mount while protected route content changes.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Canvas and CRT overlays remain pointer-events-none and do not intercept admin login, navigation, search, pagination, confirmation, form, MTProto action, or chart controls.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Reduced-motion mode renders a static readable Matrix admin shell without running animation loops on login and protected route smoke.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Admin route smoke records no console errors from canvas init, resize, hidden-tab pause, cleanup, or unavailable canvas context branches.</gate-4>
    <gate-5>Phase-54 smoke must fail if Matrix runtime changes deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose or backend runtime topology.</gate-5>
  </phase-54-runtime-gates>
  <phase-67-runtime-gates status="pass-local">
    <gate-1>User splash/auth Matrix runtime must use browser feature detection instead of assuming modern matchMedia addEventListener support.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>Canvas 2D context unavailable, zero-size canvas, inactive tab, reduced-motion, and unmount paths must exit cleanly without uncaught errors or duplicate animation loops.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>Fallback rendering must remain readable and pointer-events-none on /, /login, /register, /forgot-password, and /reset-password.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Phase-67 must not change admin runtime behavior except through shared guards that keep existing admin smokes green.</gate-4>
  </phase-67-runtime-gates>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Matrix canvas renders nonblank behind user and admin content without intercepting clicks, keyboard focus, text selection, or mobile scroll.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">VisualShell keeps content in a higher readable layer while the canvas and CRT overlays remain pointer-events-none.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Resize recomputes canvas dimensions and drop columns without accumulating duplicate listeners or animation loops.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Reduced-motion mode renders a static readable Matrix frame and suppresses requestAnimationFrame loops.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Canvas 2D context is unavailable; runtime logs a controlled fallback marker and the app remains usable.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Route navigation and component unmount cancel animation frames, timers, and listeners.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[MatrixVisualRuntime][init][CANVAS_READY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MatrixVisualRuntime][resize][CANVAS_RESIZE]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[MatrixVisualRuntime][motionPolicy][REDUCED_MOTION]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[MatrixVisualRuntime][fallback][CANVAS_CONTEXT_UNAVAILABLE]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MatrixVisualRuntime][cleanup][ANIMATION_STOPPED]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase53][USER_ROUTE_CANVAS_READY]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase53][POINTER_EVENTS_SAFE]</marker-7>
    <marker-8>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase54][ADMIN_ROUTE_CANVAS_READY]</marker-8>
    <marker-9>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase54][POINTER_EVENTS_SAFE]</marker-9>
    <marker-10>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase54][REDUCED_MOTION_ADMIN]</marker-10>
    <marker-11>[MatrixMotion][phase59][INACTIVE_TAB_SAFE]</marker-11>
    <marker-12>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase67][BROWSER_COMPAT_SAFE]</marker-12>
    <marker-13>[MatrixVisualRuntime][phase67][STATIC_FALLBACK_SAFE]</marker-13>
  </required-log-markers>
  <evidence-levels>
    <module-local>Static smoke inspects source contracts, exported components, cleanup paths, reduced-motion branches, and protected imports.</module-local>
    <wave-level>User and admin frontend builds prove shared runtime integration across both apps.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Screenshot/pixel checks prove nonblank canvas, readable content, and reduced-motion behavior on desktop and mobile.</phase-level>
  </evidence-levels>
  <redaction>
    <rule-1>Do not log user emails, access tokens, proxy secrets, tg links, VPN config contents, admin tokens, raw IP history, or screenshot binary data.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Allowed telemetry: viewport dimensions, runtime branch, canvas support state, reduced-motion state, and animation lifecycle state.</rule-2>
  </redaction>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>medium</level>
    <allowed>Implement frontend-only runtime, shell mounts, and smoke checks inside M-070 boundaries.</allowed>
    <blocked>Changing backend APIs, auth state, billing, VPN, MTProto provisioning, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or production runtime topology.</blocked>
    <handoff-trigger>Stop and report if screenshot checks show blank canvas, unreadable content, input interception, or reduced-motion failure.</handoff-trigger>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <acceptance>
    <target-1>User and admin frontend builds pass.</target-1>
    <target-2>Phase-52 smoke passes with runtime lifecycle, protected surface, and redaction checks.</target-2>
    <target-3>Canvas nonblank and reduced-motion screenshot checks pass on mobile and desktop.</target-3>
    <target-4>No protected deploy/install/runtime surface changes are present.</target-4>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-3>
      <command-4>Chrome headless screenshot audit for user/admin /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus --force-prefers-reduced-motion=reduce at 390x844.</command-4>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-user-reduced-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-360x740.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-390x844.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-430x932.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-1440x900.png /tmp/krotpn-phase52-admin-reduced-390x844.png</screenshot-paths>
      <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology diff.</protected-surface>
    </local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-2>
      <command-3>Chrome production-preview screenshot proof for /login, /register, /reset-password, desktop /login, and reduced-motion /login with virtual-time-budget.</command-3>
      <screenshot-paths>/tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-mobile-v5.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/register-mobile-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/reset-mobile-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-desktop-final.png /tmp/krotpn-phase53-shots/login-mobile-reduced-motion.png</screenshot-paths>
      <protected-surface>No install.sh, deploy, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology diff.</protected-surface>
    </phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
      <result>DESIGNED</result>
      <summary>Phase-54 runtime gates require admin VisualShell/MatrixBackground proof across login and protected admin routes, pointer-safe overlays, reduced-motion fallback, console-error guard, and protected deploy/install/runtime isolation.</summary>
    </phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</command-1>
      <command-2>node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</command-2>
      <summary>Static runtime proof passed for admin VisualShell/MatrixBackground source integration, pointer-events-none overlays, reduced-motion admin markers, route matrix markers, and protected deploy/install/runtime isolation.</summary>
      <follow-up>Authenticated protected-route screenshot review remains clean-deploy follow-up because this local execution did not run a real admin backend session.</follow-up>
    </phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-2>
      <summary>VisualShell route motion markers and MatrixBackground reduced-motion, pointer-scroll, and inactive-tab lifecycle markers passed static verification without changing canvas behavior.</summary>
    </phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-67-local-2026-06-04>
      <result>PASS</result>
      <command-1>node scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</command-1>
      <command-2>node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs</command-2>
      <command-3>node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</command-3>
      <summary>MatrixBackground now supports legacy matchMedia listener APIs, missing requestAnimationFrame/cancelAnimationFrame branches, canvas-context fallback, reduced-motion, resize cleanup, and static fallback markers without changing admin runtime behavior.</summary>
    </phase-67-local-2026-06-04>
  </evidence>
</V-M-070>
