<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-053 MODULE="M-053" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="superseded-pass-local">
  <purpose>Verify the Phase-40 official MTProxy secret-sync reference and, for Phase-41, verify that it no longer drives active production issuance.</purpose>
  <phase-41-supersession>
    <item-1>Phase-41 production issuance uses KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI policy via M-043/M-044 instead of official secret manifests.</item-1>
    <item-2>M-053 may remain available only for rollback/reference behavior.</item-2>
  </phase-41-supersession>
  <test-files>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_mtproxy_secret_sync.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_api.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_ops.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_scheduler.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 LEVEL="module-local">cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproxy_secret_sync.py tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py tests/test_mtproto_api.py tests/test_mtproto_admin_ops.py tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py tests/test_scheduler.py -v</check-1>
    <check-2 LEVEL="wave">Run frontend and frontend-admin builds after payload/API shape changes.</check-2>
    <check-3 LEVEL="phase-live">Run Phase-40 live smoke against one newly verified user and one revoked/reissued user without printing secrets.</check-3>
    <check-4 LEVEL="phase-41">Verify active issuance does not render or apply official secret manifests after KPprotoN rollback.</check-4>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Verified user receives one canonical official credential-mode assignment and owner-only secure link with secret=dd&lt;32-hex-secret&gt;.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Repeated verified-registration or dashboard refresh reuses the same active assignment unless explicit reissue is requested.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Active assignments render to a deterministic redacted manifest and apply only when the manifest fingerprint changes.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="success">Admin revoke removes exactly one user secret and preserves unrelated active users.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Admin reissue rotates exactly one user secret, invalidates the old runtime secret, and returns the new owner payload only to the owner.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="success">Startup replay after backend, runtime, or restored-server startup restores all active assignment secrets.</scenario-6>
    <scenario-7 kind="failure">Unverified user receives no MTProxy secret and no runtime apply attempt.</scenario-7>
    <scenario-8 kind="failure">Runtime apply failure returns degraded state, retries safely, and does not block normal KrotPN login.</scenario-8>
    <scenario-9 kind="failure">Oversized manifest or command-line guard prevents unsafe runtime launch and reports scale-out requirement.</scenario-9>
    <scenario-10 kind="success">Phase-41 reissue creates a KPprotoN fake-TLS assignment payload and bypasses official manifest sync.</scenario-10>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[MTProxySecretSync][derive][FINGERPRINT_ONLY]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[MTProxySecretSync][manifest][REDACTED_COUNT]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[MTProxySecretSync][apply][FINGERPRINT_CHANGED]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[MTProxySecretSync][revoke][ASSIGNMENT_ONLY]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[MTProxySecretSync][reissue][ROTATED_ONE]</marker-5>
    <marker-6>[MTProxySecretSync][replay][ACTIVE_COUNT]</marker-6>
    <marker-7>[MTProxySecretSync][degraded][RETRYABLE]</marker-7>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Admin APIs, audit events, health checks, task logs, and smoke output may expose only assignment id, user id when authorized, masked hostname, secret fingerprint, count, status, and timestamps.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Raw secret is allowed only in the authenticated owner payload needed to configure Telegram and must not be persisted in admin-visible fields.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <evidence-levels>
    <level-1>Deterministic unit assertions first: secret format, stable derivation or encrypted persistence contract, owner-only payload, idempotency, redaction, and lifecycle transitions.</level-1>
    <level-2>Trace assertions second: required log markers on create, apply, revoke, reissue, replay, and degraded branches.</level-2>
    <level-3>Integration checks third: scheduler replay, runtime adapter calls, API/admin responses, and UI payload rendering.</level-3>
  </evidence-levels>
  <failure-policy>
    <policy-1>Any raw secret in admin responses, audit events, logs, task output, or smoke output fails verification.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Any revoke or reissue operation affecting more than the target assignment fails verification.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Any MTProxy issuance before email verification fails verification.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Any active user payload returned before runtime apply succeeds or explicitly reports degraded state fails verification.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>After Phase-41 execution, any official manifest apply during normal user issuance fails verification unless rollback is explicit.</policy-5>
  </failure-policy>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design marks official secret sync as superseded for production and requires active issuance to use KPprotoN fake-TLS policy instead.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local execution verified active provisioning, admin actions, and scheduler replay bypass official manifest sync in favor of M-044 KPprotoN policy apply.</evidence-2>
  </evidence>
</V-M-053>
