<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-042 MODULE="M-042" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local" VERSION="1.2.0">
  <module>mtproto-assignment-registry</module>
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-29 status="pass-local">Postgres-backed MTProto assignment registry implemented and verified locally.</phase-29>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
  </test-files>
  <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py tests/test_db_migrations.py -v</commands>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Repository and model tests use isolated DB sessions and deterministic fixtures; no live Telegram, DNS, or host mutation.</module-local>
    <wave-level>Runs with V-M-043 and migration tests so provisioning cannot persist data the registry cannot restore.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Phase-29 cannot pass unless assignment persistence is enough to rebuild owner-safe MTProto payloads after backup/restore.</phase-level>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">Assignment table enforces one canonical active assignment per user.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">SNI uniqueness and lifecycle status transitions are deterministic.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Alembic migration is compatible with SQLModel metadata and existing DB tests.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Persisted state excludes raw tg://proxy links, raw base secret, raw salt, and derived secret unless encrypted storage is explicitly approved.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="restore-fixture">A restore-like fixture can rebuild the public response from user_id, SNI, credential mode, assignment status, and rotation marker.</check-5>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Assignment is saved and read back by user id.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Restore-like fixture preserves user linkage, SNI, credential mode, and status.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="success">Idempotent save for the same verified user returns the existing canonical assignment without changing SNI.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Duplicate SNI or duplicate active user assignment is rejected or converted into an explicit superseded state.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="failure">Unverified, inactive, missing, or deleted users cannot receive active assignments.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Migration drift between SQLModel metadata and Alembic revision fails the gate.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-042][save_assignment][WRITE_ASSIGNMENT]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-042][get_user_assignment][LOOKUP_USER]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-042][list_assignments][REDACT_ADMIN_LIST]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-042][save_assignment][UNIQUENESS_CONFLICT]</marker-4>
    <marker-5>[M-042][migration][MTPROTO_ASSIGNMENT_SCHEMA]</marker-5>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Admin list and repository logs do not contain full tg://proxy links or raw secrets.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Uniqueness and migration errors may include assignment id and user id, but not SNI-derived secret material.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>safe-local-db-only</level>
    <reason>Phase-29 M-042 can be executed autonomously only against local test databases and Alembic metadata checks; production migration apply remains operator-controlled.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: V-M-042 target tests passed locally inside the combined Phase-29 pytest run.</evidence-1>
  </evidence>
</V-M-042>
