<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-003 MODULE="M-003" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local-phase45-pass-local-phase70" PHASE-70="pass-local">
  <module>vpn</module>
  <checks>Provisioning and config generation remain compatible with route-aware topology. QR/config endpoints remain available to verified users with pending trial access before countdown activation. First VPN handshake can start the Phase-45 trial countdown without changing config rendering.</checks>
  <test-files>backend/tests/test_vpn_service.py backend/tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py backend/tests/test_manual_client_cli.py backend/tests/test_trial_activation.py</test-files>
  <commands>pass-local 2026-06-01: Phase-45 backend suite covers VPN compatibility and pending-trial first-config/handshake activation path.</commands>
  <anchors>VPN_PROVISION_ROUTE_SELECTED VPN_CONFIG_RENDERED VPN_PEER_APPLIED PENDING_TRIAL_ACCESS</anchors>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="VPN_PROVISION_ROUTE_SELECTED">Provisioning selects correct topology and routing policy</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="VPN_CONFIG_RENDERED">Config rendered successfully for provisioned client</scenario>
    <scenario kind="success" trace="PENDING_TRIAL_ACCESS">Pending trial user can retrieve first VPN config before countdown starts</scenario>
  </scenarios>
  <evidence>2026-06-01: Phase-45 backend suite passed with tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py and tests/test_trial_activation.py.</evidence>
  <phase-70-verification-design status="pass-local">
    <scope>VPN configuration payload and QR parity verification.</scope>
    <gate-1>Frontend QR, backend QR endpoint, and deploy/create-client generated QR must encode the same WireGuard/AWG config text for the same client fixture.</gate-1>
    <gate-2>QR readability changes must be limited to rendering parameters such as size, margin, or error-correction level after payload parity is proven.</gate-2>
    <gate-3>WireGuard/AWG profile fields, keys, endpoints, DNS, AllowedIPs, and interface/peer sections must not change during Phase-70.</gate-3>
    <gate-4>Decoded QR roundtrip must match the downloadable .conf payload exactly after normalizing line endings only.</gate-4>
    <commands>cd backend &amp;&amp; pytest tests/test_vpn_service.py tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py tests/test_manual_client_cli.py; node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</commands>
    <blocked>Phase-70 must not edit deploy/create-client.sh, VPN server runtime, or generated client semantics unless a separate confirmed phase is created.</blocked>
  </phase-70-verification-design>
  <phase-70-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">
    <command-1>cd backend &amp;&amp; SECRET_KEY=test-secret-key-with-enough-length DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY=dpFmfSVqfdAK3yx5MQV6Tcv35RZuw5MzaH0yhxJ01q0= PYTHONPATH=. ../.venv/bin/python -m pytest -o addopts='' tests/test_vpn_router_compat.py tests/test_vpn_service.py tests/test_manual_client_cli.py -v</command-1>
    <command-2>node scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</command-2>
    <summary>API config, download bytes, and backend QR payload source match exactly; QR rendering uses level M without changing config fields, keys, endpoint, DNS, AllowedIPs, or AWG profile content.</summary>
  </phase-70-evidence>
</V-M-003>
