<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-010 MODULE="M-010" PRIORITY="high" STATUS="pass" VERSION="1.1.0">
  <module>frontend-admin</module>
  <checks>Admin frontend builds and reflects current admin, Full Tunnel, system, analytics, and device-control surfaces without auth regression.</checks>
  <test-files>frontend-admin/src/main.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts frontend-admin/src/stores/auth.ts frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts frontend-admin/src/index.css</test-files>
  <commands>cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build</commands>
  <levels>
    <module-local>Run npm build after frontend-admin route, component, API binding, or type changes.</module-local>
    <wave-level>During Phase-24, pair the build with V-M-037 mobile smoke for /, /users, /devices, and /analytics.</wave-level>
    <phase-level>Frontend-admin remains pass only if auth guard, route registration, and admin API bindings compile after compact UI changes.</phase-level>
  </levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1>Routes /login, /, /users, /devices, /servers, /plans, and /analytics remain registered.</check-1>
    <check-2>Layout, Dashboard, Users, Devices, Analytics, Servers, and Plans compile against current types.</check-2>
    <check-3>adminApi base path remains /api/v1 unless a separate backend/API migration is approved.</check-3>
    <check-4>Device API binding names remain getDevices, blockDevice, unblockDevice, rotateDevice, and revokeDevice.</check-4>
    <check-5>Phase-24 does not change auth/session storage behavior; M-039 owns that in Phase-25.</check-5>
    <check-6>Admin auth store clears admin_refresh_token whenever admin_token is cleared.</check-6>
    <check-7>Admin login email/password fields do not expose stale default credential placeholders.</check-7>
    <check-8>Admin inputs with left icons use shared icon padding so the icon and placeholder/value text cannot overlap.</check-8>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Admin login route and protected layout still build after compact UI changes.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="success">Dashboard, users, devices, servers, plans, and analytics routes compile against existing admin API bindings.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">A frontend-admin UI simplification changes auth, admin API base path, or backend endpoint shape without approval.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">A compact navigation change drops /devices, /users, or /analytics from the registered protected route surface.</scenario-4>
  </scenarios>
  <observability>
    <telemetry-1>Build evidence records command, exit code, and failing TypeScript/Vite output if any.</telemetry-1>
    <telemetry-2>Do not record real admin tokens, refresh tokens, Authorization headers, or cookies in frontend-admin evidence.</telemetry-2>
  </observability>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-10: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed after Phase-24 compact admin UI changes.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-10: Route/API binding static guard confirmed /users, /devices, /analytics, /api/v1, and existing device endpoint names.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-10: Phase-25 admin refresh compatibility fix added; rebuild required by V-M-039/V-M-010.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-10: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed after admin refresh-token persistence cleanup.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-21: Local admin UI fix removed login placeholders, removed stale admin@krotpn.com fallback copy, and passed frontend-admin build.</evidence-5>
  </evidence>
</V-M-010>
