<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<V-M-040 MODULE="M-040" PRIORITY="critical" STATUS="pass-local" VERSION="1.4.0">
  <phase-scope>
    <phase-27>Email delivery foundation only: fake-provider tests must prove request shaping, template rendering, provider error mapping, and redaction before live provider use.</phase-27>
    <phase-34 status="planned">Stabilization regression gate proves verification-email delivery still participates in pending registration without leaking tokens or provider secrets.</phase-34>
    <phase-36 status="planned">Resend production wiring proves clean deployments enable EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend without exposing API keys or verification tokens.</phase-36>
  </phase-scope>
  <test-files>
    <file>backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py</file>
    <file phase="36-planned">scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</file>
  </test-files>
  <verification-levels>
    <module-local>Unit tests use a fake provider/client and never require live email credentials.</module-local>
    <phase-level>Phase-27 combines this suite with V-M-041 guard tests and MyGRACE XML lint.</phase-level>
    <integration-later>Live provider smoke is operator-run only after environment secrets are configured outside tests.</integration-later>
  </verification-levels>
  <module-checks>
    <check-1 evidence="deterministic">Email template renders readable UTF-8 subject, HTML, and text fallback with KrotPN branding.</check-1>
    <check-2 evidence="deterministic">Verification link/code is accepted as input but never appears in logs, exceptions, or provider error payloads.</check-2>
    <check-3 evidence="deterministic">Provider success returns a typed delivery receipt containing only safe message metadata.</check-3>
    <check-4 evidence="deterministic">Provider 401, 429, 5xx, timeout, and transport failures map to stable internal error codes.</check-4>
    <check-5 evidence="deterministic">Missing or disabled provider configuration blocks send with an operator-safe error and no network call.</check-5>
    <check-6 evidence="phase-34-regression">Phase-34 full registration suite confirms email delivery is invoked only for pending registration and never after MTProto owner payload generation.</check-6>
    <check-7 evidence="phase-36-planned">Resend request shape uses https://api.resend.com/emails, Authorization Bearer API key, noreply@krotpn.xyz sender, and HTML/text verification template payload.</check-7>
    <check-8 evidence="phase-36-planned">Deploy smoke proves EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend and RESEND_API_KEY are present when operator supplied the key, while logs and tests redact the key.</check-8>
  </module-checks>
  <scenarios>
    <scenario-1 kind="success">Verification email is sent to a normalized allowed email address through the fake provider.</scenario-1>
    <scenario-2 kind="failure">Provider authentication, rate-limit, server, timeout, and transport errors are surfaced as safe typed failures.</scenario-2>
    <scenario-3 kind="failure">Logs never contain verification token, verification URL, API key, or raw provider response body.</scenario-3>
    <scenario-4 kind="failure">Provider-disabled configuration returns a typed disabled-provider result before request construction.</scenario-4>
    <scenario-5 kind="success">Clean VPS deployment with a supplied Resend API key sends pending-registration verification email through Resend.</scenario-5>
    <scenario-6 kind="failure">Missing Resend API key fails with an operator-safe configuration error and no live registration side effects.</scenario-6>
  </scenarios>
  <required-log-markers>
    <marker-1>[M-040][send_verification_email][BUILD_REQUEST]</marker-1>
    <marker-2>[M-040][send_verification_email][POST_PROVIDER]</marker-2>
    <marker-3>[M-040][send_verification_email][MAP_PROVIDER_ERROR]</marker-3>
    <marker-4>[M-040][send_verification_email][PROVIDER_DISABLED]</marker-4>
  </required-log-markers>
  <redaction-rules>
    <rule-1>Never log verification links, tokens, provider API keys, SMTP credentials, or full provider response bodies.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Email addresses in logs must be normalized and masked where possible; provider message IDs are allowed.</rule-2>
  </redaction-rules>
  <autonomous-execution-safety>
    <level>safe</level>
    <reason>Phase-27 tests are deterministic and fake-provider-only; no deploy, install, DNS, TLS, or live email provider changes are allowed.</reason>
  </autonomous-execution-safety>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-13: backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py passed locally, covering template rendering, fake-provider dispatch, provider-disabled guard, redaction, and safe error mapping.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: Phase-36 planning scoped Resend deploy wiring after live clean VPS registration returned provider_disabled because EMAIL_PROVIDER was left disabled.</evidence-2>
  </evidence>
</V-M-040>
