<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-001 NAME="backend-core" TYPE="UTILITY" STATUS="stable">
  <path>backend/app/core</path>
  <owns>settings, security (JWT, password hashing, Fernet encryption, token blacklist), DB sessions, dependency injection, admin bootstrap, topology bootstrap, database migrations, AWG stealth profile settings, anti-abuse runtime settings, verified-registration email settings, and MTProto provisioning settings</owns>
  <exports>
    <fn-settings>Runtime configuration values and environment parsing</fn-settings>
    <fn-init-db>Database initialization and session lifecycle</fn-init-db>
    <fn-get-fernet>Fernet encryption with explicit DATA_ENCRYPTION_KEY requirement</fn-get-fernet>
    <fn-token-blacklist>Redis-based JWT token revocation</fn-token-blacklist>
    <fn-migrations>Database migration helpers extracted from database.py</fn-migrations>
    <fn-awg-profile-settings>Validated environment settings for CLIENT_PROFILE and RELAY_PROFILE obfuscation values</fn-awg-profile-settings>
    <fn-anti-abuse-settings>Validated ANTI_ABUSE_* mode, scan interval, history window, ping-pong window and cooldown values</fn-anti-abuse-settings>
    <fn-email-verification-settings>EMAIL_PROVIDER, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL, EMAIL_FROM, verification TTL, provider timeout, SMTP credentials, verification URL base, allow/deny/disposable domain knobs, and DNS guard toggle</fn-email-verification-settings>
    <fn-mtproto-settings>MTPROTO_BASE_DOMAIN, MTPROTO_PROXY_PORT, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, MTPROTO_SNI_PREFIX, and MTPROTO_ROTATION_MARKER validation with blank optional secrets normalized to unset</fn-mtproto-settings>
    <fn-edge-domain-settings>EDGE_PUBLIC_DOMAIN, EDGE_CANONICAL_HOST, EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_PATH, EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_KEY_PATH, EDGE_TLS_CERTIFICATE_MODE, and EDGE_SHARED_443_ENABLED validation</fn-edge-domain-settings>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-028</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-001</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/database.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/security.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/dependencies.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/init_admin.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/init_vpn.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/migrations.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/migrations_legacy.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/__init__.py</file>
  </files>
  <disaster-recovery-role>
    <role-1>Phase-22 application validation must prove settings, database sessions, Redis/token-blacklist behavior, admin bootstrap assumptions, and encryption keys are restored before cutover.</role-1>
    <role-2>Health/auth smoke evidence must not print secrets or raw environment values.</role-2>
  </disaster-recovery-role>
  <hotspot>H-011: Token blacklist depends on Redis — graceful degradation must not break auth</hotspot>
  <hotspot>H-014: Admin audit middleware must not log sensitive bodies or tokens</hotspot>
  <hotspot>H-026: Email provider secrets and verification tokens must never leak through settings-driven logs or errors</hotspot>
  <hotspot>H-030: MTProto base secret and salt must stay runtime-only and never appear in logs or persisted assignment rows</hotspot>
  <hotspot>H-032: krotpn.xyz domain TLS and shared 443 settings must not leak secrets or create unsafe production claims before trusted wildcard TLS is ready</hotspot>
  <phase-36-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="planned">Keep Resend settings env-backed and validated by backend Settings without logging API keys or raw provider payloads.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="planned">Support deploy-generated EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend, RESEND_API_KEY, RESEND_API_URL, EMAIL_FROM, and EMAIL_VERIFICATION_URL_BASE values for production registration.</step-2>
  </phase-36-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: Clean VPS Phase-35 hotfix normalized blank MTProto secret env values to None so backend startup can degrade MTProto provisioning instead of crashing normal KrotPN runtime.</evidence-1>
  </evidence>
</M-001>
