<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-012 NAME="deploy-surface" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="stable">
  <path>deploy install.sh nginx docker-compose.yml scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-36.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml</path>
  <owns>installation, deploy scripts, runtime composition, proxying, operator wildcard TLS install, Resend email provider env wiring, dev-only cert generation, host-tool preflight, AWG stealth profile generation, awg0 peer sync watchers, deploy-time secret handling, backup/restore, nginx hardening, and planned DE-backed MTProto edge rollout</owns>
  <depends>M-003, M-007, M-019, M-030, M-050</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-012</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-all.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/lib/awg-obfuscation.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/quick-start.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/create-client.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/remove-client.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/rollback.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/backup-db.sh</file>
    <file>install.sh</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <disaster-recovery-role>
    <role-1>Phase-22 uses the existing deploy/install surface as an operator-approved black box for replacement-server provisioning.</role-1>
    <role-2>Phase-22 recovery planning must not redesign, edit, or bypass deploy/ or install.sh.</role-2>
  </disaster-recovery-role>
  <hotspot>H-015: Deploy idempotency must preserve WG keys, SSL certs, .env across repeated runs</hotspot>
  <hotspot>H-017: Fresh deploys may generate obfuscation profiles, but upgrades must preserve profiles unless rotation is explicit</hotspot>
  <phase-36-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Ask for Resend API key and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender during clean production install.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Materialize EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend and Resend env values into /opt/KrotPN/.env without printing the API key.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Fail deploy readiness explicitly when Resend is required but missing, preventing later provider_disabled registration errors.</step-3>
  </phase-36-plan>
  <phase-38-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pending">Extend the deployment contract for a DE-hosted MTProto runtime while preserving the operator-approved install flow.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pending">Add RU SNI router and DE runtime wiring only after static smoke proves HTTPS fallback and policy API safety.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pending">Keep rollback to nginx-only public 443 documented before any public port ownership change.</step-3>
  </phase-38-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: Phase-35 changed the deploy surface so production installs consume validated operator wildcard TLS files instead of silently generating self-signed certificates.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: Clean VPS hotfix generates MTProto base secret and salt during deploy .env creation so backend Settings validation does not restart-loop after first compose startup.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-17: Phase-36 added redacted Resend deploy config handoff and /opt/KrotPN/.env generation for EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Phase-38 plan adds DE-backed MTProto edge deployment as the next step after RU-only mtproto_proxy live blocking.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
</M-012>
