<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-010 NAME="frontend-admin" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="stable-pass-local-phase51-phase52-phase54-phase59-pass-local-minimal-login">
  <path>frontend-admin frontend-admin/public frontend-admin/index.html scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-54.xml docs/plans/Phase-59.xml</path>
  <owns>admin login, mobile-capable dashboard, users, devices, MTProto operations, servers, plans, analytics, settings, Full Tunnel status, and device anomaly review controls</owns>
  <depends>M-006, M-024, M-070, M-071, M-077</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-010</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/main.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/index.html</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/public/favicon.ico</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/public/favicon-16x16.png</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/public/favicon-32x32.png</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/public/apple-touch-icon.png</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/stores/auth.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <phase-25-scope>
    <surface-1>Admin login persists admin_refresh_token so the existing 401 refresh interceptor can operate.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Admin logout and setToken(null) clear admin_refresh_token together with admin_token.</surface-2>
  </phase-25-scope>
  <phase-33-scope>
    <surface-1>Compact /mtproto admin page renders redacted assignment rows and runtime health.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Reissue and revoke actions use explicit confirmation and call M-047 endpoints only.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>Admin navigation exposes MTProto without changing deploy/install or public edge surfaces.</surface-3>
  </phase-33-scope>
  <phase-24-scope>
    <surface-1>Compact mobile admin shell and overview.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Mobile-safe users and devices pages without table-only primary workflows.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>Confirmation-safe device actions using existing M-024 admin endpoints.</surface-3>
    <surface-4>Analytics/payment/system summaries that remain readable on phone viewports.</surface-4>
  </phase-24-scope>
  <phase-51-scope>
    <surface-1>Admin browser favicon and Apple touch icon are served from frontend-admin public assets.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>No visible admin panel logo/layout change is introduced before the planned frontend redesign.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>2026-06-02: frontend-admin npm run build passed and Phase-51 smoke --expect-dist verified the browser asset surface.</surface-3>
  </phase-51-scope>
  <phase-52-scope>
    <surface-1>Shared Matrix visual shell wraps the admin route tree without changing admin auth, route structure, API clients, MTProto operations, billing, or deploy behavior.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>2026-06-03: frontend-admin npm run build passed; Phase-52 smoke passed; Chrome screenshots for /login at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, and reduced-motion 390x844 passed visual review.</surface-2>
  </phase-52-scope>
  <phase-54-verification-design>
    <surface-1>Admin route redesign verification covers /login, /, /users, /devices, /mtproto, /servers, /plans, and /analytics in the Matrix shell.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Execution gate is cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build plus scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs with mobile, tablet, desktop, reduced-motion, confirmation, redaction, and protected-surface checks.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>Phase-54 remains frontend-admin UI only and must not change admin auth/session, API clients, backend schemas, billing, MTProto runtime, deploy, install, nginx, or docker-compose surfaces.</surface-3>
  </phase-54-verification-design>
  <phase-54-execution>
    <surface-1>Admin login, layout, dashboard, users, devices, MTProto, MTProto analytics, servers, plans, analytics, StatCard, and shared admin CSS were retuned into compact Matrix operator surfaces.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs now gates route registration, compact primitives, bounded lists, confirmation markers, MTProto redaction, canonical Plans readonly behavior, reduced-motion markers, and protected deploy/install isolation.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>2026-06-03: cd frontend-admin &amp;&amp; npm run build passed; node scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs passed.</surface-3>
    <surface-4>2026-06-04: Admin login follow-up reduces /login to a large unframed logo, email/password inputs, error state, and submit action while preserving the admin API role gate.</surface-4>
  </phase-54-execution>
  <phase-59-scope>
    <surface-1>Admin VisualShell/MatrixBackground and shared CSS expose Phase-59 route motion, reduced-motion, pointer-scroll, focus, and inactive-tab safety markers.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Devices, MTProto, and MTProtoAnalytics add compact feedback/status motion classes without changing API clients, admin auth, deploy, install, or runtime behavior.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>2026-06-04: frontend-admin npm run build passed; Phase-59 smoke passed; post-commit Phase-58 regression smoke passed; protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</surface-3>
  </phase-59-scope>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Frontend-admin must continue to call existing M-006 and M-024 API contracts unless an API change is separately approved.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Admin auth/session hardening belongs to Phase-25 and must not be bundled into Phase-24 UI simplification.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Deployment and install scripts are out of scope for this UI module phase.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Admin login inputs must not prefill or hint stale default credentials; icon-bearing inputs must reserve enough padding so icons and placeholder text never overlap.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Admin login must not show informational route cards, helper copy, default credentials, or non-essential operator text unless a later approved phase reintroduces it.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-21: Local admin UI fix removed login email/password placeholders, removed stale admin@krotpn.com fallback copy, and standardized left-icon input padding.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-06-03: Phase-54 local execution passed frontend-admin build and admin Matrix UI smoke without deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime changes.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-04: Minimal admin login fix passed Phase-54 smoke updates and frontend-admin build with only logo, fields, error state, and Войти action visible.</evidence-3>
  </evidence>
</M-010>
