<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-037 NAME="mobile-admin-console" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pending">
  <path>frontend-admin docs/plans/Phase-24.xml</path>
  <owns>Compact mobile-first admin console for operational status, users, devices, payments, analytics summary, system health, and emergency device actions</owns>
  <exports>
    <view-admin-mobile-overview>Dense service overview with health, users, subscriptions, revenue, VPN/system status, and urgent navigation</view-admin-mobile-overview>
    <view-admin-mobile-users>Searchable mobile user list with role, status, identity, last-login, subscription/payment, and device summary paths</view-admin-mobile-users>
    <view-admin-mobile-devices>Compact device registry with user/device/status/signals fields optimized for phone scanning</view-admin-mobile-devices>
    <view-admin-mobile-device-actions>Block, unblock, rotate, and revoke device controls with explicit confirmation and feedback</view-admin-mobile-device-actions>
    <view-admin-mobile-payments>Compact payment/analytics status for revenue, subscriptions, referrals, and conversion signals</view-admin-mobile-payments>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-006, M-010, M-024, M-038</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-037</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-24.xml</file>
  </files>
  <data-flows>
    <DF-UI-ADMIN-OVERVIEW>Stats and system health render as a compact first-screen operator status surface.</DF-UI-ADMIN-OVERVIEW>
    <DF-UI-ADMIN-USER-SEARCH>Admin searches users and reads compact account rows without table-only mobile dependency.</DF-UI-ADMIN-USER-SEARCH>
    <DF-UI-ADMIN-DEVICE-ACTION>Admin selects one device action, confirms the exact peer target, calls the existing endpoint, then sees refreshed status and feedback.</DF-UI-ADMIN-DEVICE-ACTION>
    <DF-UI-ADMIN-PAYMENT-STATUS>Billing and analytics status stays reachable from mobile navigation without backend/provider changes.</DF-UI-ADMIN-PAYMENT-STATUS>
  </data-flows>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Admin emergency actions must remain visible from phone navigation and require clear confirmation.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Mobile admin UI must avoid desktop-only tables, oversized dashboard cards, nested card layouts, and decorative hero sections.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Audit-sensitive actions must preserve existing backend audit behavior and show success/error feedback after mutation.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Device actions must target one peer/device and must not imply or trigger whole-account disablement.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Deploy/install scripts, backend business rules, and Phase-25 session handling are out of scope.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <hotspot>H-024: Mobile admin console must keep emergency operator actions visible without desktop-only dashboards</hotspot>
</M-037>
