<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-033 NAME="mygrace-integrity-cleanup" TYPE="UTILITY" STATUS="wip">
  <path>docs/graph-index.xml docs/plan-index.xml docs/verification-index.xml docs/plans/Phase-21.xml</path>
  <owns>MyGRACE index consistency, stale Full Tunnel cleanup references, active verification surface correctness, and AI handoff accuracy</owns>
  <exports>
    <check-index-sync>Verifies graph, plan, and verification indexes match per-entity files</check-index-sync>
    <check-obsolete-routing-artifacts>Identifies active tests or docs that still require removed split-tunnel modules</check-obsolete-routing-artifacts>
    <check-handoff-read-order>Ensures README and project docs point agents to MyGRACE indexes, not monolithic GRACE files</check-handoff-read-order>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-006, M-007, M-017</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-033</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>docs/graph-index.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plan-index.xml</file>
    <file>docs/verification-index.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-21.xml</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not change runtime behavior while cleaning documentation and verification references.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Historical references may remain only when explicitly archived or superseded.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <execution-notes>
    <note-1>Phase-21 step-1 audit classified stale routing references as active cleanup targets, historical/superseded references, or valid Full Tunnel regression assertions.</note-1>
    <note-2>Phase-21 step-4 archived obsolete routing-policy/ipset tests under backend/tests/archive/phase17_removed_routing with non-test filenames to keep pytest collection aligned with Full Tunnel runtime.</note-2>
    <note-3>Phase-21 step-5 synchronized index comments, dependency CrossLinks, AI handoff text, and active frontend-admin per-entity wording with MyGRACE and Full Tunnel reality.</note-3>
  </execution-notes>
  <hotspot>H-020: Stale split-tunnel tests and phase references can break verification even when runtime Full Tunnel code is correct</hotspot>
</M-033>
