<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-035 NAME="portable-data-backup" TYPE="DATA_LAYER" STATUS="blocked-live">
  <path>backend/app/core docs/plans/Phase-22.xml docs/modules/M-035.xml docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml docs/recovery/DRY-RUN-PHASE-22.xml</path>
  <owns>Portable backup/restore contract for PostgreSQL data, runtime secrets, AWG state, device-client linkage, MTProto assignments, and integrity manifests</owns>
  <exports>
    <artifact-postgres-dump>Durable dump of users, subscriptions, payments, devices, VPN clients, MTProto assignments, audit events, and migrations state</artifact-postgres-dump>
    <artifact-runtime-secrets>Protected copy of .env and required deployment secrets without log exposure</artifact-runtime-secrets>
    <artifact-vpn-state>AWG profile, server keys, peer state, subnet settings, and client linkage needed for restore</artifact-vpn-state>
    <artifact-restore-manifest>Checksums, creation timestamp, schema version, and item counts for restore verification</artifact-restore-manifest>
    <artifact-restore-evidence>Before/after table counts, checksum verification, migration state, and restore notes</artifact-restore-evidence>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001, M-003, M-020, M-028, M-030, M-042, M-043</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-035</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-22.xml</file>
    <file>docs/modules/M-035.xml</file>
    <file>docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml</file>
    <file>docs/recovery/DRY-RUN-PHASE-22.xml</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Secrets, tokens, passwords, and private keys must not be printed in command output or logs.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Restore validation must compare counts and checksums before cutover.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Existing client configs must not be silently invalidated unless operator explicitly chooses rotation.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Backup bundle must include enough runtime and VPN state to boot replacement servers without guessing missing values.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Any mismatch in schema version, checksums, or critical table counts blocks cutover until explicitly waived by the operator.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <backup-bundle-contract>
    <item-manifest>manifest.json with app version, schema version, created_at, artifact list, checksums, and table counts.</item-manifest>
    <item-postgres>postgres.dump for users, subscriptions, payments, devices, VPN clients, MTProto assignments, plans, audit events, and migration state.</item-postgres>
    <item-runtime-env>Protected runtime env material required by backend, database, Redis, billing, Telegram, and admin bootstrap.</item-runtime-env>
    <item-vpn-state>AWG profiles, server keys, peer state, subnet settings, and device-client linkage.</item-vpn-state>
    <item-evidence>table_counts.before.json, table_counts.after.json, checksums.sha256, migration_state.txt, and restore_notes.md.</item-evidence>
  </backup-bundle-contract>
  <execution-notes>
    <note-1>Phase-22 step-2 created docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml with maintenance/freeze sequence, pre-backup evidence, and secret-redaction policy.</note-1>
    <note-2>Phase-22 step-3 expanded docs/recovery/BACKUP-PHASE-22.xml with required bundle artifacts, manifest fields, and checksum rules.</note-2>
    <note-3>Phase-22 step-4 added restore integrity gates for schema/migration state, checksums, table counts, selected row invariants, and no-secret-log evidence.</note-3>
    <note-4>Phase-22 step-6 linked restore sequence evidence outputs to bundle validation, after-restore counts, VPN fingerprints, and service-start notes.</note-4>
    <note-5>Phase-22 step-9 added cutover evidence retention requirements for rollback and incident handoff.</note-5>
    <note-6>Phase-22 step-10 recorded required dry-run restore evidence and blocked-live checks because no backup bundle or restore target was available locally.</note-6>
    <note-7>Phase-34 added MTProto assignment and rotation-marker coverage to backup counts, restore invariants, and release handoff.</note-7>
  </execution-notes>
  <hotspot>H-022: Backup bundles can expose secrets or fail restore if they omit AWG profiles, runtime env, or device/client linkage</hotspot>
</M-035>
