<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-038 NAME="compact-ui-system" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done">
  <path>frontend frontend-admin docs/plans/Phase-23.xml docs/plans/Phase-24.xml</path>
  <owns>Shared compact UI rules for user and admin frontends: mobile-first layout, dense information surfaces, simple navigation, and readable controls</owns>
  <exports>
    <rule-mobile-layout>Responsive layout rules for phone-first screens without horizontal scroll</rule-mobile-layout>
    <rule-compact-controls>Standard sizes and interaction patterns for buttons, lists, tabs, dialogs, and confirmations</rule-compact-controls>
    <rule-content-priority>Priority order for visible information on user and admin mobile surfaces</rule-content-priority>
    <rule-visual-density>Reduced spacing, restrained panels, and non-decorative backgrounds for operational screens</rule-visual-density>
    <rule-safe-text>Wrapping, truncation, and stable sizing rules for long emails, device keys, status labels, and payment text</rule-safe-text>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009, M-010</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-038</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Users.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/StatCard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-23.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-24.xml</file>
  </files>
  <rules>
    <rule-1>Operational pages start with the usable product surface, not a marketing hero or explanatory landing section.</rule-1>
    <rule-2>Cards must not be nested inside other cards; page sections should be flat, dense, and scan-friendly.</rule-2>
    <rule-3>Use compact list rows, segmented controls, tabs, icon buttons, and concise labels instead of large decorative card grids.</rule-3>
    <rule-4>Phone navigation must keep primary actions reachable without a 320px desktop sidebar or repeated identity/status panels.</rule-4>
    <rule-5>Text must not overlap adjacent content; critical values must wrap or truncate intentionally within stable containers.</rule-5>
    <rule-6>Prefer lucide icons in action buttons where an icon exists; do not replace familiar icons with text-only controls.</rule-6>
    <rule-7>Reduce large border radii and glass styling during execution; target compact operational panels rather than oversized rounded sections.</rule-7>
    <rule-8>Do not use decorative radial-gradient/orb backgrounds as the visual basis for the cabinet or admin work surfaces.</rule-8>
    <rule-9>Destructive or disruptive admin actions must use confirmation-safe mobile affordances instead of immediate table-row mutations.</rule-9>
    <rule-10>Charts and secondary analytics panels must collapse behind concise KPI summaries on phone-first admin surfaces.</rule-10>
  </rules>
  <phase-boundaries>
    <phase-23>User frontend adopts compact UI rules for the personal cabinet.</phase-23>
    <phase-24>Admin frontend adopted the same compact UI rules for operator overview, users, devices, payments, analytics, and system health workflows.</phase-24>
    <phase-25>Session security changes are separate and must not be bundled into UI simplification.</phase-25>
  </phase-boundaries>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No new marketing-style landing pages for operational surfaces.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Use compact lists, segmented views, and clear action buttons instead of heavy decorative card grids.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Text must fit on mobile without overlap, truncation of critical values, or horizontal scroll.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Do not touch deploy/install scripts while applying UI rules.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Do not mix session token hardening into compact UI execution; Phase-25 owns that risk.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <verification>
    <viewport-1>360x740 phone viewport</viewport-1>
    <viewport-2>390x844 phone viewport</viewport-2>
    <viewport-3>430x932 phone viewport</viewport-3>
    <check-1>No document-level horizontal scroll.</check-1>
    <check-2>No text overlap in nav, buttons, rows, modals, or status areas.</check-2>
    <check-3>Primary action buttons have stable dimensions across loading, empty, success, and error states.</check-3>
    <check-4>Admin device confirmations stay usable at 360x740, 390x844, and 430x932.</check-4>
  </verification>
  <execution-notes>
    <note-1>Phase-23 user frontend compact UI passed local build and mobile smoke.</note-1>
    <note-2>Phase-24 admin frontend compact UI passed local build and Chrome/CDP mobile smoke.</note-2>
    <note-3>M-038 is done locally for the planned user/admin compact UI scope; Phase-25 session security remains separate.</note-3>
  </execution-notes>
</M-038>
