<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-036 NAME="mobile-user-cabinet" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pass-local-phase46-phase53-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase69-pass-local-phase70-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72-pass-local-phase73-pass-local-phase76">
  <path>frontend scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-23.xml docs/plans/Phase-45.xml docs/plans/Phase-46.xml docs/plans/Phase-53.xml docs/plans/Phase-68.xml docs/plans/Phase-69.xml docs/plans/Phase-70.xml docs/plans/Phase-71.xml docs/plans/Phase-72.xml docs/plans/Phase-73.xml</path>
  <owns>Compact mobile-first personal cabinet for VPN status, subscription state, trial countdown/calendar, device management, and config access</owns>
  <exports>
    <view-mobile-home>Single compact home surface with VPN status, subscription state, and primary config action</view-mobile-home>
    <view-mobile-config>Selected-device config workflow with QR, .conf download, copy, and device controls without visible raw-config diagnostics bloat</view-mobile-config>
    <view-mobile-devices>Small-screen device list with create, rotate, revoke, and selected-device config actions</view-mobile-devices>
    <view-mobile-billing>Compact subscription and payment action surface</view-mobile-billing>
    <view-mobile-countdown-calendar>Compact Phase-45 pending-first-VPN state, remaining days/hours/minutes, and active subscription date calendar</view-mobile-countdown-calendar>
    <view-mobile-empty-states>Phone-safe unavailable, expired, loading, and error states with actionable next steps</view-mobile-empty-states>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-002, M-003, M-004, M-005, M-022, M-038, M-071</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-036</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase69-referral-bonus-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-23.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-45.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-46.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-53.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-68.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-69.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-70.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-71.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-72.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-73.xml</file>
  </files>
  <workflows>
    <DF-UI-USER-HOME>Dashboard aggregates auth/user stats, VPN stats, subscription state, and device summary into the first mobile screen.</DF-UI-USER-HOME>
    <DF-UI-CONFIG-ACTION>Primary config action opens QR/download/copy for the current or newly created device without requiring a desktop layout.</DF-UI-CONFIG-ACTION>
    <DF-UI-DEVICE-MANAGEMENT>Device create, rotate, revoke, and config retrieval remain available through compact rows and confirmation-safe controls.</DF-UI-DEVICE-MANAGEMENT>
    <DF-UI-BILLING>Subscription page and dashboard renewal CTA preserve the existing billing API contract and payment redirect behavior while rendering Phase-45 pending/countdown/calendar state.</DF-UI-BILLING>
    <DF-UI-MTPROTO-PROXY>Dashboard shows the authenticated owner's Telegram MTProto proxy state and copy/open actions without hiding VPN trial or config actions.</DF-UI-MTPROTO-PROXY>
    <DF-UI-MTPROTO-DUAL-LINKS>Dashboard exposes Telegram app tg:// and browser https://t.me proxy links through compact owner-only actions.</DF-UI-MTPROTO-DUAL-LINKS>
  </workflows>
  <content-priority>
    <primary>VPN status, config action, QR/download, subscription state, trial countdown/calendar, device slots, active device rows</primary>
    <secondary>Telegram MTProto proxy state, traffic counters, last handshake, referral CTA, profile/settings shortcuts, raw config text</secondary>
    <removable-from-first-screen>Decorative hero copy, repeated identity panels, large status card grids, explanatory marketing text</removable-from-first-screen>
  </content-priority>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Primary VPN config and subscription actions must be reachable within one or two taps on a phone.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Avoid wide tables, nested cards, decorative hero blocks, and horizontal scrolling.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Keep existing backend API contracts unless a separate contract change is approved.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Do not change deploy, install, Docker, nginx, or remote-server automation surfaces in this phase.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Do not mix session token storage hardening into this phase; that is owned by M-039 and Phase-25.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1>360x740, 390x844, and 430x932 viewports render without horizontal document scroll.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Config QR/download/copy path is reachable from the mobile home within one or two taps.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Device create, rotate, revoke, and selected config retrieval remain present after simplification.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm run build passes.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>Phase-31 MTProto card renders without horizontal scroll and keeps VPN config/subscription actions reachable.</metric-5>
    <metric-6>Phase-45 subscription UX smoke passes for pending trial copy, server-derived countdown fields, active-date calendar marker, and stale 3-day copy guard.</metric-6>
    <metric-7>Phase-46 UX smoke passes for password example, MTProto dual links, Russian labels, and bounded status refresh.</metric-7>
    <metric-8>Phase-53 smoke and screenshot review pass for compact Matrix dashboard/config/subscription/referrals/settings routes without protected deploy/install changes.</metric-8>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <phase-69-scope>
    <primary-files>Referrals.tsx, SubscriptionPanel.tsx, lib/api.ts</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Mobile-safe masked referral history rows and truthful pending referral-bonus subscription copy.</primary-behaviors>
  </phase-69-scope>
  <phase-70-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Phone-safe config page keeps QR/download/copy/device controls while QR rendering is visually lighter and payload-identical.</primary-behaviors>
  </phase-70-scope>
  <phase-71-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Phone and tablet config route must present a compact device list, selected-device detail, sticky QR/.conf/Copy actions, and separated destructive actions without horizontal scroll or bottom-nav overlap.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>Users with 9 devices can select any device and export config on 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, and tablet viewports without wide tables or long uncontrolled action rows.</acceptance>
  </phase-71-executed-scope>
  <evidence>2026-06-01: frontend npm run build passed, node scripts/phase45-trial-subscription-ux-smoke.mjs passed, and node scripts/phase46-user-cabinet-ux-smoke.mjs passed for password guidance and compact MTProto link/status UX. 2026-06-03: frontend npm run build and node scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs passed; production-preview auth screenshots confirmed readable Matrix mobile surfaces while protected route coverage is static due local auth redirect. 2026-06-04: Phase-68 frontend build and smokes passed for MTProto-first dashboard, shared SubscriptionPanel, compact tariff/calendar view, and removed visible config raw/diagnostics panels. 2026-06-04: Phase-69 frontend build and smoke passed for masked referral rows and access_label-aware pending bonus copy. 2026-06-04: Phase-70 frontend build and Phase-70/57/62 smokes passed for lighter QR and compact config workflow preservation.</evidence>
  <hotspot>H-023: Mobile user cabinet must keep config download, QR, subscription and device actions reachable without clutter</hotspot>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Frontend build and Phase-71 smoke passed for mobile-safe master-detail device UX, sticky export actions, no raw diagnostics return, and compact user-cabinet copy/i18n cleanup.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Keep Главная, Конфигурация, Подписка, Рефералы, and Настройки reachable in a compact bottom dock with safe-area padding and no content overlap while desktop logout remains directly under Settings.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>Phase-72 and Phase-61 smokes passed for bottom navigation markers, safe-area padding, touch target policy, and protected-surface guard.</acceptance>
  </phase-72-executed-scope>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Frontend build, frontend-admin build prerequisite, Phase-72 smoke, and Phase-61 responsive smoke passed for mobile dock reachability and desktop logout ordering.</phase-72-evidence>
  <phase-73-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/i18n/index.ts scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Mobile config route now shows KPN copy, keeps AmneziaWG QR/.conf/Copy reachable, removes unsupported AmneziaVPN QR advertising, and shows tariff-aware device-limit copy without changing API shapes.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>Phone/tablet config workflows preserve selected-device actions and bottom-dock safety while AmneziaVPN users are directed to .conf import.</acceptance>
  </phase-73-executed-scope>
  <phase-73-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-73 smoke, Phase-71 regression smoke, and Phase-70 QR parity smoke passed locally for mobile config correctness and protected backend/deploy/runtime isolation.</phase-73-evidence>
</M-036>
