<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-045 NAME="mtproto-user-cabinet" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="verification-designed-phase41">
  <path>frontend backend/app/mtproto backend/app/main.py scripts docs/plans/Phase-31.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>User-facing API and compact dashboard UI for personal free Telegram MTProto proxy access.</owns>
  <purpose>Show every verified user their free indefinite MTProto proxy alongside KrotPN trial and VPN actions in the mobile cabinet.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <api-get-my-mtproto-proxy>Authenticated endpoint returning server, port, secret, tg link, status, and reissue guidance.</api-get-my-mtproto-proxy>
    <view-mtproto-card>Dashboard card with primary https://t.me/proxy open action, full-link copy, copy server, copy port, and copy secret actions.</view-mtproto-card>
    <view-mtproto-empty-state>Compact unavailable, pending, degraded, and reissue-required states.</view-mtproto-empty-state>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-002,M-009,M-036,M-042,M-043</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-045</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/schemas.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/main.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_api.py</file>
    <file>scripts/phase31-mtproto-cabinet-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase34-mtproto-stabilization-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="41-designed">scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <ui-contract>
    <primary>MTProto proxy status and copy/open actions fit the first mobile dashboard screen without hiding VPN trial state.</primary>
    <secondary>Manual Telegram fields remain available for desktop and mobile copy workflows.</secondary>
  </ui-contract>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>The MTProto card must not create horizontal scroll at 360x740, 390x844, or 430x932.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Full proxy links are shown only to the authenticated owner and never in admin summary lists.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Phase-41 owner dashboard must show only the current KPprotoN ee fake-TLS link as active and must not present stale official dd links as usable production credentials.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <phase-41-verification-design>
    <check-1>Owner API and dashboard payload use server=u-*.krotpn.xyz, port=443, and secret=ee... after reissue.</check-1>
    <check-2>Official credential-mode assignments render reissue-required or unavailable state until Phase-41 reissue completes.</check-2>
    <check-3>Dashboard copy/open actions remain full-link owner-only behavior, with no secret-bearing console or smoke output.</check-3>
    <check-4>Mobile dashboard remains compact after adding Phase-41 reissue messaging.</check-4>
  </phase-41-verification-design>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-31 local backend tests, frontend build, static mobile/API smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-14: Phase-34 local integration confirms post-verify owner dashboard/API reuses exactly one canonical MTProto assignment and keeps pending/unverified users secret-free.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Phase-39 keeps manual fields but makes the primary Telegram action a https://t.me/proxy link and copy action a full-link copy to reduce manual secret-entry mistakes.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design adds owner-cabinet gates for ee fake-TLS payloads, official-dd reissue-required state, redaction, and mobile compactness.</evidence-4>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-031: User dashboard must show MTProto access compactly without hiding VPN trial status or config actions</hotspot>
</M-045>
