<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-041 NAME="verified-email-registration" TYPE="CORE_LOGIC" STATUS="pass-local-phase45">
  <path>backend/app/users backend/app/email backend/tests/test_trial_activation.py scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-27.xml docs/plans/Phase-28.xml docs/plans/Phase-36.xml docs/plans/Phase-45.xml</path>
  <owns>Pending email registration, email ownership verification, disposable-domain guard, Phase-28 post-verification onboarding orchestration, and Phase-45 pending trial handoff.</owns>
  <purpose>Build the verified-registration foundation so KrotPN can create user access, pending trial access, VPN config, referral effects, and MTProto proxy only after email ownership is proven.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-request-registration>Validate email/password/referral input and send a one-time verification email without creating active access.</fn-request-registration>
    <fn-verify-registration>Consume verification token once for low-level token lifecycle checks.</fn-verify-registration>
    <fn-activate-registration>Consume verification token once, create verified user, and hand off onboarding side effects after ownership proof, including pending VPN trial access.</fn-activate-registration>
    <fn-email-risk-check>Evaluate syntax, domain, MX/DNS, disposable-domain, and configured deny/allow policies.</fn-email-risk-check>
    <fn-registration-status>Return safe pending, verified, expired, or rejected registration state for the frontend.</fn-registration-status>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-002,M-004,M-005,M-022,M-027,M-040</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-041</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/users/models.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/users/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/users/schemas.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/email/verification.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_email_verification_guard.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_verified_registration.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_phase34_mtproto_integration.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_trial_activation.py</file>
  </files>
  <registration-policy>
    <policy-1>Phase-27 kept active /register behavior unchanged while pending-registration primitives were verified.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Phase-28 changes plain /register so active user access is not created before email verification.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Trial access is a four-day pending trial after verified activation; the countdown starts only after the first successful VPN handshake.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Telegram auth remains a separate verified identity path unless explicitly merged later.</policy-4>
  </registration-policy>
  <implementation-state>
    <state-1>Phase-27 implemented PendingEmailRegistration, HMAC token hashing, TTL/replay-safe token consumption, email normalization, allow/deny/disposable-domain policy, and optional DNS guard.</state-1>
    <state-2>Phase-28 implements /register pending response, /verify-email activation, post-verification trial/VPN/referral orchestration, replay-safe activation, and frontend onboarding states.</state-2>
    <state-3>MTProto assignment remains deferred to Phase-29+ and is not issued in Phase-28.</state-3>
    <state-4>Phase-34 local integration verifies verified activation can expose one owner MTProto assignment while pending/unverified registration creates none.</state-4>
    <state-5>Phase-36 wires production Resend deploy settings so pending registration sends verification emails on clean VPS deployments after operator Resend domain verification.</state-5>
    <state-6>Phase-45 changes verified activation to create pending trial access only; countdown activation is owned by M-063/M-004 after first VPN handshake.</state-6>
  </implementation-state>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not issue trial, VPN device, referral bonus, or MTProto proxy for unverified email.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Verification token consumption must be one-time, TTL-bound, and replay-safe.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Temp-mail blocking is defense-in-depth; email ownership proof remains the decisive gate.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Production /register must fail with an operator-actionable provider configuration error only when Resend env values are missing or rejected, not because the provider is left disabled by deploy defaults.</constraint-4>
  </constraints>
  <phase-36-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Verify /register calls M-040 with EMAIL_PROVIDER=resend and does not produce provider_disabled after deploy wiring is present.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Keep all pre-verification side-effect guards unchanged while enabling live email delivery.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-live">Add live handoff notes for controlled-mailbox registration smoke after Resend domain verification completes.</step-3>
  </phase-36-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: Phase-36 local verification keeps registration tests on fake providers and leaves controlled-mailbox Resend smoke operator-only.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy registration via email succeeded with Resend configured while preserving pending-before-verification behavior.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-06-01: Phase-45 backend suite passed and proves verified-email activation creates pending four-day trial access without starting the countdown before first VPN handshake.</evidence-3>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-027: Trial, VPN provisioning, referral effects, and MTProto issuance must not happen before email ownership is verified</hotspot>
</M-041>
