<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-044 NAME="kpproton-runtime-bridge" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="verification-designed-phase41">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto backend/app/tasks/scheduler.py backend/app/core/config.py mtproto-runtime docs/plans/Phase-30.xml docs/plans/Phase-37.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml</path>
  <owns>Runtime bridge from KrotPN assignments to the KPprotoN/mtproto_proxy policy layer, startup policy replay, and explicit policy revoke.</owns>
  <purpose>Keep Telegram MTProto access aligned with issued assignment state by loading or removing SNI assignments at the runtime edge without blocking normal KrotPN auth.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-apply-domain-policy>Apply one issued SNI to the MTProto policy runtime.</fn-apply-domain-policy>
    <fn-revoke-domain-policy>Remove one issued SNI from the MTProto policy runtime after an explicit admin revoke.</fn-revoke-domain-policy>
    <fn-replay-active-assignments>Load active assignments after process or container restart.</fn-replay-active-assignments>
    <fn-runtime-health>Expose bridge health for user-safe and admin-safe status checks.</fn-runtime-health>
    <fn-http-policy-adapter>Apply, revoke, and health-check issued SNI policies through the token-protected MTProto edge policy API, including the planned private DE runtime target.</fn-http-policy-adapter>
    <task-mtproto-policy-sync>Scheduled reconciliation between Postgres assignments and edge policy state.</task-mtproto-policy-sync>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-008,M-012,M-042,M-043,M-049,M-050</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-044</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/health.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/tasks/scheduler.py</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_policy_handler.erl</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_scheduler.py</file>
  </files>
  <runtime-policy>
    <policy-1>Bridge failures mark MTProto provisioning degraded but do not prevent normal KrotPN login.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Verified registration may complete with a pending proxy status only if user messaging is explicit.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Startup replay must be idempotent and safe after backup restore.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Runtime revoke must be idempotent by SNI and must remove an already-applied policy without requiring the assignment to remain active.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>Provisioning must apply the issued SNI to the live edge before returning an active user payload; failed apply returns an explicit degraded/incomplete state instead of a dead active proxy link.</policy-5>
    <policy-6>Phase-38 policy apply may target the DE runtime only over a private, token-protected policy API and must remain degraded-safe when unreachable.</policy-6>
  </runtime-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not rely on KPprotoN DETS registry as the source of truth.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Do not expose raw tg://proxy links or secrets in runtime logs.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Do not rotate MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX or MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT when enabling the live runtime for existing assignments.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <phase-41-reactivation>
    <item-1>Phase-41 supersedes the Phase-40 official MTProxy production path and reactivates M-044 as the production SNI policy bridge.</item-1>
    <item-2>Policy apply/revoke/replay must target the DE KPprotoN runtime and must not depend on official MTProxy secret manifests.</item-2>
    <item-3>Adding a new SNI policy must not restart the MTProto data-plane when the runtime supports in-memory policy updates.</item-3>
  </phase-41-reactivation>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-30 target pytest passed for fake/local adapter policy apply, replay idempotency, degraded mode, runtime health redaction, and scheduler registration.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-14: Phase-33 fix added runtime policy revoke regression coverage for admin assignment disable.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Phase-37 added HTTPMTProtoPolicyAdapter, provisioning-time live policy apply, token-protected Erlang policy handler, and local regression coverage for live edge policy calls.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Phase-38 plan keeps the same bridge contract but moves the production policy target from RU-local runtime to the private DE runtime.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution permits private DE policy URLs, rejects public/wildcard policy API targets, and adds HTTP adapter trace markers for apply/health operations.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: DE live smoke found mtproto_proxy bootstrap still hardcoded to 127.0.0.1 while policy API was privately bound to 172.29.255.1; runtime now builds bootstrap URLs from POLICY_LISTEN_IP.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-18: DE live rebuild passed with mtproto_proxy listening on 0.0.0.0:443 and private policy health OK on 172.29.255.1:18080.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Phase-40 planning marks KPprotoN/Erlang data-plane as insufficient after req_pq timeout against issued user links.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design reopens the KPprotoN runtime bridge as the intended production policy plane after official MTProxy proved operationally mismatched for per-user issuance.</evidence-9>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-030: MTProto runtime bridge must degrade safely when policy loading fails and must not block normal KrotPN login</hotspot>
</M-044>
