<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-047 NAME="mtproto-admin-ops" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="done-local">
  <path>backend/app/admin frontend-admin scripts/phase33-mtproto-admin-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-33.xml</path>
  <owns>Admin inspection and controlled operations for MTProto assignments, runtime bridge health, reissue, revoke, and audit-safe diagnostics.</owns>
  <purpose>Give the operator visibility and controlled recovery actions for user MTProto proxy assignments without exposing secrets broadly.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <api-admin-list-mtproto>List assignments by user, SNI, status, and timestamps with redacted sensitive fields.</api-admin-list-mtproto>
    <api-admin-reissue-mtproto>Force explicit reissue after secret rotation or runtime repair.</api-admin-reissue-mtproto>
    <api-admin-revoke-mtproto>Disable one user's MTProto assignment without disabling VPN account access.</api-admin-revoke-mtproto>
    <view-admin-mtproto>Admin UI surface for health, assignment search, reissue, revoke, and recent failures.</view-admin-mtproto>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-006,M-010,M-024,M-042,M-043,M-044</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-047</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/admin/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/admin/audit.py</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/main.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase33-mtproto-admin-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_ops.py</file>
  </files>
  <admin-policy>
    <policy-1>Admin list views show redacted or derived-safe assignment fields by default.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Reissue and revoke are explicit audited actions with confirmation in the frontend.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>MTProto revoke does not implicitly cancel KrotPN subscription or VPN device access.</policy-3>
  </admin-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Audit events must not store full tg://proxy links, verification tokens, or raw secrets.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Admin mobile UX must preserve confirmation-safe destructive actions.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <completion>
    <item-1>Backend admin endpoints expose redacted list/detail/runtime health and explicit reissue/revoke operations under /api/v1/admin/mtproto.</item-1>
    <item-2>Reissue and revoke require confirmation, write safe audit events, and do not return owner-only proxy links or derived secrets.</item-2>
    <item-3>Frontend-admin includes a compact /mtproto page with search, status filter, runtime health, and confirmation-safe actions.</item-3>
    <item-4>Local Phase-33 backend tests, frontend-admin build, static smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed on 2026-05-14.</item-4>
  </completion>
  <hotspot>H-033: Admin MTProto operations must never expose full secrets or proxy links in logs, tables, or audit payloads</hotspot>
</M-047>
