<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-044 NAME="kpproton-runtime-bridge" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="done-local">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto backend/app/tasks</path>
  <owns>Runtime bridge from KrotPN assignments to the KPprotoN/mtproto_proxy policy layer and startup policy replay.</owns>
  <purpose>Keep Telegram MTProto access active by loading issued SNI assignments into the runtime edge without blocking normal KrotPN auth.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-apply-domain-policy>Apply one issued SNI to the MTProto policy runtime.</fn-apply-domain-policy>
    <fn-replay-active-assignments>Load active assignments after process or container restart.</fn-replay-active-assignments>
    <fn-runtime-health>Expose bridge health for user-safe and admin-safe status checks.</fn-runtime-health>
    <task-mtproto-policy-sync>Scheduled reconciliation between Postgres assignments and edge policy state.</task-mtproto-policy-sync>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-008,M-012,M-042,M-043</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-044</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/health.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/tasks/scheduler.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_kpproton_runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_scheduler.py</file>
  </files>
  <runtime-policy>
    <policy-1>Bridge failures mark MTProto provisioning degraded but do not prevent normal KrotPN login.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Verified registration may complete with a pending proxy status only if user messaging is explicit.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Startup replay must be idempotent and safe after backup restore.</policy-3>
  </runtime-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not rely on KPprotoN DETS registry as the source of truth.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Do not expose raw tg://proxy links or secrets in runtime logs.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-30 target pytest passed for fake/local adapter policy apply, replay idempotency, degraded mode, runtime health redaction, and scheduler registration.</evidence-1>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-030: MTProto runtime bridge must degrade safely when policy loading fails and must not block normal KrotPN login</hotspot>
</M-044>
