<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-048 NAME="installer-wildcard-tls" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="partial-live">
  <path>install.sh deploy/deploy-on-server.sh nginx docker-compose.yml .env.example scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-35.xml docs/plans/Phase-36.xml docs/plans/Phase-37.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml</path>
  <owns>installer prompts, remote wildcard certificate validation, deploy-time certificate installation, production edge env wiring, Phase-36 Resend email env prompts, Phase-37 MTProto runtime token/env wiring, planned Phase-38 DE-backed edge wiring, and operator-safe TLS reuse.</owns>
  <purpose>Make fresh deploys accept an operator-provided wildcard certificate instead of reissuing or silently generating production self-signed TLS material.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <installer-domain-prompt>Prompt for the public domain with krotpn.xyz as the default.</installer-domain-prompt>
    <installer-fullchain-prompt>Prompt for the absolute RU-server fullchain path with /root/krotpn-ssl/fullchain1.pem as the default.</installer-fullchain-prompt>
    <installer-privkey-prompt>Prompt for the absolute RU-server private key path with /root/krotpn-ssl/privkey1.pem as the default.</installer-privkey-prompt>
    <installer-resend-prompt>Prompt for the Resend API key and sender address for production verification emails.</installer-resend-prompt>
    <remote-cert-validator>Bootstrap openssl when needed, then verify existence, readability, expiry, cert/key match, and SAN coverage before deploy mutates the runtime TLS directory.</remote-cert-validator>
    <edge-env-wiring>Generate DOMAIN, FRONTEND_URL, MTPROTO_BASE_DOMAIN, MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX, MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT, EMAIL_PROVIDER, RESEND_API_KEY, EMAIL_FROM, and EDGE_TLS_* values for the deployed .env.</edge-env-wiring>
    <mtproto-runtime-env-wiring>Generate MTPROTO_RUNTIME_POLICY_URL, MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN, MTPROTO_POLICY_PORT, EDGE_SHARED_443_ENABLED, and EDGE_HTTPS_FALLBACK_PORT for the live edge runtime.</mtproto-runtime-env-wiring>
    <phase38-de-edge-env-wiring>Plan DE runtime policy URL, RU SNI router targets, and cert reuse without printing token, private key, or proxy secrets.</phase38-de-edge-env-wiring>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-044,M-046,M-049,M-050</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-048</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>install.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>.env.example</file>
    <file>scripts/phase35-installer-wildcard-tls-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-35.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-36.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-37.xml</file>
  </files>
  <operator-inputs>
    <input-1>PUBLIC_DOMAIN defaults to krotpn.xyz.</input-1>
    <input-2>TLS_FULLCHAIN_PATH defaults to /root/krotpn-ssl/fullchain1.pem on the RU server.</input-2>
    <input-3>TLS_PRIVKEY_PATH defaults to /root/krotpn-ssl/privkey1.pem on the RU server.</input-3>
    <input-4>RESEND_API_KEY is entered by the operator and must never be echoed.</input-4>
    <input-5>EMAIL_FROM defaults to noreply@krotpn.xyz.</input-5>
  </operator-inputs>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Production installs must not fall back to self-signed TLS unless the operator explicitly selects a dev/self-signed mode.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>The private key must never be printed, copied into logs, embedded in XML evidence, or sent through unsafe command output.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Certificate validation must fail before docker compose changes when paths are missing, key mismatch occurs, SAN coverage is wrong, or the cert is expired.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Shared 443 MTProto routing remains a live-gated M-046/M-044 concern; this module only makes trusted wildcard TLS material deployable and reusable.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Operator certificate source paths must not be under /opt/KrotPN because installer refreshes that repository directory during clone.</constraint-5>
    <constraint-6>Fresh deploys must generate non-empty 32-hex MTProto base secret and salt values without printing them.</constraint-6>
    <constraint-7>Fresh production deploys must configure Resend email delivery or fail with an explicit operator message before registration can later hit provider_disabled.</constraint-7>
    <constraint-8>Fresh deploys must generate an MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN and must not print it or reuse it outside the localhost policy bridge.</constraint-8>
    <constraint-9>Hotfix deploys must preserve existing MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX and MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT so already-issued Telegram proxy links remain valid.</constraint-9>
    <constraint-10>Phase-38 must not expose the DE policy API publicly and must not print wildcard private key material while preparing DE runtime TLS.</constraint-10>
  </constraints>
  <planned-execution>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Extend install.sh prompt allowlist and interactive flow for domain, fullchain path, and privkey path after RU SSH credentials are known.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Pass sanitized TLS inputs to the remote deploy configuration without exposing private key contents.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Teach deploy/deploy-on-server.sh to validate and install operator-provided certs into /opt/KrotPN/ssl/server.crt and /opt/KrotPN/ssl/server.key.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="pass-local">Generate production domain and edge TLS env values for backend, frontend, admin, nginx, and MTProto base-domain expectations.</step-4>
    <step-5 STATUS="pass-local">Preserve existing certs across redeploys unless a validated replacement is provided.</step-5>
    <step-6 STATUS="pass-local">Collect and pass Resend API key and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender for production email verification delivery.</step-6>
    <step-7 STATUS="pass-local">Generate and wire the live MTProto runtime policy token and shared-443 fallback env values.</step-7>
    <step-8 STATUS="pending">Plan DE runtime TLS reuse, private policy URL, and RU SNI router env wiring for Phase-38.</step-8>
  </planned-execution>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: Local Phase-35 implementation added installer prompts, RU cert preflight, deploy-time certificate validation/install, production env wiring, runtime nginx rendering, and static smoke coverage.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: Live clean VPS deploy with prepared wildcard certificate files remains operator-required before STATUS can move beyond partial-local.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-17: Reviewer follow-up fixed clean VPS openssl bootstrap risk, rejected /opt/KrotPN cert source paths, and added dynamic installer validator smoke checks.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-17: Live clean VPS backend unhealthy failure was fixed by generating deploy-time MTProto secrets and adding smoke coverage against blank deploy values.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-17: Phase-36 local execution added Resend secret prompt, sender validation, deploy env wiring, static smoke coverage, and redaction checks.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: Phase-37 added deploy-time MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN generation, localhost policy URL wiring, shared-443 enablement, and static smoke guards for the mtproto-edge service.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-18: Phase-38 plan requires DE runtime TLS/key handling and private policy URL wiring to stay redaction-safe before execution.</evidence-7>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-034: Installer-provided wildcard TLS must validate cert/key/domain before deploy and must never log private key material.</hotspot>
</M-048>
