<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-040 NAME="email-delivery" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="pass-live-phase36">
  <path>backend/app/email backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py scripts/phase36-resend-deploy-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-27.xml docs/plans/Phase-36.xml</path>
  <owns>Email provider adapter, verification email templates, provider error mapping, and safe operator evidence for email delivery.</owns>
  <purpose>Provide a KrotPN-native email delivery surface for verified registration without exposing tokens or provider secrets.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-send-verification-email>Send a one-time registration verification link or code to a normalized email address.</fn-send-verification-email>
    <fn-build-verification-template>Render Russian and English subject, HTML, and text fallback content.</fn-build-verification-template>
    <fn-map-email-provider-error>Map provider HTTP or transport failures to typed application errors.</fn-map-email-provider-error>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-040</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/email/service.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/email/templates.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/email/provider.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/email/__init__.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py</file>
  </files>
  <implementation-state>
    <state-1>Phase-27 implemented provider-neutral requests, Resend and SMTP adapters, disabled-provider guard, templates, safe log markers, and fake-provider test coverage.</state-1>
    <state-2>Live provider smoke is operator-run only after EMAIL_PROVIDER and provider secrets are configured outside tests; clean VPS registration email is now operator-confirmed.</state-2>
    <state-3>Phase-36 local execution adds production deploy wiring and request-shape tests so Resend is enabled during clean VPS installs and registration no longer fails with provider_disabled when an API key is supplied.</state-3>
  </implementation-state>
  <source-transfer>
    <from-project>KPprotoN</from-project>
    <reuse>Resend request payload shape, readable UTF-8 templates, provider error normalization.</reuse>
    <do-not-reuse>Standalone KPprotoN portal registration endpoint or DETS token storage.</do-not-reuse>
  </source-transfer>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Verification tokens must never appear in logs, traces, or provider error payloads.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Email sending failures block registration activation but do not create user, trial, VPN, or MTProto records.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Provider configuration remains env-backed through M-001 settings.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Production Resend configuration must use https://api.resend.com/emails, Authorization Bearer API key, and noreply@krotpn.xyz sender after domain verification.</constraint-4>
  </constraints>
  <phase-36-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Strengthen Resend request-shape tests for URL, Bearer header, sender, recipient, subject, HTML, and text payload.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Add deploy smoke coverage that EMAIL_PROVIDER is not left disabled when Resend API key is provided.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-live">Keep live Resend smoke operator-only and redact message IDs, API keys, tokens, and full verification links.</step-3>
  </phase-36-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-17: backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py passed locally with Phase-36 Resend URL, Bearer header, sender, payload, timeout, and safe receipt assertions.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy registration via email succeeded with Resend configured, closing the provider_disabled production blocker.</evidence-2>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-026: Email delivery must not leak verification tokens, API keys, or raw provider responses</hotspot>
</M-040>
