<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-043 NAME="mtproto-provisioning" TYPE="CORE_LOGIC" STATUS="pass-local-phase47">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto docs/plans/Phase-29.xml docs/plans/Phase-40.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml docs/plans/Phase-47.xml</path>
  <owns>Deterministic assignment identity, CTA MTProto hostname generation, legacy u-* preservation, KPprotoN fake-TLS link generation, superseded official MTProxy per-user secret generation, tg://proxy assembly, and idempotent reissue policy.</owns>
  <purpose>Port the useful KPprotoN provisioning logic into KrotPN as Python/FastAPI domain code backed by Postgres assignments.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-generate-sni>Generate a stable user-bound wildcard-safe SNI under krotpn.xyz.</fn-generate-sni>
    <fn-generate-cta-sni>Generate a Phase-47 CTA-prefixed wildcard-safe SNI for newly issued assignments.</fn-generate-cta-sni>
    <fn-shorten-public-user-id>Derive a 7-hex public suffix without exposing raw numeric user IDs.</fn-shorten-public-user-id>
    <fn-select-cta-prefix>Validate explicit CTA prefixes or choose a stable pseudo-random allowed prefix.</fn-select-cta-prefix>
    <fn-derive-fake-tls-secret>Build a per-SNI Telegram fake-TLS secret from configured base secret and private salt.</fn-derive-fake-tls-secret>
    <fn-derive-official-mtproxy-secret superseded="phase41-pass-local">Build a 16-byte official MTProxy secret for one canonical user assignment.</fn-derive-official-mtproxy-secret>
    <fn-issue-user-proxy>Create or reuse a user's canonical MTProto assignment and return a safe response payload.</fn-issue-user-proxy>
    <fn-build-tg-link>Assemble tg://proxy from server, port, and derived secret for the authenticated user.</fn-build-tg-link>
    <fn-build-secure-official-tg-link superseded="phase41-pass-local">Assemble tg://proxy with secret=dd&lt;32-hex-secret&gt; for the authenticated owner after Phase-40 execution.</fn-build-secure-official-tg-link>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-002,M-040,M-042</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-043</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/schemas.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/service.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_provisioning.py</file>
  </files>
  <source-transfer>
    <from-project>KPprotoN</from-project>
    <reuse>Stable SNI derivation, per-SNI derived credentials, supersession warning semantics.</reuse>
    <rewrite>Implement in Python with deterministic test vectors and KrotPN settings.</rewrite>
  </source-transfer>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Knowing base domain, port, and base secret must not be enough to authenticate without issued derived credential.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Base secret or salt rotation invalidates old links and must require explicit reissue messaging.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Provisioning must be idempotent for repeated verified-registration retries.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Missing or blank MTProto secret configuration must fail proxy issuance safely without crashing unrelated backend startup.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Phase-40 official MTProxy links must treat fake-TLS SNI-derived links as legacy and must reissue explicitly rather than silently claiming compatibility.</constraint-5>
    <constraint-6>Phase-41 fake-TLS links must treat official dd-secret assignments as superseded and must reissue users explicitly rather than silently claiming compatibility.</constraint-6>
    <constraint-7>Phase-47 new assignments use CTA-prefixed one-label hostnames, but existing active u-* assignments must be preserved without silent mass reissue.</constraint-7>
  </constraints>
  <phase-41-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Restore owner payloads to server=u-*.krotpn.xyz and secret=ee... fake-TLS format.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Detect official credential-mode assignments and return reissue-required state before showing a stale dd link as active.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Keep SNI, base secret, salt, and derived secret redacted in logs and admin surfaces.</step-3>
  </phase-41-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-29 target pytest passed for deterministic SNI, KPprotoN fake-TLS vector, verified-user guard, idempotency, reissue, and config failure paths.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-17: Clean VPS hotfix added regression coverage for blank MTProto env values being normalized to missing config and rejected at issuance time.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-19: Phase-40 plan adds official MTProxy per-user secret issuance because the fake-TLS data-plane did not pass real req_pq availability.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design supersedes official dd-secret issuance for production and returns owner payloads to the KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI model.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local tests passed for derived_per_sni defaults, ee fake-TLS owner payloads, explicit official-mode reissue, owner API behavior, and Phase-34 verified-registration integration.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-06-01: Phase-47 local tests passed 14/14 for CTA allow-list, public short IDs, explicit prefix validation, one-label SNI, final-SNI fake-TLS binding, and legacy u-* assignment preservation.</evidence-6>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-029: Changing MTProto base secret or salt invalidates issued Telegram proxy links unless reissue is explicit</hotspot>
</M-043>
