<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-042 NAME="mtproto-assignment-registry" TYPE="DATA_LAYER" STATUS="done-local">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto backend/alembic</path>
  <owns>PostgreSQL-backed MTProto proxy assignment records, uniqueness constraints, lifecycle status, and restore-safe metadata.</owns>
  <purpose>Store each user's personal Telegram MTProto proxy assignment inside KrotPN's primary database instead of KPprotoN DETS.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <model-MTProtoAssignment>User-linked assignment table with SNI, credential mode, status, timestamps, and rotation metadata.</model-MTProtoAssignment>
    <fn-get-user-assignment>Return the current active or latest assignment for one user.</fn-get-user-assignment>
    <fn-save-assignment>Create or update an idempotent user assignment.</fn-save-assignment>
    <fn-list-assignments>Admin-safe paginated lookup without exposing raw secrets by default.</fn-list-assignments>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-002,M-028</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-042</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/models.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/repository.py</file>
    <file>backend/alembic/versions/b3f1e0d2c9a4_add_mtproto_assignments.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_assignment_registry.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
  </files>
  <data-contract>
    <field-1>user_id has a uniqueness guard for one canonical active personal proxy per user.</field-1>
    <field-2>sni is unique and remains stable across idempotent reissue unless rotation is explicit.</field-2>
    <field-3>secret material is derived on demand or encrypted if persisted; raw proxy links are not logged.</field-3>
  </data-contract>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Backup/restore must preserve assignment linkage with users and migration state.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Schema changes require Alembic coverage and SQLModel compatibility.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-29 target pytest passed for assignment registry, SNI uniqueness, redacted listing, and migration metadata.</evidence-1>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-028: MTProto assignment backup/restore must preserve SNI, credential mode, and user linkage without storing unnecessary raw secrets</hotspot>
</M-042>
