<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-047 NAME="mtproto-admin-ops" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="pass-local-phase43-phase54-pass-local-phase80">
  <path>backend/app/admin frontend-admin scripts/phase33-mtproto-admin-smoke.mjs scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-33.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml docs/plans/Phase-43.xml docs/plans/Phase-54.xml</path>
  <owns>Admin inspection and controlled operations for MTProto assignments, runtime bridge health, reissue, revoke, and audit-safe diagnostics.</owns>
  <purpose>Give the operator visibility and controlled recovery actions for user MTProto proxy assignments without exposing secrets broadly.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <api-admin-list-mtproto>List assignments by user, SNI, status, and timestamps with redacted sensitive fields.</api-admin-list-mtproto>
    <api-admin-reissue-mtproto>Force explicit reissue after secret rotation or runtime repair.</api-admin-reissue-mtproto>
    <api-admin-revoke-mtproto>Disable one user's MTProto assignment and remove its runtime SNI policy without disabling VPN account access.</api-admin-revoke-mtproto>
    <api-admin-alert-actions>Phase-43 acknowledge, resolve, disable-proxy, and TTL IP block actions from MTProto abuse alerts.</api-admin-alert-actions>
    <view-admin-mtproto>Admin UI surface for health, assignment search, reissue, revoke, and recent failures.</view-admin-mtproto>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-006,M-010,M-024,M-026,M-042,M-043,M-044,M-060,M-061,M-071</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-047</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/admin/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/admin/audit.py</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/main.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase33-mtproto-admin-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase34-mtproto-stabilization-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="41-pass-local">scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="43-pass-local">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file phase="54-pass-local">scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_admin_ops.py</file>
  </files>
  <admin-policy>
    <policy-1>Admin list views show redacted or derived-safe assignment fields by default.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Reissue and revoke are explicit audited actions with confirmation in the frontend.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>MTProto revoke does not implicitly cancel KrotPN subscription or VPN device access.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Phase-43 alert actions require explicit confirmation, audit, and safe evidence from M-060/M-061 before enforcement.</policy-4>
  </admin-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Audit events must not store full tg://proxy links, verification tokens, or raw secrets.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Admin mobile UX must preserve confirmation-safe destructive actions.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Phase-41 admin operations must treat official dd credential-mode assignments as superseded/reissue-required and must not expose owner-only KPprotoN ee links or derived secrets.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Phase-43 IP block actions are TTL-bound and must never store decrypted raw IP strings in audit details.</constraint-4>
  </constraints>
  <phase-41-verification-design>
    <check-1>Admin list/detail show credential mode and superseded official state with safe identifiers only.</check-1>
    <check-2>Admin reissue changes exactly one assignment back to KPprotoN fake-TLS SNI policy without returning owner credentials.</check-2>
    <check-3>Admin revoke removes one KPprotoN SNI policy through M-044 and does not call official manifest sync as the production path.</check-3>
    <check-4>Admin UI/smoke output contains no tg links, ee secrets, dd secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, or private key material.</check-4>
  </phase-41-verification-design>
  <completion>
    <item-1>Backend admin endpoints expose redacted list/detail/runtime health and explicit reissue/revoke operations under /api/v1/admin/mtproto.</item-1>
    <item-2>Reissue and revoke require confirmation, write safe audit events, remove runtime policy state on revoke, and do not return owner-only proxy links or derived secrets.</item-2>
    <item-3>Frontend-admin includes a compact /mtproto page with search, status filter, runtime health, and confirmation-safe actions.</item-3>
    <item-4>Local Phase-33 backend tests, frontend-admin build, static smoke, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint passed on 2026-05-14.</item-4>
    <item-5>Phase-34 static smoke keeps admin MTProto pages free of owner-only tg links, derived secrets, and console secret traces.</item-5>
    <item-6>Phase-41 local execution restores admin reissue/revoke to KPprotoN runtime policy behavior and keeps superseded official state redacted.</item-6>
    <item-7>Phase-41 backend admin tests passed for KPprotoN bridge health, single-assignment reissue/revoke, audit-safe payloads, and no official manifest sync calls in the production path.</item-7>
    <item-8>Phase-43 local execution adds alert acknowledge/resolve, confirmation-safe proxy disable, and TTL IP-block record actions with audit-safe details and no decrypted raw IP strings in audit payloads.</item-8>
  </completion>
  <phase-54-verification-design>
    <surface-1>Matrix admin redesign must keep /mtproto assignment inventory, runtime health, search/filter, paging, reissue, revoke, and confirmation surfaces visible and compact.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Admin DOM/smoke output must remain free of owner proxy links, ee/dd secrets, base secret, salt, runtime tokens, and private key material.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>No backend MTProto admin endpoint, audit schema, runtime policy, or provisioning behavior changes are included in Phase-54.</surface-3>
  </phase-54-verification-design>
  <phase-54-execution>
    <surface-1>/mtproto now carries compact Matrix assignment inventory, runtime bridge surface, bounded list, and explicit Phase-54 redaction/confirmation markers.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Reissue/revoke code paths, admin API endpoints, audit schemas, and runtime policy behavior were not changed.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>2026-06-03: Phase-54 smoke passed [M-047][phase54_mtproto_admin][OPS_CONTROLS_READABLE], [CONFIRMATIONS_SAFE], and [REDACTION_PRESERVED].</surface-3>
  </phase-54-execution>
  <hotspot>H-033: Admin MTProto operations must never expose full secrets or proxy links in logs, tables, or audit payloads</hotspot>
</M-047>
