<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-049 NAME="mtproto-live-edge-runtime" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="pass-local-phase41">
  <path>mtproto-runtime backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py nginx/nginx.conf docker-compose.yml deploy/deploy-on-server.sh deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-37.xml docs/plans/Phase-38.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml</path>
  <owns>Live KPprotoN/mtproto_proxy runtime, token-protected policy API, DE MTProto data-plane ownership, and HTTPS domain-fronting fallback.</owns>
  <purpose>Make issued KrotPN MTProto assignments reachable by Telegram clients by running a real fake-TLS MTProto edge instead of only generating proxy links.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <runtime-mtproto-edge>Host-network mtproto-edge service owns public TCP 443 and loads KPprotoN-compatible fake-TLS policy.</runtime-mtproto-edge>
    <runtime-policy-api>Local HTTP policy API applies, revokes, and health-checks issued SNI domains using a deploy-generated bearer token.</runtime-policy-api>
    <https-fallback>Normal HTTPS requests are domain-fronted from the MTProto edge to the configured private frontend fallback.</https-fallback>
    <provisioning-live-apply>Backend provisioning applies an issued SNI to the live edge before returning an active proxy payload.</provisioning-live-apply>
    <runtime-smoke>Phase-37 static and local runtime smoke checks protect service wiring, nginx port ownership, and secret redaction.</runtime-smoke>
    <telegram-upstream-routes>Deploy keeps Telegram MTProto upstream ranges routed through the existing RU-to-DE awg-client tunnel so RU edge can reach Telegram DCs without changing the host default route.</telegram-upstream-routes>
    <phase38-supersession>Phase-38 keeps the runtime artifacts but moves production traffic to a DE-hosted runtime behind an RU SNI router.</phase38-supersession>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-043,M-044,M-046,M-048,M-050</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-049</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/Dockerfile</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_core_api.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_web.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_policy_handler.erl</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime/apps/kpproton_proxy/src/mtproto/kpproton_proxy_bridge.erl</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file>.env.example</file>
    <file>scripts/phase37-mtproto-runtime-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <runtime-policy>
    <policy-1>Public TCP 443 has exactly one runtime owner: mtproto-edge. Nginx serves HTTPS fallback on internal 8443.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>The edge must accept issued SNI policies only through the localhost policy API with MTPROTO_RUNTIME_TOKEN.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Existing MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX and MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT values must be preserved across hotfix deploys.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Normal HTTPS, /api, and /admin traffic must continue working through the fallback path after mtproto-edge starts.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>Logs and health payloads may expose status and counts, but never base secret, salt, derived secrets, full tg:// links, private keys, JWTs, or email tokens.</policy-5>
    <policy-6>MTProto bootstrap must use bounded Telegram core fetches with static fallback artifacts so the edge can start when core.telegram.org is slow or blocked.</policy-6>
    <policy-7>RU host routes for Telegram upstream ranges must be scoped to Telegram networks only and use awg-client, not a broad default-route mutation.</policy-7>
  </runtime-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Host-network public 443 changes are production-sensitive and must be paired with rollback-ready nginx fallback validation.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Policy API must bind to localhost only and reject missing or wrong tokens.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Telegram availability cannot be fully proven by local unit tests; final proof requires a real Telegram client or protocol-compatible live smoke.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Phase-38 must preserve Phase-37 local runtime work while avoiding RU-only live handshakes as the production dependency.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Phase-41 must reconcile runtime behavior against CodexKPprotoN_for_KPN before claiming fake-TLS production readiness.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <phase-41-plan>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Compare mtproto-runtime fake-TLS, per-SNI policy, and bootstrap paths with the reference CodexKPprotoN_for_KPN implementation.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Keep the DE runtime as the production MTProto listener and apply user SNI policy without official secret manifests.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Expose only redacted health, policy counts, and safe failure codes to KrotPN diagnostics.</step-3>
  </phase-41-plan>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-18: Local Erlang compile passed for mtproto-runtime with the token-protected policy handler.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-18: Local Erlang prod release passed from an ASCII temp path; direct release from the Cyrillic checkout path hit a rebar3 path-formatting bug only.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Backend regression tests passed for HTTP policy adapter, provisioning live apply, API payloads, and existing local bridge behavior.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Live RU application exposed Telegram upstream reachability problems; deploy now routes Telegram MTProto ranges through awg-client and runtime includes bounded static bootstrap fallback before final Telegram Desktop proof.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: RU HTTPS was rolled back to nginx public 443 after mtproto_proxy continued failing downstream handshakes; website remains available while MTProto live proof is blocked.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: Phase-38 plan supersedes RU-only runtime ownership with a DE-backed runtime and RU SNI router, while preserving existing assignments and secrets.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution keeps the reusable mtproto-runtime and policy API but moves the local mtproto-edge compose service behind an explicit profile so default public 443 belongs to the RU SNI router.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design selects the KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime as the production data-plane to match the reference project and avoid official MTProxy process restarts on per-user issuance.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local execution passed Erlang compile and static smoke proving the production DE runtime path uses KPprotoN policy apply instead of official secret manifests.</evidence-9>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-036: MTProto live edge must own public TCP 443, forward normal HTTPS to nginx 8443, and load issued SNI policies without rotating existing secrets.</hotspot>
</M-049>
