<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-046 NAME="krotpn-domain-tls-edge" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="partial-local">
  <path>backend/app/core/config.py nginx docker-compose.yml .env.example scripts docs/edge/PHASE-32-CUTOVER.xml docs/plans/Phase-32.xml</path>
  <owns>krotpn.xyz domain edge, HTTP to HTTPS redirect, wildcard TLS expectations, and shared 443 routing contract for HTTPS plus MTProto.</owns>
  <purpose>Define the production edge model needed for https://krotpn.xyz and Telegram fake-TLS MTProto proxy to coexist safely.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <edge-http-redirect>Force http://krotpn.xyz and http://www.krotpn.xyz to https://krotpn.xyz.</edge-http-redirect>
    <edge-wildcard-tls>Use trusted certificates covering krotpn.xyz and *.krotpn.xyz.</edge-wildcard-tls>
    <edge-shared-443>Route MTProto fake-TLS by issued SNI and forward normal HTTPS to KrotPN frontend/backend/admin.</edge-shared-443>
    <edge-static-guard>Static checks proving deploy/install scripts are not redesigned in this phase.</edge-static-guard>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-044</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-046</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>.env.example</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_domain_tls_edge_static.py</file>
    <file>scripts/phase32-edge-contract-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/edge/PHASE-32-CUTOVER.xml</file>
    <file>docs/handoff/PHASE-34-RELEASE-CHECKLIST.xml</file>
  </files>
  <edge-policy>
    <policy-1>Shared 443 design must be verified before replacing direct nginx ownership of 443.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Wildcard certificate issuance may remain operator-driven; this module defines runtime expectations first.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Existing deploy/install scripts are protected unless the operator explicitly approves edge deployment changes.</policy-3>
  </edge-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Misrouting 443 can break both website and Telegram proxy, so rollout requires a rollback plan.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Self-signed certificates are unacceptable for production Telegram fake-TLS links.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-14: Phase-32 local static verification passed for settings, nginx redirect/fallback, compose config, protected deploy/install guard, cutover runbook, XML parse, and MyGRACE lint.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>Production smoke remains blocked-live until operator-provided DNS, trusted wildcard certificate, and rollback window are available.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-14: Phase-34 release handoff records V-M-046 as operator-live and keeps deploy/install/edge surfaces protected during local stabilization.</evidence-3>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-032: Shared 443 edge can break both HTTPS and Telegram proxy if fallback routing or wildcard TLS is misconfigured</hotspot>
</M-046>
