<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-055 NAME="mtproto-runtime-telemetry-bridge" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="planned">
  <path>mtproto-runtime backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py backend/app/tasks/scheduler.py scripts/phase42-mtproto-telemetry-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-42.xml</path>
  <owns>Secret-free telemetry extraction from the KPprotoN runtime, private telemetry API, backend ingestion, and bounded runtime buffers.</owns>
  <purpose>Move runtime connection, traffic, error, unknown-SNI, and req_pq metadata from the DE edge into KrotPN analytics safely.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <runtime-telemetry-event>Handshake, close, bytes, error, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, active_connection, and req_pq proof metadata event.</runtime-telemetry-event>
    <api-runtime-telemetry-snapshot>Token-protected private runtime endpoint returning current counters without draining them.</api-runtime-telemetry-snapshot>
    <api-runtime-telemetry-drain>Token-protected private runtime endpoint returning and acknowledging new events by cursor.</api-runtime-telemetry-drain>
    <task-mtproto-telemetry-ingest>Scheduled backend task that polls the runtime and writes M-054 records.</task-mtproto-telemetry-ingest>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-044,M-049,M-050,M-054</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-055</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file planned="true">mtproto-runtime/apps/kpproton_proxy/src/mtproto/kpproton_usage_telemetry.erl</file>
    <file planned="true">mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_policy_handler.erl</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/app/mtproto/usage_ingestion.py</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/app/tasks/scheduler.py</file>
    <file planned="true">scripts/phase42-mtproto-telemetry-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_runtime_telemetry_bridge.py</file>
  </files>
  <runtime-contract>
    <item-1>Telemetry API is private and protected by the existing runtime token or a dedicated telemetry token.</item-1>
    <item-2>Runtime buffers are bounded and loss-tolerant; overflow increments a dropped_events counter rather than blocking proxy traffic.</item-2>
    <item-3>Events include assignment_id/user_id only when policy metadata is known; unknown SNI stays safe and masked.</item-3>
  </runtime-contract>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No full tg links, derived secrets, base secret, salt, runtime token, or private keys in runtime events.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Telemetry ingestion failure must degrade analytics only, not MTProto availability.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Live release requires no-regression proof for issued-link req_pq and Telegram client behavior.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <hotspot>H-042: Runtime telemetry must be secret-free, bounded, and resilient so analytics cannot break the MTProto data-plane</hotspot>
</M-055>
