<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-059 NAME="mtproto-promotion-tag-control" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="pass-live-phase42-pass-local-phase79">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto/promotion_tag.py backend/app/admin/router.py backend/app/core/config.py mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml .env.example scripts/phase42-mtproto-promotion-tag-smoke.mjs scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs backend/tests/test_mtproto_promotion_tag.py docs/plans/Phase-42.xml docs/plans/Phase-79.xml</path>
  <owns>Operator-managed MTProxyBot promotion tag storage, validation, redaction, audit trail, runtime apply state, and deploy env propagation.</owns>
  <purpose>Allow the KrotPN admin to configure the Telegram MTProxy promotion tag safely from the admin panel.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <api-get-promotion-tag-state>Return masked tag, source, runtime status, and pending_restart flag.</api-get-promotion-tag-state>
    <api-update-promotion-tag>Validate and store a new MTProxyBot tag with explicit admin confirmation.</api-update-promotion-tag>
    <fn-validate-promotion-tag>Accept a 32-hex Telegram proxy tag or a zero 32-hex fallback; reject blanks and malformed values.</fn-validate-promotion-tag>
    <fn-apply-promotion-tag>Apply to runtime when supported or mark pending restart if the data-plane requires restart.</fn-apply-promotion-tag>
    <runtime-proxy-ad-tag>Pass the configured value as PROXY_AD_TAG/MTPROTO_AD_TAG without logging it.</runtime-proxy-ad-tag>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-006,M-012,M-047,M-049,M-050</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-059</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file status="implemented">backend/app/mtproto/promotion_tag.py</file>
    <file status="implemented">backend/app/admin/router.py</file>
    <file status="implemented">backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file status="unchanged-existing">deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file status="unchanged-existing">.env.example</file>
    <file status="implemented">mtproto-runtime/src/kpproton_app.erl</file>
    <file status="implemented">scripts/phase42-mtproto-promotion-tag-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="phase79-pass-local">scripts/phase79-cyber-title-and-mtproto-promo-safe-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="implemented">backend/tests/test_mtproto_promotion_tag.py</file>
  </files>
  <evidence>pass-live 2026-05-23 and pass-local-phase79 2026-06-06: promotion tag validator/API tests, static smoke, runtime compile, and operator clean-deploy validation passed; Phase-79 smoke confirms anti-abuse alerts do not rotate issued links, expose full tags, or mutate promotion tag state.</evidence>
  <external-reference>
    <source-1>Telegram MTProxy setup documents promotion tags from @MTProxyBot and server-side proxy tag configuration at https://core.telegram.org/proxy.</source-1>
  </external-reference>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Blank tag must never reach runtime; use explicit zero 32-hex fallback when no promotion channel is configured.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Full tag must not appear in admin list views, audit details, logs, telemetry, or frontend bundles.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Changing promotion tag must not rotate user SNI, base secret, salt, or proxy links.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4 phase="79-pass-local">MTProto abuse-alert handling does not change promotion tag state, expose the full tag, or treat promotion-sharing as automatic abuse.</constraint-4>
  </constraints>
  <phase-79-executed-scope>
    <scope>Phase-79 kept promotion tag control independent from anti-abuse: links, SNI, tag validation, masking, and runtime application semantics remain unchanged.</scope>
    <verification>PASS local: backend promotion-tag tests, Phase-42 smoke, and Phase-79 smoke prove tag state is masked and independent from MTProto alert handling.</verification>
  </phase-79-executed-scope>
  <hotspot>H-046: Promotion tag control must validate MTProxyBot tags, avoid blank runtime tags, and never log full tags</hotspot>
</M-059>
