<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-058 NAME="mtproto-admin-analytics-ui" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pass-local-phase43">
  <path>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-42.xml docs/plans/Phase-43.xml</path>
  <owns>Compact admin UI for MTProto usage analytics, per-proxy details, abuse signals, runtime health, availability proof, and promotion tag controls.</owns>
  <purpose>Let the operator analyze MTProto usage from desktop or mobile admin panel without exposing secrets.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <view-mtproto-analytics>Admin page or MTProto tab for global metrics, traffic windows, active connections, top users, and error summaries.</view-mtproto-analytics>
    <view-mtproto-assignment-detail>Per-proxy detail panel with last seen, session count, duration, traffic, errors, and abuse flags.</view-mtproto-assignment-detail>
    <view-mtproto-user-investigation>Phase-43 compact user/proxy drawer with issued time, last seen, current IP, last IP, 90-day IP history, sessions, graphs, and errors.</view-mtproto-user-investigation>
    <view-mtproto-alert-inbox>Phase-43 admin alert inbox for high/critical abuse signals with acknowledge, resolve, disable proxy, and TTL IP block actions.</view-mtproto-alert-inbox>
    <view-mtproto-promotion-tag>Promotion tag form showing masked current tag, validation state, apply status, and pending restart state.</view-mtproto-promotion-tag>
    <smoke-admin-analytics-redaction>Static smoke ensuring UI bundles do not render full tg links, secrets, tokens, or raw tags.</smoke-admin-analytics-redaction>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-010,M-037,M-038,M-057,M-059,M-060,M-061</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-058</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file status="implemented">scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file status="implemented">scripts/phase43-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <evidence>pass-local 2026-05-21: frontend-admin build and Phase-42/Phase-43 admin analytics static smokes passed; UI removes Recent events, paginates large proxy/user lists, exposes compact area graphs, clarifies source-IP unavailable states, splits Abuse into open inbox plus archive, and standardizes icon input padding.</evidence>
  <ui-policy>
    <policy-1>Mobile layout uses dense summary rows, tabs, filters, and drill-down panels rather than large decorative dashboards.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Promotion tag editing requires confirmation and never displays the full stored tag after save.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Abuse signals are visibly observe-only in Phase-42.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>Phase-43 removes the visible Recent events panel and replaces it with compact Overview, Users, Abuse, and Settings surfaces.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>Raw IP values may render only inside the explicit admin investigation drawer and must never appear in general analytics cards or static smoke output.</policy-5>
    <policy-6>Large assignment/user inventories must use compact paging and bounded scroll panes so the admin panel remains usable with thousands of proxies.</policy-6>
    <policy-7>Abuse actions remove items from the open inbox by querying only open alerts, while acknowledged/resolved alerts remain visible in an archive list.</policy-7>
  </ui-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Admin UI must not hide existing MTProto reissue/revoke controls.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Frontend build and mobile smoke must pass before phase closure.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <hotspot>H-045: Admin analytics UI must remain compact on mobile while exposing enough filters for incident triage</hotspot>
</M-058>
