<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-054 NAME="mtproto-usage-telemetry" TYPE="DATA_LAYER" STATUS="planned">
  <path>backend/app/mtproto backend/alembic docs/plans/Phase-42.xml</path>
  <owns>PostgreSQL-backed MTProto usage events, connection sessions, traffic rollups, last-seen metadata, and abuse-signal records.</owns>
  <purpose>Persist metadata-only MTProto proxy usage so admins can analyze service activity without inspecting Telegram payloads.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <model-MTProtoUsageEvent>Append-only event row for handshake, close, bytes, error, unknown_sni, rejected_sni, and req_pq proof events.</model-MTProtoUsageEvent>
    <model-MTProtoUsageSession>Per-assignment session row with start, end, duration, status, byte counters, and active flag.</model-MTProtoUsageSession>
    <model-MTProtoUsageRollup>Hourly, daily, and monthly aggregate counters by assignment and global scope.</model-MTProtoUsageRollup>
    <model-MTProtoAbuseSignal>Observe-only abuse signal row for many IPs, high concurrency, traffic spikes, and repeated failures.</model-MTProtoAbuseSignal>
    <fn-ingest-telemetry-batch>Store runtime telemetry batches idempotently by runtime event id.</fn-ingest-telemetry-batch>
    <fn-update-last-seen>Update last successful MTProto handshake timestamp per assignment.</fn-update-last-seen>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-042,M-028</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-054</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file planned="true">backend/app/mtproto/usage_models.py</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/app/mtproto/usage_repository.py</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/alembic/versions/phase42_add_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py</file>
    <file planned="true">backend/tests/test_mtproto_usage_telemetry.py</file>
  </files>
  <data-contract>
    <field-1>assignment_id links usage to MTProtoAssignment when SNI is known.</field-1>
    <field-2>Unknown or rejected SNI events may store masked SNI and safe reason codes but never derived secrets or tg links.</field-2>
    <field-3>Client IP is stored as HMAC/hash or prefix-based aggregate by default, not raw public IP unless an explicit future privacy decision allows it.</field-3>
    <field-4>Rollups must be sufficient for day, week, month, top users, last seen, connection count, duration, and traffic views.</field-4>
  </data-contract>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Telemetry persistence must not block live MTProto proxy traffic.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Retention policy must keep raw events bounded while preserving rollups.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Backup/restore must preserve rollups and assignments without exposing secrets.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <hotspot>H-041: MTProto telemetry must support useful analytics without storing raw secrets, full proxy links, or unnecessary raw IP addresses</hotspot>
</M-054>
