<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-052 NAME="official-mtproxy-data-plane" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="partial-live">
  <path>official-mtproxy deploy docker-compose.yml deploy/deploy-on-server.sh deploy/haproxy-phase40.cfg deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml scripts/phase40-official-mtproxy-live-smoke.sh docs/plans/Phase-40.xml</path>
  <owns>Official Telegram MTProxy runtime, redacted runtime launcher, local stats/health contract, and RU-to-DE MTProto data-plane routing.</owns>
  <purpose>Provide the production MTProto data-plane that real Telegram clients can validate through req_pq while KrotPN remains the control-plane for users and secrets.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <runtime-official-mtproxy>Runs the official mtproto-proxy binary on the DE MTProto node with generated -S user secrets.</runtime-official-mtproxy>
    <launcher-redacted>Starts the runtime from a secret manifest without printing full tg links or raw secrets.</launcher-redacted>
    <stats-private>Exposes MTProxy stats only over a private or loopback-only path for operator health checks.</stats-private>
    <ru-mtproto-route>Receives non-HTTPS MTProto traffic from the RU public 443 router and forwards it to DE.</ru-mtproto-route>
    <phase40-live-smoke>Validates public RU 443 to DE official runtime with an operator-safe req_pq probe.</phase40-live-smoke>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-050,M-051</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-052</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/entrypoint.sh</file>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/Dockerfile</file>
    <file implemented="true">official-mtproxy/secret-control.py</file>
    <file implemented="true">deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file implemented="true">deploy/haproxy-phase40.cfg</file>
    <file implemented="true">deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file implemented="true">docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file implemented="true">scripts/phase40-official-mtproxy-live-smoke.sh</file>
    <file implemented="true">backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
  </files>
  <data-plane-contract>
    <contract-1>The official runtime accepts one or more active user secrets as 32-hex -S values.</contract-1>
    <contract-2>The user-facing secure link uses secret=dd&lt;32-hex-secret&gt;, but the runtime receives the secret without the dd prefix.</contract-2>
    <contract-3>The launcher must obtain Telegram proxy-secret and proxy-multi.conf using the official upstream endpoints or existing cached files, with refresh behavior documented for restart.</contract-3>
    <contract-4>Runtime health must include ready/active target checks where available and must not require public stats exposure.</contract-4>
  </data-plane-contract>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not use a wrapper mode that prints generated proxy links or raw secrets into docker logs.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Do not rely on the old KPprotoN fake-TLS policy API as the production data-plane gate.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Public TCP 443 changes must preserve HTTPS reachability for krotpn.xyz and admin 8443 behavior.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Restart-on-secret-manifest-change is acceptable in Phase-40, but apply failure must be visible as degraded and retryable.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Any runtime token, private key, proxy-secret file, user secret, or full proxy link must be redacted from logs and smoke output.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-19: Phase-39 client-level diagnostics found req_pq timeout through the current KPprotoN/Erlang runtime.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-19: Temporary official MTProxy runtime on the DE host passed normal and secure req_pq smoke, proving the official runtime is the selected Phase-40 data-plane.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-19: Local execution added official-mtproxy runtime scaffold, Phase-40 HAProxy router, DE compose wiring, deploy copy/env changes, redacted live-smoke gate, and deploy/static tests; clean-VPS live req_pq remains pending.</evidence-3>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-039: Official MTProxy runtime must pass req_pq through public 443 and must not print generated links or secrets through default wrapper logs.</hotspot>
</M-052>
