<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-058 NAME="mtproto-admin-analytics-ui" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pass-local-phase42">
  <path>frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-42.xml</path>
  <owns>Compact admin UI for MTProto usage analytics, per-proxy details, abuse signals, runtime health, availability proof, and promotion tag controls.</owns>
  <purpose>Let the operator analyze MTProto usage from desktop or mobile admin panel without exposing secrets.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <view-mtproto-analytics>Admin page or MTProto tab for global metrics, traffic windows, active connections, top users, and error summaries.</view-mtproto-analytics>
    <view-mtproto-assignment-detail>Per-proxy detail panel with last seen, session count, duration, traffic, errors, and abuse flags.</view-mtproto-assignment-detail>
    <view-mtproto-promotion-tag>Promotion tag form showing masked current tag, validation state, apply status, and pending restart state.</view-mtproto-promotion-tag>
    <smoke-admin-analytics-redaction>Static smoke ensuring UI bundles do not render full tg links, secrets, tokens, or raw tags.</smoke-admin-analytics-redaction>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-010,M-037,M-038,M-057,M-059</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-058</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file status="implemented">frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file status="implemented">scripts/phase42-mtproto-admin-analytics-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <evidence>pass-local 2026-05-19: frontend-admin build and Phase-42 admin analytics static smoke passed.</evidence>
  <ui-policy>
    <policy-1>Mobile layout uses dense summary rows, tabs, filters, and drill-down panels rather than large decorative dashboards.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>Promotion tag editing requires confirmation and never displays the full stored tag after save.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Abuse signals are visibly observe-only in Phase-42.</policy-3>
  </ui-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Admin UI must not hide existing MTProto reissue/revoke controls.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Frontend build and mobile smoke must pass before phase closure.</constraint-2>
  </constraints>
  <hotspot>H-045: Admin analytics UI must remain compact on mobile while exposing enough filters for incident triage</hotspot>
</M-058>
