<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-050 NAME="mtproto-de-backed-edge" TYPE="INTEGRATION" STATUS="pass-live-phase41">
  <path>mtproto-runtime nginx docker-compose.yml deploy/deploy-on-server.sh deploy/haproxy-phase38.cfg deploy/haproxy-phase40.cfg deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml backend/app/core/config.py backend/app/mtproto scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs scripts/phase41-kpproton-faketls-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-38.xml docs/plans/Phase-40.xml docs/plans/Phase-41.xml</path>
  <owns>DE-hosted MTProto runtime, RU public TCP 443 router, private RU-to-DE policy/API reachability, superseded official MTProxy routing, planned Phase-41 KPprotoN SNI routing, and live Telegram availability gates.</owns>
  <purpose>Restore Telegram MTProto availability by routing issued user SNI traffic from the RU public edge to a DE-hosted MTProto runtime while keeping HTTPS on krotpn.xyz available.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <ru-sni-router>Public RU TCP 443 router classifies TLS ClientHello SNI and sends web SNI to local nginx fallback or issued MTProto SNI to DE runtime.</ru-sni-router>
    <de-mtproto-runtime>DE runtime owns the real MTProto fake-TLS service and upstream Telegram DC connectivity.</de-mtproto-runtime>
    <de-policy-api>Token-protected policy API is reachable only from RU/backend over the private RU-DE path and never from the public internet.</de-policy-api>
    <assignment-replay>Existing active assignment SNI policies are replayed to the DE runtime without rotating MTPROTO_BASE_SECRET_HEX or MTPROTO_SECRET_SALT.</assignment-replay>
    <phase38-smoke>Static and live smoke gates prove routing roles, policy redaction, HTTPS fallback, and Telegram Desktop availability.</phase38-smoke>
    <phase40-routing superseded="planned-phase41">Route HTTPS ClientHello traffic to web/admin fallbacks while routing non-HTTPS MTProto traffic to M-052 official MTProxy.</phase40-routing>
    <phase41-routing status="pass-live">Restore issued wildcard SNI routing to the DE KPprotoN fake-TLS runtime while web SNI continues to nginx fallback.</phase41-routing>
    <de-mtproto-ad-tag>DE runtime propagates MTPROTO_AD_TAG/PROXY_AD_TAG and defaults it to 32 zero hex chars so Telegram proxy_req receives a valid tag.</de-mtproto-ad-tag>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-012,M-043,M-044,M-046,M-048,M-049,M-052</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-050</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>deploy/deploy-on-server.sh</file>
    <file>deploy/haproxy-phase38.cfg</file>
    <file>deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml</file>
    <file>docker-compose.yml</file>
    <file>nginx/nginx.conf</file>
    <file>mtproto-runtime</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/config.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/runtime_bridge.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/mtproto/provisioning.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_mtproto_de_edge_contract.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_deploy_phase38_static.py</file>
    <file>scripts/phase38-de-mtproto-edge-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-38.xml</file>
    <file>docs/verification/V-M-050.xml</file>
  </files>
  <edge-policy>
    <policy-1>RU public TCP 443 has exactly one owner: the SNI router.</policy-1>
    <policy-2>RU web SNI names such as krotpn.xyz and www.krotpn.xyz route to local private nginx HTTPS fallback on 9443.</policy-2>
    <policy-3>Issued MTProto SNI names under the configured wildcard domain route to the DE MTProto runtime.</policy-3>
    <policy-4>DE policy API binds privately and requires the existing runtime token or a deploy-generated replacement that is never logged.</policy-4>
    <policy-5>Existing assignment secrets, salts, SNI names, and tg links must be preserved unless an explicit reissue phase is approved.</policy-5>
    <policy-6 superseded="planned-phase41">Phase-40 treats official per-user secrets as the MTProto access primitive; user wildcard hostnames may remain stable labels but no longer drive fake-TLS SNI policy routing.</policy-6>
    <policy-7 status="pass-local">Phase-41 restores issued wildcard hostnames as the routing and policy primitive for KPprotoN fake-TLS proxy access.</policy-7>
    <policy-8 status="pass-live">DE KPprotoN runtime must not start with a blank proxy ad tag; use a real MTProxyBot tag or the zero 32-hex tag.</policy-8>
  </edge-policy>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No public exposure of the DE policy API, runtime token, private key, base secret, salt, derived secret, or full proxy link.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>RU HTTPS rollback must remain available before any public 443 ownership change is applied.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Telegram availability release gates require operator-live proof with a real Telegram client after DE runtime activation.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <planned-execution>
    <step-1 STATUS="pass-local">Design the RU SNI router target map for web SNI, wildcard MTProto SNI, and unknown SNI fallback behavior.</step-1>
    <step-2 STATUS="pass-local">Define DE runtime install, TLS material delivery, firewall, and private policy API reachability.</step-2>
    <step-3 STATUS="pass-local">Update backend bridge settings so policy apply/revoke/health can target the DE policy API safely.</step-3>
    <step-4 STATUS="pass-local">Add deterministic local/static smoke coverage and live operator gates.</step-4>
  </planned-execution>
  <evidence>
    <evidence-1>2026-05-18: Phase-37 local runtime wiring exists, but RU live mtproto_proxy downstream handshakes remain blocked and nginx public 443 rollback keeps web available.</evidence-1>
    <evidence-2>2026-05-18: Phase-38 planning selects DE-backed MTProto runtime plus RU SNI router as the safer production architecture.</evidence-2>
    <evidence-3>2026-05-18: Phase-38 local execution added RU HAProxy SNI router, DE runtime compose/deploy wiring, private policy bind, backend private policy URL guards, secret-preserving deploy env generation, and deterministic smoke/pytest coverage.</evidence-3>
    <evidence-4>2026-05-18: Clean VPS deploy found HAProxy lacked low-port bind permission for 443 and the admin 8443 URL collided with the web fallback; fixed by running sni-router with NET_BIND_SERVICE/root and moving web fallback to private 9443 while preserving admin 8443.</evidence-4>
    <evidence-5>2026-05-18: DE runtime follow-up found the policy API healthy on the private bind but mtproto_proxy down because bootstrap still used 127.0.0.1; fixed by deriving bootstrap from POLICY_LISTEN_IP.</evidence-5>
    <evidence-6>2026-05-18: Live RU/DE checks passed for public web/admin titles, RU 443 HAProxy ownership, private nginx fallback 9443, public admin 8443, DE listener 443, private policy health, and HAProxy mtproto_de_runtime backend UP.</evidence-6>
    <evidence-7>2026-05-18: Phase-39 live smoke detected and corrected stale DE domain-fronting fallback 8443 to private 9443; rerun passed fake-TLS accept and Telegram downstream reachability.</evidence-7>
    <evidence-8>2026-05-19: Phase-40 plan changes the production route target from KPprotoN fake-TLS data-plane to official MTProxy after client-level req_pq failed.</evidence-8>
    <evidence-9>2026-05-19: Phase-41 verification design supersedes the Phase-40 routing target and restores DE KPprotoN fake-TLS routing for issued wildcard SNI names.</evidence-9>
    <evidence-10>2026-05-19: Phase-41 local execution restored the active compose/deploy surface to deploy/haproxy-phase38.cfg plus deploy/mtproto-de-compose.yml KPprotoN runtime, with static deploy/edge tests and smoke passing.</evidence-10>
    <evidence-11>2026-05-19: Live DE runtime with blank tag reproduced issued-link req_pq timeout; adding PROXY_AD_TAG=00000000000000000000000000000000 and replaying active policy made mtp_ping pass for the issued u-*.krotpn.xyz proxy across DC +1 through +5.</evidence-11>
    <evidence-12>2026-05-19: Operator clean-deploy validation confirmed RU public HTTPS, admin access, VPN, and Telegram Desktop/mobile MTProto proxy behavior are working from the Phase-41 edge.</evidence-12>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-037: DE-backed MTProto edge and RU SNI router can break HTTPS or expose policy/cert material unless routing, private API reachability, and redaction gates are strict.</hotspot>
</M-050>
