<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-068 NAME="paid-tariff-catalog" TYPE="CORE_LOGIC" STATUS="done-local-phase50-phase53-phase54-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase73-pass-local-phase74">
  <path>backend/app/billing backend/app/core/migrations.py backend/alembic/versions/phase50_paid_tariff_catalog.py frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/i18n/index.ts frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs README.md docs/plans/Phase-50.xml docs/plans/Phase-53.xml docs/plans/Phase-54.xml docs/plans/Phase-68.xml docs/plans/Phase-73.xml docs/plans/Phase-74.xml</path>
  <owns>Canonical three-plan paid tariff catalog, server-authoritative payment amounts, device-limit checkout guards, compact tariff presentation in the user frontend, and historical hidden admin tariff inspection code retained for regression only after Phase-74.</owns>
  <purpose>Guarantee that clean deployments and existing deployments converge to the approved KrotPN paid tariff matrix without trusting frontend-provided prices.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <fn-canonical-tariff-catalog>Return the approved paid tariff definitions: 1 device for 369 RUB, 6 devices for 693 RUB, and 9 devices for 936 RUB.</fn-canonical-tariff-catalog>
    <fn-upsert-canonical-tariffs>Idempotently create or update canonical plan rows without duplicating plans on backend restart.</fn-upsert-canonical-tariffs>
    <fn-validate-checkout-plan>Validate that a selected plan is active, canonical, and compatible with the user's current consumed device slots before payment creation.</fn-validate-checkout-plan>
    <ui-user-tariff-cards>Render exactly three compact user-facing tariff cards with price, duration, device limit, and checkout action.</ui-user-tariff-cards>
    <ui-admin-tariff-matrix>Historical hidden admin tariff matrix retained for Phase-50/54 regression proof only; Phase-74 removes it from visible admin navigation and direct route display.</ui-admin-tariff-matrix>
    <smoke-phase50-tariff-catalog>Static smoke for user/admin tariff copy, canonical price/device-limit values, and protected deploy/install surfaces.</smoke-phase50-tariff-catalog>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-001,M-004,M-006,M-009,M-010,M-021,M-022,M-028,M-036,M-038,M-071</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-068</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>backend/app/billing/catalog.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/__init__.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/models.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/service.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/router.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/billing/yookassa.py</file>
    <file>backend/app/core/migrations.py</file>
    <file>backend/alembic/versions/phase50_paid_tariff_catalog.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_tariff_catalog.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_service.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_billing_plan_api.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_device_access_policy.py</file>
    <file>backend/tests/test_db_migrations.py</file>
    <file>frontend/src/lib/api.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/i18n/index.ts</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Plans.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/types/index.ts</file>
    <file>scripts/phase50-tariff-catalog-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>README.md</file>
  </files>
  <tariffs>
    <tariff-1 slug="krotpn-1" name="KrotPN 1" price-rub="369" duration-days="30" device-limit="1" sort-order="10" popular="false" />
    <tariff-2 slug="krotpn-6" name="KrotPN 6" price-rub="693" duration-days="30" device-limit="6" sort-order="20" popular="true" />
    <tariff-3 slug="krotpn-9" name="KrotPN 9" price-rub="936" duration-days="30" device-limit="9" sort-order="30" popular="false" />
  </tariffs>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Frontend may submit only plan_id; backend must derive price, currency, duration_days, device_limit, description, and YooKassa metadata from server-side canonical state.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Clean deploys and backend restarts must not create duplicate plan rows or silently leave stale canonical prices active.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Purchasing a lower device-limit tariff must be blocked when active or blocked device slots already exceed the target limit.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Pending four-day trial behavior from M-063 remains unchanged; successful paid checkout cancels pending trial and activates paid access immediately after payment webhook.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Personal MTProto proxy entitlement remains verified-email based and is not moved behind paid tariffs in Phase-50.</constraint-5>
    <constraint-6>Do not modify install.sh, deploy scripts, docker-compose, nginx routing, TLS material, VPN runtime topology, or MTProto runtime topology.</constraint-6>
    <constraint-7>Phase-74 may remove only the visible admin tariff section and direct /plans display; backend catalog, user purchase cards, checkout guards, canonical values, and Phase-50 regression proof remain intact.</constraint-7>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1>Public billing plans API returns exactly the three active canonical tariffs in sort order with 30-day duration, RUB currency, and device limits 1, 6, and 9.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Payment creation and YooKassa payload use backend-derived amounts 369.00, 693.00, and 936.00 and include non-secret tariff metadata.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Device provisioning enforces the purchased plan limit and checkout blocks incompatible downgrades before payment creation.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>User and admin frontends build and show compact, Russian, mobile-safe tariff surfaces with no stale placeholder CRUD wording.</metric-4>
    <metric-5>Backend tariff, billing, device-limit, migration, frontend build, admin build, static smoke, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, and protected deploy/install diff guard pass.</metric-5>
    <metric-6>Phase-50 verification design is complete before execution: deterministic assertions, trace markers, UI/API contract, and protected-surface guard are explicitly mapped in V-M-068.</metric-6>
    <metric-7>Phase-53 smoke confirms Matrix subscription UI preserves canonical tariff slugs, server-authoritative checkout shape, and mobile readability.</metric-7>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <evidence>2026-06-03: Phase-53 and Phase-54 frontend/admin builds and smokes passed for Matrix tariff UI while preserving backend canonical 369/693/936 RUB prices, 1/6/9 device limits, plan_id-only checkout shape, and readonly admin canonical plan controls. 2026-06-04: Phase-68 smoke and Phase-50 tariff smoke passed after display aliases changed to KrotPN Self/Family/Team without changing canonical slugs, prices, limits, or checkout shape.</evidence>
  <phase-54-verification-design>
    <surface-1>Admin Plans Matrix verification must preserve exactly KrotPN 1/6/9 with 369/693/936 RUB prices and 1/6/9 device limits.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Admin tariff UI must stay inspection-focused without accidental canonical edit/delete controls or frontend-controlled money fields.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>Mobile smoke must prove compact readability for tariff rows/cards without horizontal overflow.</surface-3>
  </phase-54-verification-design>
  <phase-54-execution>
    <surface-1>Admin Plans page is compact Matrix-styled and marked with canonical tariff readability plus no-CRUD drift guards.</surface-1>
    <surface-2>Phase-54 did not change billing catalog, payment creation, YooKassa payloads, device-limit guards, migrations, or deploy/install surfaces.</surface-2>
    <surface-3>2026-06-03: Phase-54 smoke confirmed KrotPN 1/6/9 canonical tariff values and absence of admin create/update/delete plan controls.</surface-3>
  </phase-54-execution>
  <phase-73-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/i18n/index.ts scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Expose only the display tariff name in the config page device-limit exhausted copy; canonical tariff slugs, prices, duration, device limits, checkout payload, and admin tariff surfaces remain unchanged.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-73 smoke passed display-name-only and device-limit-message-safe markers; no billing API, YooKassa, device-limit enforcement, or admin plan code changed.</verification>
  </phase-73-executed-scope>
  <phase-73-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Config page reads existing subscription display data for copy only and maps legacy KrotPN 1/6/9 names to Self/Family/Team presentation aliases.</phase-73-evidence>
  <phase-74-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/main.tsx scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Remove visible admin Tariffs navigation and redirect direct /plans to dashboard while keeping backend canonical tariffs and user-facing tariff purchase UI unchanged.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-74 smoke passed ADMIN_TARIFF_UI_REMOVED_ONLY and CANONICAL_TARIFFS_PRESERVED markers; Phase-50 tariff smoke remains part of the regression suite.</verification>
  </phase-74-executed-scope>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Admin tariff UI is retired from the shell only; canonical slugs krotpn-1/krotpn-6/krotpn-9, prices, device limits, checkout shape, and user tariff aliases remain protected.</phase-74-evidence>
  <hotspot>H-055: Paid tariff catalog must keep server-authoritative prices, canonical device limits, no duplicate clean-deploy plans, and no deploy/install drift</hotspot>
</M-068>
