<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-079 NAME="premium-email-templates" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="planned-phase66">
  <path>backend/app/email/templates.py backend/app/email/service.py backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py docs/plans/Phase-64.xml docs/plans/Phase-66.xml scripts/phase64-premium-email-template-smoke.mjs scripts/phase66-minimal-email-template-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Premium Matrix/cyberpunk Resend verification and password-reset email templates.</owns>
  <purpose>Bring transactional email visual quality in line with the premium KrotPN frontend without weakening token safety.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <template-premium-verification>Email verification HTML/text templates with logo, action button, security copy, and spam-safe structure.</template-premium-verification>
    <template-premium-reset>Password reset HTML/text templates with one-time token semantics and clear safety copy.</template-premium-reset>
    <rule-email-fallback>Readable text fallback without image URLs, raw tokens, or visual-only meaning.</rule-email-fallback>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-040,M-062,M-069,M-072,M-080</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-079</verification-ref>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Verification/reset tokens, provider keys, and full one-time URLs must never leak to logs or provider error details.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Email must remain usable when remote images are blocked by the mailbox client.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Template changes do not modify Resend deploy configuration or provider semantics.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local-phase64">Backend email tests pass for verification and reset templates.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-phase64">Phase-64 smoke proves logo URL, text fallback, token redaction, and dark-email compatibility markers.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="pass-local-phase64">Protected deploy/install guard remains clean.</metric-3>
    <metric-4 status="verification-designed-phase64">V-M-079 maps HTML/text/token/provider/logo/protected-surface gates before execution changes are made.</metric-4>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <verification-design>
    <target-1>Verification and password-reset templates must share a premium email shell without changing one-time token, pending registration, or password reset semantics.</target-1>
    <target-2>Text fallback must stay plain, readable, independent of remote images, and free of visual-only meaning.</target-2>
    <target-3>Body logo usage must rely on an approved public frontend asset URL and must not claim mailbox sender-avatar, BIMI provider, or DNS behavior.</target-3>
    <target-4>Phase-64 execution must not modify Resend installer wiring, EMAIL_FROM, provider credentials, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, VPN, or MTProto runtime behavior.</target-4>
    <target-5>Phase-66 must remove operator-specified verbose Matrix/access/security copy, the green top-strip, and opaque outer background while preserving CTA/fallback usability and token safety.</target-5>
  </verification-design>
  <phase-66-plan>
    <scope>Minimal verification/reset email polish: larger body logo, shorter content, no KrotPN Matrix Access label, no eyebrow/intro/support/footer noise, no #5cf2c8 card-edge strip, and transparent outer wrapper background.</scope>
    <protected-surfaces>Resend provider configuration, EMAIL_FROM, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, DNS/BIMI, frontend public/user/admin pages, auth token semantics, password policy, billing, VPN, and MTProto runtime remain out of scope.</protected-surfaces>
    <planned-verification>backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py, scripts/phase64-premium-email-template-smoke.mjs, scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs, scripts/phase66-minimal-email-template-smoke.mjs, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected surface guard.</planned-verification>
  </phase-66-plan>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-04>Premium verification/reset templates now share an email-client-safe Matrix shell, public email-logo body image, CTA button, compact fallback panel, plain text fallback, and required Phase-64 redaction/brand/protected-surface markers without changing Resend provider configuration or deploy/runtime surfaces.</local-2026-06-04>
    <verification-2026-06-04>Passed: backend/tests/test_email_delivery.py 5/5, scripts/phase64-premium-email-template-smoke.mjs, scripts/phase51-brand-assets-smoke.mjs, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected deploy/provider/runtime/frontend guard.</verification-2026-06-04>
  </execution-evidence>
  <hotspot>H-066: Premium Resend templates must remain token-safe, text-fallback clean, and compatible with image-blocking email clients.</hotspot>
</M-079>
