<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-075 NAME="premium-user-cabinet" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase57-planned-phase62">
  <path>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/pages/Subscription.tsx frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx frontend/src/pages/Settings.tsx docs/plans/Phase-57.xml docs/plans/Phase-62.xml scripts/phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Premium compact personal cabinet for VPN, MTProto, subscription, devices, referrals, and settings.</owns>
  <purpose>Turn the user cabinet into a compact premium command center without hiding core actions.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <view-premium-user-home>First-screen VPN state, config action, subscription countdown, and MTProto access.</view-premium-user-home>
    <view-premium-config>QR, download, copy, and raw config workflow with compact premium controls.</view-premium-config>
    <view-premium-subscription>Tariff, countdown, calendar, and renewal flow with server-derived data.</view-premium-subscription>
    <rule-user-deletion-audit>Remove duplicated, bulky, decorative, or non-actionable user-cabinet content.</rule-user-deletion-audit>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-036,M-045,M-063,M-064,M-068,M-070,M-071,M-072,M-074</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-075</verification-ref>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>VPN config and subscription actions must remain reachable within one or two taps on phone.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Owner-only MTProto secrets and links must remain redacted from logs and unavailable to other users.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>No backend API, deploy, install, billing, VPN, or MTProto runtime behavior changes are included.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local">Frontend build and premium user smoke passed on 2026-06-03.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-static">Static route proof and CSS guards cover compact first screen, no legacy route redirects, and no horizontal scroll primitives; authenticated screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="planned-phase62">Deletion audit remains Phase-62 scope; Phase-57 only collapsed and compacted protected user surfaces while preserving primary workflows.</metric-3>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <evidence>2026-06-03: Phase-57 added protected user command center, /dashboard/* primary actions, compact config/subscription/referral/settings surfaces, Phase-57 smoke, frontend build, Phase-45/46/48/50/52/53/55/56 regression smokes, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</evidence>
  <hotspot>H-062: Premium user cabinet must keep VPN config, subscription, MTProto, and device actions reachable in one or two taps.</hotspot>
</M-075>
