<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-078 NAME="premium-frontend-qa-gates" TYPE="UTILITY" STATUS="pass-local-phase60-verification-designed-phase65">
  <path>scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs scripts/phase65-premium-rc-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-60.xml docs/plans/Phase-65.xml</path>
  <owns>Premium frontend verification gates for screenshots, performance, reduced-motion, responsive safety, and release readiness.</owns>
  <purpose>Prevent premium visual work from shipping with usability, performance, or MyGRACE drift regressions.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <gate-screenshot-matrix>Public, auth, user, admin, email-template preview screenshot matrix.</gate-screenshot-matrix>
    <gate-performance-budget>Bundle, Lighthouse/Web Vitals, canvas CPU, and motion budget checks.</gate-performance-budget>
    <gate-accessibility-motion>Reduced-motion, focus-visible, contrast, no-overlap, and keyboard reachability checks.</gate-accessibility-motion>
    <gate-protected-surface>Deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime diff guard.</gate-protected-surface>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-010,M-036,M-037,M-038,M-070,M-071,M-073,M-074,M-075,M-076,M-077,M-079,M-080</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-078</verification-ref>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>QA gates must fail on visual overlap, horizontal scroll, broken reduced-motion, or protected deploy/install drift.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Authenticated protected-route screenshot gaps must be explicit rather than implied as covered.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Release candidate gate must include MyGRACE lint and XML parse.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local-phase60">Phase-60 smoke script passes locally.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-phase60">User/admin builds and git diff --check pass.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="pass-local-phase60">Protected deploy/install/backend/runtime guard remains empty unless a separate approved deploy phase exists.</metric-3>
    <metric-4 status="verification-designed-phase65">Phase-65 release-candidate verification is designed with full premium regression smokes, builds, backend email tests, screenshot/static evidence, release notes, live-gap recording, MyGRACE checks, and protected-surface guard.</metric-4>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <verification-design-phase65>
    <target-1>Phase-65 must run the complete premium regression train from Phase-55 through Phase-64 plus Phase-60 QA, user/admin builds, and backend email tests before any release-candidate decision.</target-1>
    <target-2>Release-candidate evidence must separate local/static proof from clean-deploy-only proof, especially authenticated protected-route screenshots and delivered Resend email rendering.</target-2>
    <target-3>Release notes must be generated for premium Matrix frontend, responsive adaptation, compactness, visible logos, and premium Resend templates without tagging or pushing a release during verification design.</target-3>
    <target-4>Protected deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/VPN/MTProto/runtime/provider surfaces must remain unchanged unless a separate approved release/deploy phase explicitly owns that change.</target-4>
  </verification-design-phase65>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: node scripts/phase60-premium-qa-smoke.mjs passed with required PremiumQAGates markers.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend and frontend-admin production builds passed; dist artifact budgets are below Phase-60 limits.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-52/55/56/57/58/59 regression smokes passed and are wired into the Phase-60 QA gate.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</item>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-065: Premium QA gates must include screenshots, performance budgets, reduced-motion, no-overlap, and protected deploy/install guards.</hotspot>
</M-078>
