<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-073 NAME="premium-public-site" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase56-pass-local-phase62-pass-local-phase67">
  <path>frontend/src/App.tsx frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/index.css frontend/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx frontend/src/pages/VerifyEmail.tsx frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx docs/plans/Phase-56.xml docs/plans/Phase-62.xml docs/plans/Phase-67.xml scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Phase-67 public splash entry, auth, registration, verification, and password recovery surfaces.</owns>
  <purpose>Present KrotPN public/auth access as a compact premium Matrix entry while keeping registration and email verification clear.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <view-public-entry>Splash-only KrotPN logo animation on / with automatic redirect to /login and no marketing/tariff/product content.</view-public-entry>
    <view-premium-auth>Compact premium login/register/reset/verify screens with logo and clear state feedback.</view-premium-auth>
    <view-tariff-preview>Historical Phase-56 public preview removed from / by Phase-67; M-068 remains the tariff catalog owner for authenticated subscription surfaces.</view-tariff-preview>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-038,M-068,M-069,M-070,M-071,M-072,M-074</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-073</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend/src/App.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Login.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/pages/VerifyEmail.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not issue or imply VPN, trial, JWT, referral, or MTProto access before verified email proof.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Public visual effects must not slow or obscure registration, reset, or verification forms.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Tariff information must not return to / unless a later approved phase changes the Phase-67 splash-only contract.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1>Frontend build passes and public/auth route smoke covers mobile, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Registration pending and duplicate-email recovery states remain clear and token-safe.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Protected deploy/install guard remains clean.</metric-3>
    <metric-4 status="pass-local-phase62">Public value and tariff feature detail copy is folded while registration CTA, email-proof copy, reset, verify, and tariff clarity remain visible.</metric-4>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <phase-67-verification-design>
    <scope>Replace the current public landing presentation with a splash-only logo redirect and retune login/register/forgot/reset into frameless premium Matrix auth surfaces.</scope>
    <copy-contract>Use Кибернетический Протокол Навигации as the auth eyebrow/title replacement, Вход в KrotPN, Присоединиться к KrotPN, and Назначить пароль where requested; remove the operator-listed helper paragraphs and above-field labels while preserving accessible names.</copy-contract>
    <route-contract>/ must redirect to /login after the logo animation; /login, /register, /forgot-password, and /reset-password must preserve current API calls, pending/check-email state, duplicate-email recovery, password example, reset-token handling, and auth state boundaries.</route-contract>
    <negative-contract>No visible matrix-auth-card frame, no framed logo lockup, no public marketing/tariff detail on /, no stale hidden copy, no changed backend/auth/billing/VPN/MTProto/deploy behavior.</negative-contract>
    <verification-status>pass-local</verification-status>
  </phase-67-verification-design>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>Phase-56 added the public / landing route, moved authenticated user cabinet routes under /dashboard with legacy redirects, added visible logo lockups to auth flows, added compact public tariff preview verified against M-068, added scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs, passed frontend build, Phase-44/46/50/52/53/55 regression smokes, captured Chrome screenshot matrix in /tmp/krotpn-phase56-screenshots, passed XML/MyGRACE/diff checks, and kept deploy/install/backend/VPN/MTProto/billing runtime surfaces untouched.</local-2026-06-03>
    <local-2026-06-04-phase62>Phase-62 folded secondary public feature/tariff details, preserved email-proof and auth clarity, and passed frontend build, Phase-56 smoke, Phase-62 smoke, Phase-60/61 regressions, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</local-2026-06-04-phase62>
    <local-2026-06-04-phase67>Phase-67 superseded the Phase-56 public landing with a splash-only / redirect to /login, removed visible auth card frames and requested helper/label copy from login/register/forgot/reset, preserved registration pending/check-email, password example, duplicate-email recovery, reset-token handling, and passed Phase-67 plus Phase-56/60/61/62/63 regressions.</local-2026-06-04-phase67>
  </execution-evidence>
  <hotspot>H-060: Public/auth premium presentation must not delay registration, hide verification states, or imply access before email proof.</hotspot>
</M-073>
