<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-077 NAME="matrix-motion-interactions" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase59-pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72">
  <path>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx frontend/src/pages/Dashboard.tsx frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/pages/Referrals.tsx frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx frontend/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Devices.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProto.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/MTProtoAnalytics.tsx frontend-admin/src/index.css docs/plans/Phase-59.xml docs/plans/Phase-68.xml scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Premium Matrix motion language and microinteractions across user and admin frontends.</owns>
  <purpose>Add high-quality interaction feedback without scroll hijacking, motion overload, or workflow blocking.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <interaction-copy-success>Copy/download/proxy-link feedback animations.</interaction-copy-success>
    <interaction-status-transition>VPN, MTProto, subscription, alert, and health state transitions.</interaction-status-transition>
    <interaction-route-transition>Short route entrance transitions that preserve navigation speed.</interaction-route-transition>
    <interaction-root-transform-safety>Route transition transform is applied to the content layer, not the root fixed-background shell.</interaction-root-transform-safety>
    <rule-reduced-motion>Static/fade-only fallback for all motion-heavy effects.</rule-reduced-motion>
    <interaction-phase71-close-and-calendar phase="71-pass-local">Icon-only QR close button, device row selection feedback, sticky action feedback, and subscription boundary pulse with reduced-motion fallback.</interaction-phase71-close-and-calendar>
    <interaction-phase72-touch-dock phase="72-pass-local">Touch dock focus/active underline and compact transform feedback without scroll hijacking or pointer interception.</interaction-phase72-touch-dock>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-010,M-070,M-071,M-072,M-075,M-076</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-077</verification-ref>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No scroll hijacking, pointer interception, keyboard trap, blocking loader, or long decorative animation.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>All motion must respect prefers-reduced-motion and inactive-tab lifecycle.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Critical text, forms, tables, QR/config, and admin controls must remain readable during transitions.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Route transform animation must not create a transformed ancestor for fixed Matrix canvas/fallback layers.</constraint-4>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="passed-local">User and admin builds pass with motion smoke.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="passed-static">Reduced-motion static-route proof confirms static/fade fallback markers; authenticated screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="passed-local">Smoke confirms pointer-events safety and no scroll hijacking markers.</metric-3>
    <metric-4 status="pass-local-rainfix">Phase-59 smoke confirms root shell does not carry motion-route-enter and the content layer does.</metric-4>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend npm run build passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend-admin npm run build passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: node scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs, phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs, phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs, and phase57-premium-user-cabinet-smoke.mjs passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: protected backend/deploy/runtime diff guard passed; post-commit Phase-58 regression smoke passed after HEAD included Phase-59 frontend changes.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: rainfix updated Phase-59 smoke to assert CSS rain fallback, mobile overscan, visualViewport listeners, and root transform safety; node scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-68 reused motion-interactive/status primitives for compact dashboard/subscription controls; Phase-59 and Phase-68 smokes passed.</item>
  </evidence>
  <phase-71-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Use bounded motion for the new X close icon, selected device rows, sticky action controls, and subscription start/end day pulse without scroll hijacking or transform-heavy reduced-motion regressions.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-71 smoke and Phase-59 regression assert motion budget, pointer/scroll safety, keyboard focus safety, and reduced-motion fallback.</verification>
  </phase-71-executed-scope>
  <hotspot>H-064: Motion and microinteractions must respect reduced-motion, avoid scroll hijacking, and never block operational workflows.</hotspot>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Phase-71 smoke passed for QR close motion, selected-device row feedback, sticky action motion, calendar boundary pulse, and reduced-motion safeguards.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Add bounded bottom-dock hover/focus/active feedback and preserve reduced-motion, keyboard focus, pointer-scroll, and no-scroll-hijack guarantees.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-72 smoke and Phase-59 motion regression passed locally with protected backend/deploy/runtime guards clean.</verification>
  </phase-72-executed-scope>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Matrix motion interactions passed local Phase-72 verification for touch dock reveal and reduced-motion nav safety.</phase-72-evidence>
</M-077>
