<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-070 NAME="matrix-visual-runtime" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase52-phase53-phase54-phase59-planned-phase67">
  <path>frontend/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx frontend/src/components/VisualShell.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/MatrixBackground.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/VisualShell.tsx scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-52.xml docs/plans/Phase-53.xml docs/plans/Phase-54.xml docs/plans/Phase-59.xml docs/plans/Phase-67.xml scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Shared React/Vite Matrix canvas runtime and CRT overlay mount points for the user frontend and admin frontend.</owns>
  <depends>M-009, M-010, M-038, M-071, M-077</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-070</verification-ref>
  <reference>
    <source-1>TRUFFLEX matrix-background.js Matrix rain loop, resize behavior, pointer influence, and reduced-motion static fallback.</source-1>
    <source-2>TRUFFLEX style-system scanline, flicker, glitch, and matrix fade effects adapted to KrotPN operational screens.</source-2>
  </reference>
  <source-contract>
    <required-header>MODULE_CONTRACT, MODULE_MAP, CHANGE_SUMMARY</required-header>
    <role>UI_COMPONENT</role>
    <map-mode>EXPORTS</map-mode>
  </source-contract>
  <public-interfaces>
    <interface-1>MatrixBackground React component renders a fixed, pointer-events-none canvas layer.</interface-1>
    <interface-2>VisualShell React component mounts MatrixBackground, scanline overlay, and app content with safe z-index boundaries.</interface-2>
    <interface-3>MatrixBackground internal motion policy applies prefers-reduced-motion, tab visibility, resize, and canvas context guards.</interface-3>
  </public-interfaces>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not change backend APIs, auth flows, billing logic, VPN provisioning, MTProto provisioning, deploy scripts, install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or runtime topology.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Canvas failures must degrade to a readable static background without uncaught exceptions.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Animations must stop or simplify under prefers-reduced-motion and inactive-tab conditions.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Do not import TRUFFLEX music, NFT content, spider physics, fluid cursor, or WebGL glow unless a later phase explicitly approves it.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Canvas and overlay layers must never intercept clicks, focus, keyboard navigation, or mobile scroll gestures.</constraint-5>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance>
    <metric-1>Desktop and mobile screenshots prove the Matrix canvas is nonblank while content remains readable.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Reduced-motion screenshot proves a static readable fallback instead of a running animation loop.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Frontend and frontend-admin builds pass with no deploy/install diff.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>Runtime smoke verifies no console errors from canvas init, resize, teardown, or missing context branches.</metric-4>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>Phase-52 implemented MatrixBackground and VisualShell for user/admin frontends, mounted both route trees, added static smoke, passed user/admin builds, and captured Chrome screenshots at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 1440x900, plus reduced-motion 390x844.</local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-53-local-2026-06-03>Phase-53 reused the runtime on all user routes, passed frontend build and Phase-53 smoke, captured production-preview auth screenshots with virtual-time-budget, and preserved pointer-events-none plus reduced-motion policy without deploy/install changes.</phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>Phase-54 verification gates require admin route canvas proof, pointer-safe overlays, reduced-motion admin fallback, no console canvas errors, and protected deploy/install/runtime isolation.</phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>Phase-54 reused the existing admin VisualShell/MatrixBackground runtime, passed frontend-admin build and Phase-54 smoke, proved pointer-safe/reduced-motion admin markers statically, and made no deploy/install/nginx/docker-compose/runtime changes.</phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-59-local-2026-06-04>Phase-59 added route-motion markers to VisualShell and MatrixMotion reduced-motion, pointer-scroll, and inactive-tab lifecycle markers to MatrixBackground without changing canvas behavior; Phase-52 and Phase-59 smokes passed.</phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
  </evidence>
  <phase-67-plan>
    <scope>Harden the user MatrixBackground browser-compatibility path used on splash/auth routes while preserving the existing visual shell contract.</scope>
    <required-behaviors>Feature-detect canvas, requestAnimationFrame, matchMedia addEventListener/addListener/removeListener variants, 2D context availability, resize cleanup, reduced-motion, and hidden-tab lifecycle without uncaught errors.</required-behaviors>
    <fallback>Unsupported or partially supported browser paths must render a readable static Matrix-safe background and never intercept pointer, keyboard, or scroll interactions.</fallback>
  </phase-67-plan>
  <crosslinks>
    <phase-52>Matrix runtime foundation and shared shell integration.</phase-52>
    <phase-53>User cabinet Matrix redesign uses this runtime.</phase-53>
    <phase-54>Admin console Matrix redesign uses this runtime.</phase-54>
    <phase-59>Motion and microinteraction layer uses runtime lifecycle proof markers.</phase-59>
    <phase-67>Browser compatibility hardening for public splash and auth Matrix canvas behavior.</phase-67>
  </crosslinks>
</M-070>
