<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-072 NAME="premium-art-direction-system" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase55">
  <path>frontend/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/index.css docs/plans/Phase-55.xml scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Premium Matrix/cyberpunk art direction across user, admin, public, and email-adjacent visual systems.</owns>
  <purpose>Raise KrotPN visual quality to a professional premium level while preserving compact operational usability.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <rule-premium-palette>Controlled Matrix green with cyan, magenta, amber, red, neutral, and deep black accents.</rule-premium-palette>
    <rule-premium-type-scale>Readable display, UI, KPI, and monospace data typography scales for phones, tablets, and desktops.</rule-premium-type-scale>
    <rule-premium-density>Compact spacing/radius/shadow rules that avoid bulky cards and nested panels.</rule-premium-density>
    <rule-premium-brand-usage>Logo placement, clear-space, size, contrast, and asset source rules.</rule-premium-brand-usage>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-038,M-069,M-070,M-071</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-072</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-55.xml</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not change backend APIs, auth behavior, VPN, billing, MTProto, deploy, install, nginx, or docker-compose.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Do not use oversized heroes, nested cards, decorative orbs, or one-note green/purple palettes.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Every premium token must remain readable under reduced-motion and low-performance device assumptions.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1>User and admin builds pass after token adoption.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Static smoke proves balanced palette, compact density, focus-visible states, reduced-motion rules, and logo rules.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Screenshot review confirms premium feel without hiding primary workflows.</metric-3>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>Phase-55 added shared premium Matrix tokens to user/admin CSS, removed decorative radial/orb shell backgrounds, preserved compact radii/density, added logo/type/density variables, added scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs, passed user/admin builds, validated screenshot artifacts in /tmp/krotpn-phase55-screenshots, and kept deploy/install/runtime surfaces untouched.</local-2026-06-03>
  </execution-evidence>
  <hotspot>H-059: Premium Matrix art direction must feel distinctive without becoming decorative noise or a one-note neon palette.</hotspot>
</M-072>
