<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-071 NAME="matrix-style-system" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="done-local-phase52-phase53-phase54-phase55-phase56-phase59-pass-local-phase67-pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase70-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72-pass-local-phase73-pass-local-phase74-pass-local-phase76">
  <path>frontend/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/index.css frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx scripts/phase52-matrix-visual-smoke.mjs scripts/phase53-user-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase54-admin-matrix-ui-smoke.mjs scripts/phase55-premium-art-direction-smoke.mjs scripts/phase56-premium-public-auth-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs docs/plans/Phase-52.xml docs/plans/Phase-53.xml docs/plans/Phase-54.xml docs/plans/Phase-55.xml docs/plans/Phase-56.xml docs/plans/Phase-59.xml docs/plans/Phase-67.xml docs/plans/Phase-68.xml docs/plans/Phase-70.xml docs/plans/Phase-73.xml docs/plans/Phase-74.xml scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs scripts/phase70-config-qr-parity-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Shared KrotPN Matrix visual language: color tokens, compact panels, CRT scanlines, neon flicker, glitch accents, focus states, and mobile-safe responsive rules.</owns>
  <depends>M-009, M-010, M-036, M-037, M-038, M-070, M-077</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-071</verification-ref>
  <reference>
    <source-1>TRUFFLEX styles.css neon flicker, scanline, glitch, matrix fade, and reduced-motion CSS blocks.</source-1>
    <source-2>KrotPN compact UI rules from M-038 remain binding for operational dashboards.</source-2>
  </reference>
  <source-contract>
    <required-header>MODULE_CONTRACT, MODULE_MAP, CHANGE_SUMMARY</required-header>
    <role>UI_COMPONENT</role>
    <map-mode>SELECTORS_AND_TOKENS</map-mode>
  </source-contract>
  <public-interfaces>
    <interface-1>CSS custom properties for KrotPN Matrix palette, surfaces, borders, focus rings, and status colors.</interface-1>
    <interface-2>Reusable class layer for matrix-visual-shell, matrix-canvas, matrix-rain-fallback, matrix-scanline-overlay, matrix-vignette, and matrix-visual-content surfaces.</interface-2>
    <interface-3>Reduced-motion and mobile viewport rules shared by user and admin frontends.</interface-3>
    <interface-4>Phase-53 user route classes for matrix-auth-screen, matrix-auth-card, matrix-layout-frame, matrix-page, matrix-action-grid, matrix-terminal, matrix-copy-box, matrix-row, and matrix-icon-tile.</interface-4>
    <interface-5>Phase-54 admin route classes for admin-login-shell, admin-login-card, admin-hero-strip, compact-toolbar, mini-kpi-grid, bounded-scroll, chart-frame, admin-route-card, and matrix-mini-card.</interface-5>
    <interface-6>Phase-55 premium art-direction tokens for balanced palette, compact typography, density, logo sizing, shadow, focus, and reduced-motion shell rules.</interface-6>
    <interface-7>Phase-56 public/auth classes for matrix-public-page, matrix-public-hero, matrix-public-band, matrix-public-tariff, matrix-brand-logo, and matrix-auth-brand-lockup.</interface-7>
    <interface-8>Phase-59 motion classes for motion-route-enter, motion-interactive, motion-copy-success, motion-feedback-success/error, motion-status, and reduced-motion fallbacks.</interface-8>
    <interface-9 phase="71-pass-local">Phase-71 implemented classes for frameless protected logo, icon-only QR close, selected-device master-detail rows, sticky mobile config actions, and pulsing subscription boundary dates.</interface-9>
    <interface-10 phase="72-pass-local">Phase-72 implemented classes for compact touch dock, desktop calendar density, user nav density markers, and mobile dock overlap guards.</interface-10>
    <interface-11 phase="73-pass-local">Phase-73 verifies compact config copy, AmneziaVPN .conf guidance, and tariff-limit messaging within existing Matrix route primitives.</interface-11>
    <interface-12 phase="74-pass-local">Phase-74 implements admin login icon-safe padding, bounded desktop admin rail, and admin content scroll surface markers.</interface-12>
  </public-interfaces>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Preserve compact operational UX: no marketing landing page, no nested cards, no decorative card-heavy dashboards.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Matrix green may be the signature color, but the final palette must use controlled cyan, magenta, neutral, warning, and danger accents so the UI is not a one-note green surface.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Text must not overlap icons, controls, status badges, charts, rows, or adjacent content at 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, tablet, and desktop viewports.</constraint-3>
    <constraint-4>Glitch, scanline, and flicker effects must not reduce readability of form fields, tariff prices, proxy secrets, VPN config actions, admin tables, or incident controls.</constraint-4>
    <constraint-5>Do not change API contracts, data shapes, auth state, deploy/install scripts, nginx, docker-compose, or backend runtime behavior.</constraint-5>
    <constraint-6>Matrix background visibility must not depend on canvas-only rendering; CSS fallback must cover the full viewport with mobile overscan and no pointer interception.</constraint-6>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance>
    <metric-1>User and admin builds pass with shared Matrix CSS tokens applied.</metric-1>
    <metric-2>Viewport smoke confirms no horizontal scroll, no visible text overlap, and stable control dimensions.</metric-2>
    <metric-3>Reduced-motion mode disables transform-heavy and flicker-heavy effects while preserving visual identity.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>Screenshot review confirms Matrix style is present without hiding primary VPN, MTProto, tariff, or admin actions.</metric-4>
    <metric-5 status="pass-local-rainfix">Mobile screenshots confirm the Matrix rain/fallback layer reaches the bottom edge with no visible black cutoff.</metric-5>
  </acceptance>
  <evidence>
    <local-2026-06-03>Phase-52 added Matrix palette tokens, canvas/scanline/vignette/content layers, focus-visible rules, reduced-motion CSS policy, protected-surface smoke markers, user/admin builds, and Chrome screenshot checks for mobile, desktop, and reduced-motion login shells.</local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-53-local-2026-06-03>Phase-53 added compact Matrix user route primitives, removed the heavy login hero, strengthened auth contrast after screenshot review, passed frontend build and Phase-53 smoke, and captured readable production-preview mobile/desktop/reduced-motion auth screenshots.</phase-53-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>Phase-54 verification gates require compact Matrix admin route surfaces, readable tables/charts/forms, focus-visible controls, reduced-motion proof, no horizontal overflow, no text/icon overlap, balanced palette, and protected-surface isolation.</phase-54-verification-design-2026-06-03>
    <phase-54-local-2026-06-03>Phase-54 added compact Matrix admin primitives, retuned admin login/layout/routes, passed frontend-admin build and Phase-54 smoke, and kept protected deploy/install/runtime surfaces unchanged.</phase-54-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-55-local-2026-06-03>Phase-55 added premium Matrix art-direction tokens to user/admin CSS, removed decorative radial/orb shell backgrounds, passed frontend/admin builds, Phase-55 static/screenshot smoke, XML/MyGRACE/diff checks, and protected deploy/install guard.</phase-55-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-56-local-2026-06-03>Phase-56 added compact premium public/auth CSS primitives, logo lockup rules, public tariff preview styling, passed Phase-52/53/55 style regressions plus Phase-56 screenshots, and kept protected deploy/install/runtime surfaces unchanged.</phase-56-local-2026-06-03>
    <phase-59-local-2026-06-04>Phase-59 added short-duration motion budget tokens, route entrance transitions, feedback/status classes, reduced-motion fallbacks, and Phase-59 smoke markers to user/admin CSS; frontend/admin builds and style regressions passed.</phase-59-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-67-local-2026-06-04>Phase-67 added splash/auth CSS primitives for frameless panels, large unframed logo, red auth focus, icon-safe fields, compact animated primary/secondary actions, phone/tablet rules, and reduced-motion fallback; Phase-55/56/59/60/61/67 smokes passed.</phase-67-local-2026-06-04>
    <rainfix-local-2026-06-04>Added .matrix-rain-fallback, CSS rain animation, 100dvh+128px canvas/fallback overscan, normal canvas blend mode, and reduced-motion fallback positions to user/admin CSS. Phase-52/59/61/67/60 smokes, user/admin builds, Chrome screenshots, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</rainfix-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-68-local-2026-06-04>Added frameless user-shell logo CSS, compact dashboard subscription panel styles, responsive tariff grid, and compact cross-month calendar rules; Phase-68/57/62/61/60 smokes and builds passed.</phase-68-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-70-local-2026-06-04>Phase-70 preserved the compact config page style system and used route-local QR spacing/size adjustments in Config.tsx rather than adding global CSS bloat; frontend build and Phase-70 smoke passed.</phase-70-local-2026-06-04>
    <phase-73-local-2026-06-05>Phase-73 kept style changes route-local in Config.tsx, removed unsupported AmneziaVPN QR tab, added compact .conf guidance, and passed Phase-73/70/71 smokes without new global CSS bloat.</phase-73-local-2026-06-05>
    <phase-74-local-2026-06-05>Phase-74 added bounded admin shell CSS and login icon-safe spacing in frontend-admin/src/index.css; frontend-admin build and Phase-74 smoke passed with protected backend/deploy/runtime/user frontend guard clean.</phase-74-local-2026-06-05>
  </evidence>
  <phase-71-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/index.css frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Support the compact master-detail config page, icon-only modal close, frameless transparent PNG logo presentation, and start/end calendar pulse borders without text overlap or motion overload.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Style smoke must preserve reduced-motion fallbacks, no horizontal scroll, no nested-card bloat, and no protected deploy/runtime diffs.</verification>
  </phase-71-executed-scope>
  <phase-67-verification-design>
    <scope>Frontend auth-only style polish for frameless public/auth screens without changing user cabinet or admin layout contracts.</scope>
    <selectors>Planned auth primitives include frameless matrix-auth-screen variants, large unframed logo sizing, icon-safe input padding, red focus/active border states, hover/active input reactions, elegant primary buttons, side-by-side secondary auth actions, and reduced-motion fallbacks.</selectors>
    <guards>No visible matrix-auth-card frame on /login, /register, /forgot-password, or /reset-password; no blue/cyan auth focus border where Phase-67 requires red; no icon/placeholder/text overlap at phone/tablet/desktop viewports.</guards>
    <verification-status>pass-local</verification-status>
  </phase-67-verification-design>
  <crosslinks>
    <phase-52>Defines the foundation token system and shared effects.</phase-52>
    <phase-53>Applies the system to user cabinet routes.</phase-53>
    <phase-54>Applies the system to admin console routes.</phase-54>
    <phase-55>Extends the system with premium art-direction tokens before Phase-56/57/58 route work.</phase-55>
    <phase-56>Applies the premium style system to the public entry route and auth surfaces.</phase-56>
    <phase-59>Adds bounded motion and microinteraction primitives to the premium Matrix style system.</phase-59>
    <phase-67>Adds frameless auth, red-focus form, and splash styling constraints for the next public/auth polish wave.</phase-67>
    <rainfix>Adds CSS rain fallback and mobile overscan constraints for Matrix background reliability.</rainfix>
    <phase-68>Adds compact dashboard subscription merge styling and frameless user-shell logo treatment.</phase-68>
    <phase-70>Keeps QR page compaction and payload parity markers within the existing compact Matrix config workflow.</phase-70>
    <phase-71>Implements master-detail config UX styling, icon close polish, subscription boundary emphasis, and final frameless cabinet logo correction.</phase-71>
    <phase-72>Implements user auth/navigation polish styling, compact desktop calendar density, bottom-dock motion markers, and Russian-only Settings cleanup markers.</phase-72>
    <phase-73>Verifies compact KPN config copy, AmneziaVPN .conf guidance, and tariff-limit messaging inside existing Matrix config page primitives.</phase-73>
    <phase-74>Bounds the admin rail, repairs desktop admin content scroll, and prevents admin login icon/text overlap without changing backend or user tariff surfaces.</phase-74>
  </crosslinks>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Frontend build and Phase-71 smoke passed for master-detail CSS, selected-row state, icon-only QR close, frameless user logo, calendar boundary pulse, and reduced-motion fallback.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/index.css frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase59-motion-interactions-smoke.mjs scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Add Phase-72 Matrix markers for localized login, bottom dock, user nav density, desktop calendar density, and responsive no-overlap while preserving reduced-motion and no horizontal-scroll policies.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Frontend/admin builds, Phase-72 smoke, Phase-59 motion smoke, and Phase-61 responsive smoke passed.</verification>
  </phase-72-executed-scope>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Matrix style system passed local Phase-72 verification for touch dock styling, desktop calendar compaction, and reduced-motion-safe motion markers.</phase-72-evidence>
  <phase-73-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx scripts/phase73-config-amnezia-qr-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Keep KPN config copy, QR modal guidance, and device-limit tariff copy compact/readable without adding new global CSS or changing reduced-motion/bottom-dock behavior.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-73 smoke passed CONFIG_COPY_COMPACT and QR_GUIDANCE_READABLE markers; Phase-71 and Phase-70 regressions remained green.</verification>
  </phase-73-executed-scope>
  <phase-73-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-73 stayed inside existing compact Matrix components and did not introduce new CSS selectors requiring separate viewport risk.</phase-73-evidence>
  <phase-74-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend-admin/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Admin login inputs reserve Phase-74 icon-safe padding; desktop shell fixes app height, rail bounds, and content-area overflow-y; route/nav markers prove no visible Tariffs nav.</primary-behaviors>
    <verification>Phase-74 smoke passed MatrixStyle markers for ADMIN_LOGIN_ICON_NO_OVERLAP, ADMIN_RAIL_BOUNDED, and ADMIN_SCROLL_SURFACE_SAFE.</verification>
  </phase-74-executed-scope>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Matrix style system passed local Phase-74 verification for admin shell scroll geometry and icon-safe login fields.</phase-74-evidence>
</M-071>
