<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-074 NAME="responsive-device-adaptation" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pass-local-phase61-pass-local-phase62-pass-local-phase67-pass-local-rainfix-pass-local-phase68-pass-local-phase71-pass-local-phase72-pass-local-phase74">
  <path>frontend frontend-admin docs/plans/Phase-61.xml docs/plans/Phase-62.xml docs/plans/Phase-67.xml docs/plans/Phase-68.xml docs/plans/Phase-71.xml docs/plans/Phase-72.xml docs/plans/Phase-74.xml scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase62-compactness-deletion-smoke.mjs scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs scripts/phase68-dashboard-subscription-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Phone, tablet, and desktop responsive closure for public, user, and admin Matrix surfaces.</owns>
  <purpose>Make the premium frontend usable and compact across mobile phones, tablets, and desktop screens.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <viewport-phone>320x568, 360x740, 375x667, 390x844, and 430x932 phone layout gates.</viewport-phone>
    <viewport-tablet>768x1024, 820x1180, 1024x768, and 1024x1366 tablet layout gates.</viewport-tablet>
    <viewport-desktop>1280x720 and 1440x900 desktop layout gates.</viewport-desktop>
    <rule-responsive-density>Responsive spacing, grid, navigation, and bounded-scroll rules.</rule-responsive-density>
    <gate-phase61-smoke>scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs static responsive gate.</gate-phase61-smoke>
    <rule-matrix-rain-overscan>Matrix canvas/fallback background uses mobile viewport overscan to avoid bottom-edge black cutoffs.</rule-matrix-rain-overscan>
    <rule-phase72-bottom-dock>Mobile user bottom navigation uses safe-area padding and content spacing so primary cabinet actions remain reachable without overlap.</rule-phase72-bottom-dock>
    <rule-phase74-admin-scroll>Desktop admin content owns overflow-y scrolling while the admin rail is clipped to 100dvh.</rule-phase74-admin-scroll>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-010,M-036,M-037,M-038,M-071,M-072</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-074</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend</file>
    <file>frontend-admin</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-61.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-71.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-72.xml</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-74.xml</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No document-level horizontal scroll at any planned viewport.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Tablet layouts must not be lazy stretched phone layouts or cramped desktop layouts.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Primary VPN, MTProto, subscription, admin health, and emergency actions must stay reachable.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local-phase61">User and admin builds pass with Phase-61 viewport/static-route smoke evidence.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-phase61">No visible text overlap, icon overlap, clipped critical values, or document-level horizontal-scroll static drift is allowed by the Phase-61 smoke.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="pass-local-phase61">Reduced-motion proof remains readable across phone and tablet viewport classes.</metric-3>
    <metric-4 status="pass-local-phase62">Phase-62 folded surfaces keep 44px summaries, no horizontal-scroll guards, bounded lists, and responsive compactness markers.</metric-4>
    <metric-5 status="pass-local-rainfix">390x844 user/admin browser screenshots show Matrix rain/fallback through the bottom viewport edge.</metric-5>
    <metric-6 status="pass-local-phase68">Phase-68 compact dashboard subscription/tariff/calendar layout stays within Phase-61 responsive budgets and Phase-60 QA bundle limits.</metric-6>
    <metric-7 status="pass-local-phase71">Phase-71 proves master-detail device config UX and sticky mobile actions stay readable across phone, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion viewports.</metric-7>
    <metric-8 status="pass-local-phase72">Phase-72 proves the mobile dock and smaller desktop calendar keep no-overlap/no-horizontal-scroll guarantees with frontend/admin build budgets intact.</metric-8>
    <metric-9 status="pass-local-phase74">Phase-74 proves admin rail viewport bounds, content-area wheel scroll, and login icon no-overlap without changing user responsive surfaces.</metric-9>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <phase-67-verification-design>
    <scope>Apply responsive closure to the new splash-only / route and frameless auth screens without changing protected user/admin layouts.</scope>
    <viewports>Phase-67 must cover 320x568, 360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1024x768, 1280x720, 1440x900, and reduced-motion auth/splash states.</viewports>
    <guards>No document-level horizontal scroll, no logo/control overlap, no icon/placeholder overlap, no clipped secondary auth actions, no hidden redirect status under reduced-motion, and 44px-safe primary/secondary actions on phone/tablet.</guards>
    <verification-status>pass-local</verification-status>
  </phase-67-verification-design>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added Phase-61 responsive CSS blocks to user and admin Matrix style systems with phone/tablet breakpoints, safe-area padding, bounded scroll, text wrapping, and 44px touch-target policy.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added Phase-61 layout markers to user and admin shells for viewport matrix, mobile header/nav safe-area, protected user static proof, and admin static proof.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added root min-width containment to admin Analytics and Servers route surfaces to protect chart/topology pages on phones and tablets.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend and frontend-admin production builds passed; Phase-61 smoke and Phase-60 premium QA regression gate passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Protected backend/deploy/runtime guard remained empty; authenticated protected-route screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up evidence.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-62 compactness/deletion audit smoke and Phase-61 responsive regression passed after adding user/admin details folds and bounded secondary surfaces.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-67 auth/splash responsive work passed frontend/admin builds, Phase-67 smoke, Phase-60 QA, Phase-61 responsive, Phase-62 compactness, and protected backend/deploy/admin/runtime guards for large unframed logo, red-focus inputs, secondary auth actions, and reduced-motion fallback.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Matrix rain reliability hotfix added Phase-61 assertions for .matrix-rain-fallback and 100dvh+128px overscan. User/admin builds, Phase-61 smoke, Phase-60 QA regression, Chrome mobile screenshots, bottom-pixel sanity, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Phase-68 dashboard subscription merge passed Phase-61 responsive smoke, Phase-60 QA, frontend/admin builds, and compact calendar/tariff no-overlap guards.</item>
    <item>2026-06-05: Phase-74 admin shell changes passed frontend-admin build and Phase-74 smoke for admin rail bounds, content-scroll surface, and login icon no-overlap.</item>
  </evidence>
  <phase-71-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/pages/Config.tsx frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/components/SubscriptionPanel.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase71-device-config-master-detail-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Verify the master-detail device config UX, sticky mobile QR/.conf/Copy actions, sidebar logout order, logo frame removal, and calendar boundary emphasis across phone, tablet, desktop, and reduced-motion viewports.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>360x740, 390x844, 430x932, 768x1024, 1024x768, 1280x720, and 1440x900 must remain free of horizontal scroll and action overlap.</acceptance>
  </phase-71-executed-scope>
  <hotspot>H-061: Tablet and mobile adaptation must be verified on real breakpoint classes, not inferred from desktop layouts.</hotspot>
  <phase-71-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-04">Frontend build and Phase-71 smoke passed for mobile sticky config actions and 9-device master-detail markers; post-commit Phase-61 and Phase-62 protected regression smokes passed cleanly.</phase-71-evidence>
  <phase-72-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend/src/index.css scripts/phase72-user-auth-navigation-smoke.mjs scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Verify mobile bottom navigation no-overlap, safe-area spacing, stable touch target dimensions, desktop calendar no-overflow, and reduced-motion-safe dock transitions.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>Phase-61 responsive smoke passed after frontend and frontend-admin builds, with bundle budgets under limits and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard clean.</acceptance>
  </phase-72-executed-scope>
  <phase-72-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Phase-72 passed local responsive verification for mobile dock no-overlap and desktop compact calendar no-overflow.</phase-72-evidence>
  <phase-74-executed-scope>
    <primary-files>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/index.css scripts/phase74-admin-shell-navigation-smoke.mjs</primary-files>
    <primary-behaviors>Bound admin rail to the viewport, move scroll ownership to admin content on desktop, and keep mobile tabbar free of the retired Tariffs item.</primary-behaviors>
    <acceptance>Phase-74 smoke passed ResponsiveAdaptation markers for ADMIN_SCROLL_NO_OVERLAP and ADMIN_RAIL_VIEWPORT_SAFE.</acceptance>
  </phase-74-executed-scope>
  <phase-74-evidence status="pass-local" date="2026-06-05">Responsive adaptation passed local Phase-74 verification for admin shell scroll and rail geometry.</phase-74-evidence>
</M-074>
