<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-074 NAME="responsive-device-adaptation" TYPE="UI_COMPONENT" STATUS="pass-local-phase61">
  <path>frontend frontend-admin docs/plans/Phase-61.xml scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Phone, tablet, and desktop responsive closure for public, user, and admin Matrix surfaces.</owns>
  <purpose>Make the premium frontend usable and compact across mobile phones, tablets, and desktop screens.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <viewport-phone>320x568, 360x740, 375x667, 390x844, and 430x932 phone layout gates.</viewport-phone>
    <viewport-tablet>768x1024, 820x1180, 1024x768, and 1024x1366 tablet layout gates.</viewport-tablet>
    <viewport-desktop>1280x720 and 1440x900 desktop layout gates.</viewport-desktop>
    <rule-responsive-density>Responsive spacing, grid, navigation, and bounded-scroll rules.</rule-responsive-density>
    <gate-phase61-smoke>scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs static responsive gate.</gate-phase61-smoke>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-010,M-036,M-037,M-038,M-071,M-072</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-074</verification-ref>
  <files>
    <file>frontend</file>
    <file>frontend-admin</file>
    <file>frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/index.css</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Analytics.tsx</file>
    <file>frontend-admin/src/pages/Servers.tsx</file>
    <file>scripts/phase61-responsive-adaptation-smoke.mjs</file>
    <file>docs/plans/Phase-61.xml</file>
  </files>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>No document-level horizontal scroll at any planned viewport.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Tablet layouts must not be lazy stretched phone layouts or cramped desktop layouts.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Primary VPN, MTProto, subscription, admin health, and emergency actions must stay reachable.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local-phase61">User and admin builds pass with Phase-61 viewport/static-route smoke evidence.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-phase61">No visible text overlap, icon overlap, clipped critical values, or document-level horizontal-scroll static drift is allowed by the Phase-61 smoke.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="pass-local-phase61">Reduced-motion proof remains readable across phone and tablet viewport classes.</metric-3>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <evidence>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added Phase-61 responsive CSS blocks to user and admin Matrix style systems with phone/tablet breakpoints, safe-area padding, bounded scroll, text wrapping, and 44px touch-target policy.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added Phase-61 layout markers to user and admin shells for viewport matrix, mobile header/nav safe-area, protected user static proof, and admin static proof.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Added root min-width containment to admin Analytics and Servers route surfaces to protect chart/topology pages on phones and tablets.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: frontend and frontend-admin production builds passed; Phase-61 smoke and Phase-60 premium QA regression gate passed.</item>
    <item>2026-06-04: Protected backend/deploy/runtime guard remained empty; authenticated protected-route screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up evidence.</item>
  </evidence>
  <hotspot>H-061: Tablet and mobile adaptation must be verified on real breakpoint classes, not inferred from desktop layouts.</hotspot>
</M-074>
