<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<M-080 NAME="visible-brand-logo-integration" TYPE="ENTRY_POINT" STATUS="done-local-phase63-planned-phase67">
  <path>frontend/public/brand/krotpn-mark-96.png frontend-admin/public/brand/krotpn-mark-96.png frontend/src/components/BrandMark.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/BrandMark.tsx frontend/src/pages/Landing.tsx frontend/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend/src/pages/Register.tsx frontend/src/pages/ForgotPassword.tsx frontend/src/pages/ResetPassword.tsx frontend/src/pages/VerifyEmail.tsx frontend/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/components/Layout.tsx frontend-admin/src/pages/Login.tsx frontend/src/index.css frontend-admin/src/index.css backend/app/email/templates.py docs/plans/Phase-63.xml docs/plans/Phase-67.xml scripts/phase63-visible-logo-integration-smoke.mjs scripts/phase67-auth-splash-smoke.mjs</path>
  <owns>Visible KrotPN logo usage across public site, auth, user cabinet, admin panel, PWA/favicons, and email templates.</owns>
  <purpose>Use prepared logo assets consistently where the premium redesign needs visible brand identity.</purpose>
  <exports>
    <asset-source-logos>/home/truffle/Загрузки/ДЛЯ КРОТА/logos PNG assets from 16x16 through 1024x1024.</asset-source-logos>
    <component-brand-mark>User and admin reusable brand mark placement.</component-brand-mark>
    <rule-logo-sizing>Responsive logo sizing and asset selection for header, auth, PWA, email, and admin contexts.</rule-logo-sizing>
    <asset-visible-mark>User/admin /brand/krotpn-mark-96.png copied from the prepared 96x96 PNG source for visible UI logo usage.</asset-visible-mark>
    <smoke-phase63-visible-logo>Validate asset dimensions, UI placement markers, regression compatibility, email/BIMI boundary, asset budgets, and protected surfaces.</smoke-phase63-visible-logo>
  </exports>
  <depends>M-009,M-010,M-040,M-062,M-069,M-072,M-073,M-075,M-076,M-079</depends>
  <verification-ref>V-M-080</verification-ref>
  <constraints>
    <constraint-1>Do not overwrite BIMI semantics or claim mailbox sender-avatar control.</constraint-1>
    <constraint-2>Use appropriately sized assets and avoid large logo files on first paint.</constraint-2>
    <constraint-3>Logo placement must not crowd mobile navigation, forms, cards, or admin tables.</constraint-3>
  </constraints>
  <acceptance-metrics>
    <metric-1 status="pass-local-phase63">User and admin builds include visible logo usage without layout overlap.</metric-1>
    <metric-2 status="pass-local-phase63">Logo smoke verifies source dimensions, copied assets, placement markers, email/BIMI boundary, and protected deploy/runtime guard.</metric-2>
    <metric-3 status="pass-local-static-proof">Static route proof and regression smokes confirm premium brand presence on public/auth/user/admin surfaces; live browser screenshots remain clean-deploy follow-up.</metric-3>
    <metric-4>Phase-63 verification design is complete before execution: asset budgets, visible-placement rules, screenshot/static proof, email/BIMI boundary, and protected-surface guard are explicitly mapped in V-M-080.</metric-4>
  </acceptance-metrics>
  <phase-67-plan>
    <scope>Provide a larger unframed KrotPN mark for splash and auth routes while retaining the existing bounded logo asset and avoiding provider/BIMI/email-avatar claims.</scope>
    <guards>The large logo must not use the previous frame/lockup border, must not crowd inputs/buttons on mobile, must remain budget-safe, and must preserve current favicon/PWA/email-logo boundaries.</guards>
  </phase-67-plan>
  <verification-design>
    <target-1>Phase-63 smoke must validate selected asset dimensions and file weights before any visible logo placement is accepted.</target-1>
    <target-2>User/admin builds and screenshot/static proof must show logo placement does not crowd mobile navigation, forms, admin tables, cards, or primary CTAs.</target-2>
    <target-3>Email template checks remain boundary-only in Phase-63; premium email body redesign belongs to Phase-64 and mailbox sender-avatar/BIMI claims remain out of scope.</target-3>
    <target-4>Protected install/deploy/backend/VPN/MTProto runtime surfaces must remain unchanged.</target-4>
  </verification-design>
  <execution-evidence>
    <local-2026-06-04 commit="c385d62">Phase-63 selected 96x96.png from the prepared operator logo set, copied it as frontend/public/brand/krotpn-mark-96.png and frontend-admin/public/brand/krotpn-mark-96.png, added user/admin BrandMark components, integrated visible logos into public/auth routes, protected user shell, admin login, admin rail, and admin topbar, preserved existing email-logo/BIMI/provider-avatar boundaries, and kept deploy/install/backend/VPN/MTProto/runtime surfaces unchanged.</local-2026-06-04>
    <verification-2026-06-04>Passed: frontend build, frontend-admin build, scripts/phase63-visible-logo-integration-smoke.mjs, Phase-55/56/57/58/60/61/62 regression smokes, XML parse, MyGRACE lint, git diff --check, and protected backend/deploy/runtime guard.</verification-2026-06-04>
  </execution-evidence>
  <hotspot>H-067: Visible logo integration must use prepared brand assets without bloating pages or conflicting with BIMI/email-avatar boundaries.</hotspot>
</M-080>
